<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sport &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/sport/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;Gum&#8221; violence</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/gum-violence/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 22:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Costas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deleuze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guattari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Rosen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Night Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandy Hook Elementary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an op/ed titled “‘Gums’ control for Bob Costas,” a piece written prior to Friday&#8217;s mass shooting, sportscaster Mark Rosen criticized his better-known colleague for a segment aired on Monday Night Football following the Jovan Belcher murder-suicide in which Costas firmly asserted the necessity for gun control. “I read about, hear about, write about, talk about [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-614" title="Costas" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Costas3.jpg" alt="" width="341" height="255" /></p>
<p>In an <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/opinion/ci_22179264/rosen-gums-control-bob-costas">op/ed</a> titled “‘Gums’ control for Bob Costas,” a piece written prior to Friday&#8217;s mass shooting, sportscaster Mark Rosen criticized his better-known colleague for a segment aired on Monday Night Football following the Jovan Belcher murder-suicide in which Costas firmly asserted the necessity for gun control.<span id="more-602"></span></p>
<p>“I read about, hear about, write about, talk about and think about politics for much of my waking — and oft-times sleeping — hours,&#8221; wrote Rosen, &#8220;Sunday Night Football on NBC is a time to get away from that for me and 20 million other American viewers. It&#8217;s an NFL sanctuary. Sportscaster Bob Costas stirred a national controversy when he violated that sanctuary to comment on the suicide of Kansas City Chiefs linebacker Jovan Belcher&#8230;It was annoying and inappropriate.”</p>
<p>Mark Rosen is a part of the problem. His reference to Monday Night Football as a “sanctuary,” is not just &#8220;annoying and inappropriate,&#8221; it suggests the same consecrating attitude towards sports institutions that allowed the atrocities at Penn State to take place repeatedly over several decades without intervention. But there are broader and more troubling principles underpinning Mr. Rosen&#8217;s ire.</p>
<p>The notion that one is entitled to ritualized spaces of psychological isolation from unsettling “real world” events is deeply woven into the fabric of “ordinary,” socio-economically secure American life—indeed, it may well be the sine qua non of the ideology of the &#8220;ordinary&#8221; itself. This regime of entitlement, foundational to suburban existence, feeds a project of empathic divestment that greases the gears of the western war machine and its profiteers and figures centrally in the technocapitalist conspiracy to transform the children of the twenty-first century into affectively conditioned test subjects in a digital age Pavlovian laboratory. (The true eventuation of the &#8216;Becoming-Animal&#8217; misguidedly envisioned by Deleuze and Guattari, at the cusp of the personal computing era, as an emancipatory proposition is the subject subsisting permanently within the <em>intermezzo</em> of the technological apparatus.) It is only when such currents manifest themselves locally, as in the tragedy that occurred yesterday in Connecticut, that the cycle is momentarily interrupted before being re-subordinated to the spectatorial anesthetization that inevitably ensues in the wake of what are thereby rendered non-events.</p>
<p>If there is a cruel fortuity to the close succession of recent nationally visible gun tragedies perhaps it is in the conversation having finally directed itself, in acknowledgement of a long-disavowed repetition compulsion, to the mechanisms of temporalization that allow disavowal to continue unabated. In this sense, Costas demonstrated foresight and courage not for breaking out of the narrow definitions of what constitutes sports reporting, nor even for profaning the sanctity of a cherished American institution, but for reminding us, in the too-soon-ness of the moment, of our propensity for staying the same. Traumatic events are too-frequently assimilated by the neoliberal subject according to a sacralizing convention whose deleterious effects are felt from Newtown, Connecticut to East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Here’s Costas:</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="500" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/B1ijkccD9_8" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MJ&#8217;s Hall of Fame Speech: From Force to Farce</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/468/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[metaphysicalvillain]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sport]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=468</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This isn&#8217;t exactly topical, since Michael Jordan gave his infamous Hall of Fame speech over three years ago. But while reading an article about Nietzsche&#8217;s critique of the liberal conception of freedom, I think I began to understand exactly why MJ&#8217;s vindictive and petty speech came off as not only, well, vindictive and petty, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-478" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/mj_trashtalking1-333x500.jpg" alt="" width="218" height="328" /></p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t exactly topical, since Michael Jordan gave his infamous Hall of Fame speech over three years ago. But while reading an article about Nietzsche&#8217;s critique of the liberal conception of freedom, I think I began to understand exactly why MJ&#8217;s vindictive and petty speech came off as not only, well, vindictive and petty, but also pathetic and farcical. The connection may seem at first glance a little ridiculous, but I think there&#8217;s something here.</p>
<p><span id="more-468"></span></p>
<p>The liberal conception of freedom is primarily a negative one (paradigmatically espoused by JS Mill): freedom consists merely in the absence of any constraint or coercive force. By contrast Nietzsche sees the will as essentially bound up with the overcoming of constraints and obstacles. Further, the will can be conceived as self-overcoming in the sense that it posits its own possible limitations in order that it may surpass them.</p>
<p>During his remarkable basketball career, MJ was famous for not only interpreting other players&#8217; comments, gestures or actions as insults, but actively imagining that they were insulting him. He made psychosis productive. For MJ, &#8220;playing his hardest&#8221; wasn&#8217;t good enough; he had to compulsively generate targets to destroy. In addition to his considerable talent, this excessive will is what made MJ an otherworldly athletic force. As the sportswriter Bill Simmons has observed, he was constantly engaged in this sort of self-deception, imagining his opponents as hostile and cocky antagonists that he could not only beat, but thoroughly humiliate.</p>
<p>MJ&#8217;s speech manifested this same kind of vindictive fantasy—a fantasy that made his vindictiveness possible in the first place. On an occasion calling for expressions of gratitude and joy, he repeatedly singled out people who &#8220;underestimated&#8221; him or trash-talked him. Many wondered what his motive was for doing this. A lot of commentators got it right: this was just MJ doing what he&#8217;d always done. He was once again fashioning villains out of opponents to fuel his will.</p>
<p>The speech made many people angry, or in any case, reaffirmed their impression that MJ had always been a jerk. But I think what&#8217;s interesting about the speech is that the habit of self-deception (the paranoid attitude that the world was against him) had obviously outlived its usefulness. In his late 40s, the retired MJ no longer had the physical prowess to materialize his will in any relevant way. The speech struck me as a sad yet comical spectacle, hardly something that ought to induce outrage. Rather than condemning MJ from a moral perspective, then, I think the proper response is to understand the psychology of obsolete viciousness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FEAR the BEARD</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/fear-the-beard/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sport]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[James Harden has 82 points in the first 2 games of the season. Only Michael Jordan and Wilt Chamberlain have scored more points in a team&#8217;s first 2 games in NBA history (sic). &#8211;ESPN stats and information]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-280" title="The BEARD" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Harden-Beard-500x280.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="280" /><a href="http://espn.go.com/nba/player/_/id/3992/james-harden">James Harden</a> has 82 points in the first 2 games of the season. Only <a href="http://espn.go.com/nba/player/_/id/1035/michael-jordan">Michael Jordan</a> and <a href="http://espn.go.com/nba/player/_/id/4142/wilt-chamberlain">Wilt Chamberlain</a> have scored more points in a team&#8217;s first 2 games in NBA history (sic).</p>
<p>&#8211;<a href="http://scores.espn.go.com/nba/recap?gameId=400277738">ESPN stats and information</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Basketball Update</title>
		<link>/j-r/basketball-update/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 03:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sport]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=70</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Down with King James!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Down with King James!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
