<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Reflections on Sandy Hook: Fantasy and Cinematic Violence</title>
	<atom:link href="/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/#comment-22</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 15:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=648#comment-22</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@ Mouse. The subtle distinction you make between cinema as an origin and cinema as a language is one of those difficult to articulate yet necessary  distinctions, and I think you emphasize this with what I might call a precise suggestiveness. Also, by calling attention to film as a language, cinema can no longer reign supreme as some totalizing force, it is brought within an ever more elusive field, one about which yes! psychoanalysis, at least the Lacanian variant, has very much to say. What your piece made me think is that though we might call these fantasies cinematic, the possibility of fantasy, the insistence of fantasy, can certainly not be relegated to the filmic world. And this is where we can locate cinema in relation to language; for, according to Lacan, it is the signifier, this kernel of language, which first possesses us with fantasy. Brutal acts have always found some way to speak and so, though we could say that we are witnessing a particular articulation nowadays, we also can’t say something so naïve like: “If we only had a different language we would not incur these tragedies.” AND YET! AND YET! I also think we cannot flounder in this generalization, that we cannot let up our critique of the mediums by which the signifier functions ‘most dangerously’ today. But, I should really say the relation to these mediums. You know, it is possible to not watch films, to not play games, to not watch TV, to not use the Internet (I mean it is possible, sort of)—that is to say, we are not slaves yet, we relate to these devices, etc. 

What I want to say though, and I hope this is not too far from your post, is that by thinking about the variety of ways we can RELATE to the mediums that spawn or produce fantasies today instead of simply casting dispersions on the mediums themselves, for me, emphasizes the stupidity of all these 20 year old kids. I don’t think they are evil and I don’t think they are properly psychotic or mad, I think they are stupid. And I think this because for some reason they don’t realize that all these mediums do is produce fantasies, that these fantasies cannot manifest something Real and everlasting, and I think it is exactly the failure to recognize this that inspires the fantasy-act of these terminal ambitions.  Somehow these kids treat the signifier as if it owed them something more, and this too is why they engage in exactly the locus of transgression, and thus why they are neither insane nor purely evil (i.e. there is Reason in their decision to do wrong)—they think all these taboo things like murder and guns are somehow the place where the fantasy becomes Real.  Where it absolves them of all their fantasies. 

So I think you are right to draw attention to your fantasy Mouse, one which you place within a giant question mark, and one which you seem to feel no pressure to fulfill. And though of course it is full of violence and definitely influenced by cinema, you do not relate to it, well…stupidly.  Call me a Platonist, but I still think ignorance is the greatest evil.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@ Mouse. The subtle distinction you make between cinema as an origin and cinema as a language is one of those difficult to articulate yet necessary  distinctions, and I think you emphasize this with what I might call a precise suggestiveness. Also, by calling attention to film as a language, cinema can no longer reign supreme as some totalizing force, it is brought within an ever more elusive field, one about which yes! psychoanalysis, at least the Lacanian variant, has very much to say. What your piece made me think is that though we might call these fantasies cinematic, the possibility of fantasy, the insistence of fantasy, can certainly not be relegated to the filmic world. And this is where we can locate cinema in relation to language; for, according to Lacan, it is the signifier, this kernel of language, which first possesses us with fantasy. Brutal acts have always found some way to speak and so, though we could say that we are witnessing a particular articulation nowadays, we also can’t say something so naïve like: “If we only had a different language we would not incur these tragedies.” AND YET! AND YET! I also think we cannot flounder in this generalization, that we cannot let up our critique of the mediums by which the signifier functions ‘most dangerously’ today. But, I should really say the relation to these mediums. You know, it is possible to not watch films, to not play games, to not watch TV, to not use the Internet (I mean it is possible, sort of)—that is to say, we are not slaves yet, we relate to these devices, etc. </p>
<p>What I want to say though, and I hope this is not too far from your post, is that by thinking about the variety of ways we can RELATE to the mediums that spawn or produce fantasies today instead of simply casting dispersions on the mediums themselves, for me, emphasizes the stupidity of all these 20 year old kids. I don’t think they are evil and I don’t think they are properly psychotic or mad, I think they are stupid. And I think this because for some reason they don’t realize that all these mediums do is produce fantasies, that these fantasies cannot manifest something Real and everlasting, and I think it is exactly the failure to recognize this that inspires the fantasy-act of these terminal ambitions.  Somehow these kids treat the signifier as if it owed them something more, and this too is why they engage in exactly the locus of transgression, and thus why they are neither insane nor purely evil (i.e. there is Reason in their decision to do wrong)—they think all these taboo things like murder and guns are somehow the place where the fantasy becomes Real.  Where it absolves them of all their fantasies. </p>
<p>So I think you are right to draw attention to your fantasy Mouse, one which you place within a giant question mark, and one which you seem to feel no pressure to fulfill. And though of course it is full of violence and definitely influenced by cinema, you do not relate to it, well…stupidly.  Call me a Platonist, but I still think ignorance is the greatest evil.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
