<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Categorically India</title>
	<atom:link href="/j-r/categorically-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/j-r/categorically-india/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: S.W.K.C.</title>
		<link>/j-r/categorically-india/#comment-76</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[S.W.K.C.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=940#comment-76</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have no idea what you are talking about. It would appear that you have little idea what you are talking about, given your bizarrely obtuse sentence structures. The only thing that you really make clear in your comments is that you are in the &quot;milieu&quot; of Hindu/Americans and when it comes to India, even if you agree with JR, it is you who have authority to make these statements. Especially over a Jew. (as it were)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have no idea what you are talking about. It would appear that you have little idea what you are talking about, given your bizarrely obtuse sentence structures. The only thing that you really make clear in your comments is that you are in the &#8220;milieu&#8221; of Hindu/Americans and when it comes to India, even if you agree with JR, it is you who have authority to make these statements. Especially over a Jew. (as it were)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: A.P.</title>
		<link>/j-r/categorically-india/#comment-73</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.P.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 18:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=940#comment-73</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And I am, admittedly, sensitive to anything Shaiva/Shakta presented in public without context for reasons having to do with both what I have seen as an overraction of interested parties and academic laziness which seems to characterize a lot of psychoanalytical approaches to Hinduism (which is obviously not what this is). It is clear it is a picture book, and in the grand scheme of things it doesn&#039;t matter much. As for Ginsburg, the culture-creators of his generation obviously found something more accessible in Shaiva/Shakta traditions and philosophies, but regardless of his intention his method of delivery is one that begs the question of how much is appropriate. 

One could level a charge of prudishness at me for being bothered by it, but I really don&#039;t think the Western understanding of tantra/shaivism has gone to the level that would make it clear that a part of Ginsburg&#039;s life was spent battling the forces of repression within the Hare Krishna movement, for example. I think what I was more trying to say (but did not say very nicely) was that if I had not already had context for what you were trying to convey from my time spent parsing the relationship between Western counterculture and &#039;Hinduism,&#039; I would have been offended, and that is something that American academics are often not self aware about. I&#039;m sorry for being callous in my critique, as it were.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And I am, admittedly, sensitive to anything Shaiva/Shakta presented in public without context for reasons having to do with both what I have seen as an overraction of interested parties and academic laziness which seems to characterize a lot of psychoanalytical approaches to Hinduism (which is obviously not what this is). It is clear it is a picture book, and in the grand scheme of things it doesn&#8217;t matter much. As for Ginsburg, the culture-creators of his generation obviously found something more accessible in Shaiva/Shakta traditions and philosophies, but regardless of his intention his method of delivery is one that begs the question of how much is appropriate. </p>
<p>One could level a charge of prudishness at me for being bothered by it, but I really don&#8217;t think the Western understanding of tantra/shaivism has gone to the level that would make it clear that a part of Ginsburg&#8217;s life was spent battling the forces of repression within the Hare Krishna movement, for example. I think what I was more trying to say (but did not say very nicely) was that if I had not already had context for what you were trying to convey from my time spent parsing the relationship between Western counterculture and &#8216;Hinduism,&#8217; I would have been offended, and that is something that American academics are often not self aware about. I&#8217;m sorry for being callous in my critique, as it were.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/j-r/categorically-india/#comment-72</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 18:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=940#comment-72</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You know, my remark about &quot;Hindus worshipping the phallus&quot; is directed to one person in particular, Babyvitrivuis. So you are right to feel a certain animosity to its laziness, etc. I do believe that what Lacan calls the phallus, that little fleck that inaugurates all signification, is indeed what we all worship. And in this sense, the simplicity and straightforwardness of the Shiva lingam is something I find quite profound. As for your critique about the Ginsburg quotation, I think I have an entirely different interpretation. I think Ginsburg is being quite loving and kind to the goddesses, he is saying you are allowed to touch them, that you can commune with them, that they are not transcendent, pure, and haughty. This is also something I experienced throughout India, the ability to touch sculptures of gods and goddesses, to paint them, to throw butter on them. All things which contrast greatly to the aura of conservation found in European churches. So your estimation of callousness, laziness, irony and cleverness are surprising to say the least. If anything, I am lazy, in that I didn&#039;t explicate, but this was mainly supposed to be a picture book.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know, my remark about &#8220;Hindus worshipping the phallus&#8221; is directed to one person in particular, Babyvitrivuis. So you are right to feel a certain animosity to its laziness, etc. I do believe that what Lacan calls the phallus, that little fleck that inaugurates all signification, is indeed what we all worship. And in this sense, the simplicity and straightforwardness of the Shiva lingam is something I find quite profound. As for your critique about the Ginsburg quotation, I think I have an entirely different interpretation. I think Ginsburg is being quite loving and kind to the goddesses, he is saying you are allowed to touch them, that you can commune with them, that they are not transcendent, pure, and haughty. This is also something I experienced throughout India, the ability to touch sculptures of gods and goddesses, to paint them, to throw butter on them. All things which contrast greatly to the aura of conservation found in European churches. So your estimation of callousness, laziness, irony and cleverness are surprising to say the least. If anything, I am lazy, in that I didn&#8217;t explicate, but this was mainly supposed to be a picture book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: A.P.</title>
		<link>/j-r/categorically-india/#comment-71</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.P.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 18:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=940#comment-71</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I find your addition of Ginsburg&#039;s poem to be off-putting. This is not because of some discomfort about sexuality that tends to animate such objections against appropriations of Hindu symbols and icons by &#039;the West,&#039; but because from a non-academic perspective it just seems callous (though I know you were going for irony and cleverness). From an academic perspective it seems lazy, because you certainly know the dangers in saying things like &#039;Hindus worship the phallus.&#039; As someone who might be categorized as Hindu-American (though in the American milieu I&#039;d rather claim atheism), the inability to accept that Shiva&#039;s iconic representation is that of a phallus among most Hindus I know is incredibly frustrating. Just like the way Hindus refuse to see the phallic representations everywhere for what they are, thus undermining the power of the image itself, the American academy also refuses to accept that such offhand remarks and characterizations undermine its ability to reach beyond its limited audience of mostly privileged caucasians (and Jews). If this blog is supposed to be an attempt to make criticism more accessible to the average internet inhabitant, you can do better.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I find your addition of Ginsburg&#8217;s poem to be off-putting. This is not because of some discomfort about sexuality that tends to animate such objections against appropriations of Hindu symbols and icons by &#8216;the West,&#8217; but because from a non-academic perspective it just seems callous (though I know you were going for irony and cleverness). From an academic perspective it seems lazy, because you certainly know the dangers in saying things like &#8216;Hindus worship the phallus.&#8217; As someone who might be categorized as Hindu-American (though in the American milieu I&#8217;d rather claim atheism), the inability to accept that Shiva&#8217;s iconic representation is that of a phallus among most Hindus I know is incredibly frustrating. Just like the way Hindus refuse to see the phallic representations everywhere for what they are, thus undermining the power of the image itself, the American academy also refuses to accept that such offhand remarks and characterizations undermine its ability to reach beyond its limited audience of mostly privileged caucasians (and Jews). If this blog is supposed to be an attempt to make criticism more accessible to the average internet inhabitant, you can do better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
