<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: La politique de l&#8217;autruche</title>
	<atom:link href="/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/#comment-28</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 21:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=663#comment-28</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You know, you had me all but convinced against stupidity until you told me they found God--then I thought they were stupid once again. I suspect, given the eerie nature of the silence you speak about, that these labels are probably ineffective. And are you telling us you knew Eric Harris?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know, you had me all but convinced against stupidity until you told me they found God&#8211;then I thought they were stupid once again. I suspect, given the eerie nature of the silence you speak about, that these labels are probably ineffective. And are you telling us you knew Eric Harris?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: le manque</title>
		<link>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/#comment-26</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[le manque]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 22:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=663#comment-26</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the first place, I don&#039;t think it&#039;s any accident that these shootings, at least beginning with Charles Whitman (and here, my god, do we not see the quintessential American &quot;I&quot;-o-cratic nature of these killings--of the lone gunmen--a sort of absolute song-of-myself--to these killings?)  through Eric Harris to Adam Lanza, take place in schools, which we may as well metonymize as the university discourse. A sort of revolt against Knowledge, then, in the name of a self-to-come. An attempt to be a Master, beyond book learning, which has ceased to be a form of knowledge. But even that doesn&#039;t have the ring of truth to it. Why?

Now I&#039;m pushing into empirical territory when I say that what unites most of these &quot;wimpy kids&quot; is that they are always &quot;intelligent.&quot; I can personally vouch for Eric Harris--he was not stupid. Strangely, I think calling them stupid gives them too much credit; in the same way that calling them evil or psychotic does (despite the risks inherent in turning those very terms into objects of fetish, academic or otherwise). We could hedge this claim by introducing the term &quot;language game,&quot; which renders all claims to intelligence a tautology, but that doesn&#039;t change the structure of the particular form of violence here.  

So when I say Adorno &quot;comes off as&quot;--I think I&#039;m hedging beyond a vernacular formulation, which takes us so close to jouissance, that this psychopathy is an illusion of discourse, an effect of ideological critique as such: nothing short of the attempt to be a master, which is the ignorance of lack--a much different concept than stupidity. I mean, this &quot;work&quot; we do here--it&#039;s really quite insane!

So I&#039;m not sure my claim is that, as you break it down so nicely,  &quot;we should view Adorno’s vision of technology creating a sort of Grand Theft Auto citizen as the very psychopathic logic of the ‘wimpy white kids’ now murdering us.&quot; I think that is the claim of a film like &quot;Elephant,&quot; which actually takes us into a video-game version of the event, as if to pre-empt any culturally conservative critique of cinematic representation qua object cause. (As mouse says, the image gives us a means to symbolize the event, not the other way round.)

So when I say that &quot;mass killers do probably glimpse the Adornian truth of things as at least one condition for pulling the trigger,&quot; I am indeed, by saying &quot;one condition,&quot; leaving plenty of room for surplus. That is actually the whole point of the post: mass killings are &quot;just&quot; gun-violence after all (a very small percentage of it at that!). There is nothing particularly &quot;evil&quot; about, as you say, the passage à l’acte (passage-a-lacked?) itself--at least not that much more than the orgasm our Humbert imagines at the pull of his trigger (a fantasy structure, by the way, Nabokov utterly deflates at the moment of Quilty&#039;s death: &quot;I hit him at very close range through the blankets [Quilty, indeed!], and then he lay back, and a big pink bubble with juvenile connotations formed on his lips, grew to the size of a toy balloon, and vanished&quot; [304].)

I just think the form of the surplus we are dealing with takes us to a dark place...the source of all silence. I think that these &quot;smart kids&quot; have found God, that this, moreover, is the form that local sacrifices to that God takes--under Capital.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the first place, I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s any accident that these shootings, at least beginning with Charles Whitman (and here, my god, do we not see the quintessential American &#8220;I&#8221;-o-cratic nature of these killings&#8211;of the lone gunmen&#8211;a sort of absolute song-of-myself&#8211;to these killings?)  through Eric Harris to Adam Lanza, take place in schools, which we may as well metonymize as the university discourse. A sort of revolt against Knowledge, then, in the name of a self-to-come. An attempt to be a Master, beyond book learning, which has ceased to be a form of knowledge. But even that doesn&#8217;t have the ring of truth to it. Why?</p>
<p>Now I&#8217;m pushing into empirical territory when I say that what unites most of these &#8220;wimpy kids&#8221; is that they are always &#8220;intelligent.&#8221; I can personally vouch for Eric Harris&#8211;he was not stupid. Strangely, I think calling them stupid gives them too much credit; in the same way that calling them evil or psychotic does (despite the risks inherent in turning those very terms into objects of fetish, academic or otherwise). We could hedge this claim by introducing the term &#8220;language game,&#8221; which renders all claims to intelligence a tautology, but that doesn&#8217;t change the structure of the particular form of violence here.  </p>
<p>So when I say Adorno &#8220;comes off as&#8221;&#8211;I think I&#8217;m hedging beyond a vernacular formulation, which takes us so close to jouissance, that this psychopathy is an illusion of discourse, an effect of ideological critique as such: nothing short of the attempt to be a master, which is the ignorance of lack&#8211;a much different concept than stupidity. I mean, this &#8220;work&#8221; we do here&#8211;it&#8217;s really quite insane!</p>
<p>So I&#8217;m not sure my claim is that, as you break it down so nicely,  &#8220;we should view Adorno’s vision of technology creating a sort of Grand Theft Auto citizen as the very psychopathic logic of the ‘wimpy white kids’ now murdering us.&#8221; I think that is the claim of a film like &#8220;Elephant,&#8221; which actually takes us into a video-game version of the event, as if to pre-empt any culturally conservative critique of cinematic representation qua object cause. (As mouse says, the image gives us a means to symbolize the event, not the other way round.)</p>
<p>So when I say that &#8220;mass killers do probably glimpse the Adornian truth of things as at least one condition for pulling the trigger,&#8221; I am indeed, by saying &#8220;one condition,&#8221; leaving plenty of room for surplus. That is actually the whole point of the post: mass killings are &#8220;just&#8221; gun-violence after all (a very small percentage of it at that!). There is nothing particularly &#8220;evil&#8221; about, as you say, the passage à l’acte (passage-a-lacked?) itself&#8211;at least not that much more than the orgasm our Humbert imagines at the pull of his trigger (a fantasy structure, by the way, Nabokov utterly deflates at the moment of Quilty&#8217;s death: &#8220;I hit him at very close range through the blankets [Quilty, indeed!], and then he lay back, and a big pink bubble with juvenile connotations formed on his lips, grew to the size of a toy balloon, and vanished&#8221; [304].)</p>
<p>I just think the form of the surplus we are dealing with takes us to a dark place&#8230;the source of all silence. I think that these &#8220;smart kids&#8221; have found God, that this, moreover, is the form that local sacrifices to that God takes&#8211;under Capital.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/#comment-23</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 01:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=663#comment-23</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@la manque. I thought I would quote in full what Lacan says about Marx, for he certainly does not say that Marx missed surplus-jouissance, in fact, he practically says the contrary:

“That is why I told you last year that in Marx the a [objet a], which is here, is recognized as functioning at the level that is articulated—on the basis of analytic discourse, not any of the others—as surplus jouissance. Here you have what Marx discovered as what actually happens at the level of surplus value.
“Of course, it wasn’t Marx who invented surplus value. It’s just that prior to him nobody knew what its place was. It has the same ambiguous place as the one I have just mentioned, that of excess work, of surplus work. “What does it pay in?” he says. “It pays in jouissance, precisely, and this has to go somewhere.
“What’s disturbing is that if one pays in jouissance, then one has got it, and then, once one has got it it is very urgent that one squander it. If one does not squander it, there will be all sorts of consequences” (Lacan, Seminar XVII: The Other Side of Psychoanalysis, p. 20).

Then later, he says, I think to clarify and also to defend the idea that the surplus jouissance of objet a is somehow prior to surplus value: “What Marx denounces is the spoliation of jouissance. And yet, this surplus value is a memorial to surplus jouissance, its equivalent of surplus jouissance. “Consumer society” derives its meaning from the fact that what makes it the “element,” in inverted commas, described as human is made the homogeneous equivalent of whatever surplus jouissance is produced by our industry—an imitation surplus jouissance, in a word” (p. 81.)

I place this here to defend Marx against Adorno, in a sense. For the program that Marx champions, you know the “workers of the world unite” is aimed at the complete upheaval of these “consequences” that occur when jouissance is squandered, when it is ‘gotten up’ in the form of a product; whereas Adorno laments the fact that products are always squandering jouissance within the brutal logic of a “consumer society” that he seems at a loss to escape: “The only responsible course is to deny oneself the ideological misuse of one’s own experience…by the shame of having air to breathe, in hell” (Minima Moralia, pp. 27-28) . 

Certainly doctrinaire Marxists treat this Adorno as a bourgeois imitation, as a product of capitalism. Yet, since I personally do not hold allegiance to one side or the other, I think that we can reread your very provocative claim within the ambiguity of these comparisons (Marx and Adorno, surplus value and jouissance): the claim that we should view Adorno’s vision of technology creating a sort of Grand Theft Auto citizen as the very psychopathic logic of the ‘wimpy white kids’ now murdering us. I think you are totally right. I think these kids believe they can fulfill this “law of pure functionality”, and yet it is exactly because I think this that I do not give Adorno ‘no mean bargain’. 

Adorno says later in Minima Moralia “only Freud’s exaggerations are true”, so I think it not entirely unfair to apply this rubric to Adorno himself. And in this case, I think we can only agree that the limit of the dream of “consumer society” is this “law of pure functionality”, one where indeed death drive is annulled because there is no more surplus. But this is exactly where Marx does not miss surplus jouissance in his term surplus value (and deductively, if he does follow him in some capacity, neither does Adorno); for the surplus value is exactly that which makes the fantasy of pure functionality forever incomplete. And this is why even if these kids try to get there, try to embody it, well as Lacan says above: “If one does not squander jouissance, there will be all sorts of consequences.” Which is another way of saying, you have to squander it, it must be squandered. And this too is why I will repeat what I said in another comment: I do not perceive these kids as psychotic, I do not think they actually exist in this pure law of functionality, they dream of it, which is much different. To me they represent very clearly the passage à l’acte of the hysteric—which, indeed, Lacan tells us in Seminar X, is suicide. And this is another way of saying that they simply cannot bear the anxiety of surplus. And yes, I think Adorno barely could, though he did, in shame, pobrecito...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@la manque. I thought I would quote in full what Lacan says about Marx, for he certainly does not say that Marx missed surplus-jouissance, in fact, he practically says the contrary:</p>
<p>“That is why I told you last year that in Marx the a [objet a], which is here, is recognized as functioning at the level that is articulated—on the basis of analytic discourse, not any of the others—as surplus jouissance. Here you have what Marx discovered as what actually happens at the level of surplus value.<br />
“Of course, it wasn’t Marx who invented surplus value. It’s just that prior to him nobody knew what its place was. It has the same ambiguous place as the one I have just mentioned, that of excess work, of surplus work. “What does it pay in?” he says. “It pays in jouissance, precisely, and this has to go somewhere.<br />
“What’s disturbing is that if one pays in jouissance, then one has got it, and then, once one has got it it is very urgent that one squander it. If one does not squander it, there will be all sorts of consequences” (Lacan, Seminar XVII: The Other Side of Psychoanalysis, p. 20).</p>
<p>Then later, he says, I think to clarify and also to defend the idea that the surplus jouissance of objet a is somehow prior to surplus value: “What Marx denounces is the spoliation of jouissance. And yet, this surplus value is a memorial to surplus jouissance, its equivalent of surplus jouissance. “Consumer society” derives its meaning from the fact that what makes it the “element,” in inverted commas, described as human is made the homogeneous equivalent of whatever surplus jouissance is produced by our industry—an imitation surplus jouissance, in a word” (p. 81.)</p>
<p>I place this here to defend Marx against Adorno, in a sense. For the program that Marx champions, you know the “workers of the world unite” is aimed at the complete upheaval of these “consequences” that occur when jouissance is squandered, when it is ‘gotten up’ in the form of a product; whereas Adorno laments the fact that products are always squandering jouissance within the brutal logic of a “consumer society” that he seems at a loss to escape: “The only responsible course is to deny oneself the ideological misuse of one’s own experience…by the shame of having air to breathe, in hell” (Minima Moralia, pp. 27-28) . </p>
<p>Certainly doctrinaire Marxists treat this Adorno as a bourgeois imitation, as a product of capitalism. Yet, since I personally do not hold allegiance to one side or the other, I think that we can reread your very provocative claim within the ambiguity of these comparisons (Marx and Adorno, surplus value and jouissance): the claim that we should view Adorno’s vision of technology creating a sort of Grand Theft Auto citizen as the very psychopathic logic of the ‘wimpy white kids’ now murdering us. I think you are totally right. I think these kids believe they can fulfill this “law of pure functionality”, and yet it is exactly because I think this that I do not give Adorno ‘no mean bargain’. </p>
<p>Adorno says later in Minima Moralia “only Freud’s exaggerations are true”, so I think it not entirely unfair to apply this rubric to Adorno himself. And in this case, I think we can only agree that the limit of the dream of “consumer society” is this “law of pure functionality”, one where indeed death drive is annulled because there is no more surplus. But this is exactly where Marx does not miss surplus jouissance in his term surplus value (and deductively, if he does follow him in some capacity, neither does Adorno); for the surplus value is exactly that which makes the fantasy of pure functionality forever incomplete. And this is why even if these kids try to get there, try to embody it, well as Lacan says above: “If one does not squander jouissance, there will be all sorts of consequences.” Which is another way of saying, you have to squander it, it must be squandered. And this too is why I will repeat what I said in another comment: I do not perceive these kids as psychotic, I do not think they actually exist in this pure law of functionality, they dream of it, which is much different. To me they represent very clearly the passage à l’acte of the hysteric—which, indeed, Lacan tells us in Seminar X, is suicide. And this is another way of saying that they simply cannot bear the anxiety of surplus. And yes, I think Adorno barely could, though he did, in shame, pobrecito&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
