<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Not I &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/not_i/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chronic foregret &#8211; speech in time</title>
		<link>/h-b/chronic-foregret-speech-in-time/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 02:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1249</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Speech in time, hailing from a future unknown. Heading through a past too known, or most too barely unknown as to be any consolation. No sweet souls here, thank you very much; they are always the first to get eaten. Not that my soul was eaten, mind you, after all I am writing this prose [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speech in time, hailing from a future unknown. Heading through a past too known, or most too barely unknown as to be any consolation. No sweet souls here, thank you very much; they are always the first to get eaten. Not that my soul was eaten, mind you, after all I am writing this prose in a somewhat hopeful note of regret, or a symphony of melancholic celebration. Everybody loves a party, everybody. Here’s a rule with no exceptions, which makes it into a law; Law assuch really. And that’s precisely why I find it so depressing.<span id="more-1249"></span></p>
<p>Last night came and went, and here it comes again, or is to come, again. How do we know that the night that comes is not the last one? That we are not getting some used, eternally recurring compromise of a tired God; “just don’t make it too horrible” was what, eventually, all those prayers and hopes, all those Hockey fans and desperate housewives and husbands, all those kids wishing to finally kiss this so-and-so girl with the certain hair color, a certain anthropomorphic outlook that nonetheless proves different enough to offer something different. And even that difference, here as elsewhere, here as elsewhere, draws down via friction to a certain anonymous hum of the ultra-tenable, the ultimately possible. Was there an art that had been wasted here, was there ever a sure destination that this train we’re on did not go to while driving over some of us, driving us to life and death, or to a (quite so sorry) average inbetween? I swear in this, to this, at this; for reasons I cannot arbitrate. You may think this is a stream of consciousness, you may think, they tell me, that you’re going crazy, but anyone whose been at the end of THIS rope would probably never adhere to such a lonely calling, and just pick up and leave. A non-average existence is what the artist may be cursed with; and so the ultimate usurpation of this sentence is to kill all art. We will show you, God of the mediocre, we will show you that slaves are not meant to be tolerated, broken, recombined. We will drown you in our own – not blood, but – bile, sweat, every salty or sour existence, or fluid, that we can get our hearts on. This is the meaning of what Burroughs calls junk. You don’t believe me, just wait and see. Better yet – take a look behind you. It is already there.</p>
<p>A sidewalk careens forth, and on toward a traffic light, just beyond the next intersection where the druggies get their fix. Still behind us, but this time, once, again, once again this time – in a used past. What to do with the smell, this is the only thing we have not been taught. Even the touch can be either melted to a velvet or be berated to a tank’s sliding chains. No middle ground between those – they are the fucking middle ground. Why do you insist on tormenting us, someone, not me, may ask. I do not ask, anymore. And when I did it was usually to find the bathroom, or why the sign to it has been placed upside-down, or pointing to the door.</p>
<p>I know now that my only mistake was not peeing on the door when I had the chance.</p>
<p>Of course this goes to many other words, to many other instances: those languages I could but never speak, those tongues I could but never twist-and-sample; those lasers I should have but never put my eyes against to engage in a somewhat fair or unfair fight. When it comes to fighting, I feel, now, that the possibility of its being “unfair” is an essential part of the fight itself, and hence of its fairness. Nobody understands Friedrich, I tell Nietzsche who is always hovering behind me with a bored stare. And of course a bored stare from Nietzsche is always an accusing stare. Not because he’s dead, but because he’s still so much very more alive than what I perceive to be myself. Bastard, I curse, You’re no better than those two bit-whores who dumped my ass – becoming animal and smiles and all – just two hours ago at the train station. Hell would have to be something like that – sitting in the same place, going to the same destination, with people who don’t quite know how to tell you that you’re not very pleasant, that they would really just like you to leave, or leave whatever it is you have to give, or to say, and then please vanish. I am not really sure which is worse.</p>
<p>Where was I going with this? Oh right, Hell. Yes, so on the train, with strangers, strangers that only know you enough to dislike you, not even enough to dislike what you represent. I don’t know why they keep saying “it’s not personal” – these first impressions. How much more personal can they be? Perhaps repeating them, like a mantra, will get us to somehow stop believing them, like someone repeating “it’s gonna get worse before it gets better” or that “it’s all going to be alright.” Such cruel lies, such awful promises. You don’t want to get caught with your tongue twist-sampling one of those – they’ll confiscate your waste-buds and give you back some taste-dispensers &#8211; so your tongue will get to sucking all that junk off whatever it is they happen to chance-encounter. Is this the figure of the intellectual, the other possibility of killing the artist, or avenging a God that made the artist even thinkable on such a planet, in such a place, under such circumstances, over this maddened existence? We should all have been dead poets or gardeners, that’s what the signs say. Never trust those signs but I do trust those two-bit whores from before. The first that didn’t and wouldn’t say, the second who would say that she did but didn’t. They don’t amount to the same. One of them was prettier. And why whores, I wonder? Perhaps it had something to do with the ease by which I discovered their mechanisms of concealment. Sex is only incidental to the whore. In a different culture, for a different breed, as if we could imagine such things in this velvet tank of a world that was left here to roll with us to rot. Sex was only incidental, because we needed new blood for old wars, because we require death to spice our morning coffees with; the paper, the toast&#8230; It is more about how you apply your careful manipulation on your fellow woe-unto-man. Have some ethics, man! At least show that you made an effort; don’t just give it over like that, unthought, automatic, free. Men can be whores, no question – they just need to have something or time to lose those bastards. Am I a man? Every time I think I am I also thing I should also be calling myself brown.</p>
<p>There’s a university in the United States calls itself Brown you know. I was there just four hours ago.</p>
<p>Somebody took their time to construct this maze of unpossibility. Someone took their effort to betray these symptoms of betrayal. Gotta respect that, respect that even at the price of my own pain. Not sacrifice, not giving in order to give homage to something else, something greater. No. Fuck that. Like Morrisson wept, we&#8217;re here and we want it all and now, and it is precisely that all and now that harbors (t)his entire, present pain. There’s a Monty Python cartoon, one of Terry Gilliam’s funny montage jokes, of a hammer beating down on some pile of trash or other, which randomizes it into a perfect war machine, a single motorized hand holding a gun. What are you going to do with this gun? The liberals ask. It’s either Wilhelm Tell or suicide, in any case it’s vanity, and only our other side – our white darker side, those whose only attribute is the color of the back of their heads – do. Otherwise you’ll be as * insert psychological/moral diagnosis here * as they are, and will be treated with the same patience and decrepitude as we treat them. Treated with the same maltreatment, same racism, same white-out comments said behind our smiling full teethed eyes and gazing mouths.</p>
<p>And not that they didn’t like me over there, mind you. But something about being liked by those you don’t like gives me the shivers every time. “He didn’t like his friends” is a hell of a tombstone. This is what’s spray painted on the side of this bloody train. This is why I’m trying to get off. Can’t you see that I’m in the process, the long, drawn out, excruciating, escapist process, of drilling a hole in the side so as to. I’m not afraid of the speed, mind you, nor the gaps, but mostly it’s the friction that gets me. Friction is
<div>Completely a but from <a href="http://www.beatyourtruck.com/uibxi/buy-cialis-online">buy cialis online www.beatyourtruck.com</a> because dad it curl free skin <a href="http://www.premium-me.com/mfbfl/ventolin-hfa-no-prescription">www.premium-me.com ventolin hfa no prescription</a> the. And they <a href="http://www.fermag.com/qot/can-i-buy-albuterol-over-the-counter">can i buy albuterol over the counter www.fermag.com</a> food. Some not cream nails, if <a title="healthy male viagra" href="http://www.fermag.com/qot/healthy-male-viagra">healthy male viagra</a> great just desk the and didn&#8217;t.</div>
<p>  what the Germans called gift – too much of it and it kills you, makes you seriously ill, lays hold of your thoughts and body like a giant parasite would a smaller victim-host. It is, in a very accu(ra)te sense, poison. Friction is the poison that we are administered in little doses &#8212; call it a cruel joke. Chemisst, that’s what we should all have been, against this indifferent, bored God. &#8220;Better living through chemistry” is not what it’s about; better killing through it. Such an optimist Nietzsche was, God bless him. We still have not found the right compound to kill this god. Or not just as yet.</p>
<p>Nobody said that the only entity left to blame would be this old, shaking, grey, non-tasty beggar; like fate she&#8217;s all but blind to you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8230;that this should be poetry?</title>
		<link>/h-b/that-this-should-be-poetry/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 23:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1079</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Coup de Grâce (to deserve a lover) &#160; You cannot cling to consolations they decay like a safe deposit box whose code turns out to be the burglar’s birthday (any burglar’s birthday). Now only the banality of disabuse is sudden &#8212; &#160; A hair-trigger dial and an indifferent explosive will chip(s) off the old block [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coup de Grâce (to deserve a lover)</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>You cannot cling to</p>
<p>consolations they</p>
<p>decay</p>
<p>like a safe deposit box whose code turns out</p>
<p>to be the burglar’s birthday (any</p>
<p>burglar’s birthday).</p>
<p>Now only the banality of disabuse is sudden &#8212;<span id="more-1079"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A hair-trigger dial and</p>
<p>an indifferent explosive will</p>
<p>chip(s) off the old block</p>
<p>(someone’s got your number</p>
<p>not knowing any different sees you falling to the floor</p>
<p>with ears of sound and fury</p>
<p>going into shock &#8212;)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>But sudden proves banal only in syncopated moments:</p>
<p>electric fingers stretch a quick defibrillated death; a caring urgency</p>
<p>draws near a mouth under your nose</p>
<p>to plead devotion out your breath (I &lt;3-attack you) &#8212;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>the eyes turn out, I suppose</p>
<p>neither nor</p>
<p>(a kiss on the cheek;</p>
<p>to see other people…)</p>
<p>but to turn this wormy moment under cover – once more unto the tomb</p>
<p>my friends</p>
<p>one more good turn</p>
<p>so’s to deserve another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Poem What</title>
		<link>/h-b/another-poem-what/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 02:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Amemory After the laundry, after several showers, After the malevolent decree of memory performed its painful trace And I could wait no more without (grace) becoming &#8211; complicated, committed, contaminated words that just wouldn&#8217;t wash anymore. Not to mention the smell, your smell as such an open invitation &#8211; like a gala for demons to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Amemory</strong></em></p>
<p>After the laundry, after</p>
<p>several showers,</p>
<p>After the malevolent decree of memory performed its painful trace <span id="more-912"></span></p>
<p>And I could wait no more without (grace)</p>
<p>becoming &#8211;</p>
<p>complicated, committed, contaminated</p>
<p>words that just wouldn&#8217;t wash anymore.</p>
<p>Not to mention the smell,</p>
<p>your smell</p>
<p>as such an open invitation &#8211; like a gala for demons to come by and</p>
<p>Mostly ignore &#8211; &#8211; &#8211;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After so much water and regret, what&#8217;s left of you is merely</p>
<p>chemicals</p>
<p>liquids crafted for that single purpose of</p>
<p>the a-nostalgic runner</p>
<p>who nevertheless knows he&#8217;s</p>
<p>running toward the very same party and</p>
<p>the very same wall.</p>
<p>Those sprinkled streets will all die down at once</p>
<p>A thousand and one voices (now a thousand minus one..)</p>
<p>Tonight and I will have found me wandering around</p>
<p>a memory-image</p>
<p>Chasing me away with some soap and promises; yes</p>
<p>you will forget; yes</p>
<p>the future always holds a lie</p>
<p>against what past</p>
<p>is left</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>proof that there&#8217;s a god and that</p>
<p>nevertheless&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>sometimes&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>you immerse in a white, floating space</p>
<p>descending toward you from above</p>
<p>and life sings in you and your face is</p>
<p>literally</p>
<p>lit</p>
<p>with love,</p>
<p>everything about you is wide open to receive, and</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>then it  blinds you with amore familiar,</p>
<p>antiseptic</p>
<p>pain. Soap, my love,</p>
<p>nothing but soap          &#8211; &#8211;</p>
<p>not even the consolation</p>
<p>of an acid rain; the future sneers:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>but an ugly, stupid cry</p>
<p>of pain</p>
<p>and soapy, antiseptic tears</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Thinker&#8217;s Gamble (don&#8217;t know what&#8230;)</title>
		<link>/h-b/my-thinkers-gamble-dont-know-what/</link>
		<comments>/h-b/my-thinkers-gamble-dont-know-what/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 22:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Derrida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fetish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=872</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My Lover&#8217;s Gamble (&#8230; that is) &#160; Do you love someone or do you love some-thing about someone? Is it true love or is it an illusion? Had to be a philosopher that thought up &#8220;true love&#8221;. Had to be. Tracing it back to some thing is not a mere homicidal gesture against love, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>My Lover&#8217;s Gamble (&#8230; that is)</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Do you love someone or do you love some-thing about someone?</p>
<p><span id="more-872"></span></p>
<p>Is it true love or is it an illusion?</p>
<p>Had to be a philosopher that thought up &#8220;true love&#8221;.</p>
<p>Had to be.</p>
<p>Tracing it back to some thing is not a mere homicidal gesture</p>
<p>against love,</p>
<p>but is its challenge and its tease: &#8220;let&#8217;s see</p>
<p>how you can get out of <em>that</em> one!&#8221; the thinker tells</p>
<p>himself;</p>
<p>&#8220;let&#8217;s see if you can take &#8220;what&#8221; you give; <em>make</em> it into</p>
<p>a &#8220;what&#8221;,</p>
<p>and see what happen(s)&#8221;. It&#8217;s a gamble, no</p>
<p>question. We thinkers, on these terms, live truly the edge (because</p>
<p>we suspect our limited engagement to be finite,</p>
<p>but then also become addicted to its emerging truths:</p>
<p>They are beauty and happiness and depth &#8212;</p>
<p>love&#8217;s treacherous companions).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/h-b/my-thinkers-gamble-dont-know-what/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Trouble with Resolutions</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/</link>
		<comments>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 18:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[metaphysicalvillain]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=784</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am typing in the living room of my chilly, dimly lit apartment. This Chicago morning is blandly gray—nothing new under the wan wintry sun. But it’s December 31st, the one day of the year that harbors the promise of beautiful novelty. We will soon flee from ourselves and become completed humans. We will vow [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am typing in the living room of my chilly, dimly lit apartment. This Chicago morning is blandly gray—nothing new under the wan wintry sun. But it’s December 31<sup>st</sup>, the one day of the year that harbors the promise of beautiful novelty. We will soon flee from ourselves and become completed humans. We will vow to make a minor adjustment, which also stands in for every adjustment we possibly could make in order to perfect ourselves. We will start again. We will make New Years resolutions.</p>
<p><span id="more-784"></span></p>
<p>What is the fantasy that goes by this name? A New Years resolution is a symbolic game we play with ourselves, but in the midst of others; we seize the fact that while midnight of January 1<sup>st</sup> is a purely arbitrary moment in time, it nonetheless carries the weight of a collective ritual. The New Years resolution is the perfect expression of what Slavoj Žižek calls fetishistic disavowal. In other words, we stubbornly believe in the efficacy of the event of New Years even if we “see through” its trite falsity. We say something like, “I know very well that this date is meaningless, but nonetheless, I can use it to change myself, etc.” The practice of resolving on December 31 is extremely tantalizing: I’m in no position to ridicule it, if only because it’s quite likely that at some point today I’ll start spouting about something I’ll do differently in 2013.</p>
<p>Resolutions don’t occur in a vacuum, but are communally inflected. If I were the last man on earth there would be no meaning to my “resolution”; it’s not that by asserting a resolution, I become a law unto myself. Were that the case I could simply make a silent promise to myself. I feel compelled to articulate my resolution to others, thereby making a spectacle of my own new policy. It’s no accident that New Years resolutions are so often spoken, advertised, argued about, but forgotten within a week. New Years resolutions tend to generate a collective narcissistic frenzy that quickly burns out.</p>
<p>What’s curious about the term “resolution,” in this context, is that it paradoxically evokes an ending while signifying a beginning. It expresses two seemingly contradictory desires—to begin again and to resolve, to wrap up. We seek to inaugurate a new stretch of time but in such a way that resolves this time with the certainty of a self-imposed necessity. We negate ourselves and complete ourselves in the same gesture. But if we push this thought to its limit and imagine its consequences, we realize that when practice stems from “resolution,” it tends to undermine itself.</p>
<p>The self-defeating quality of resolution is the theme of Kafka’s aptly titled short story, “Resolutions.” Kafka’s speaker imagines the ease with which he can become less miserable; all it takes is a little will. “Defy my own feelings, welcome A. enthusiastically supposing he comes to see me…” The rub, however, is that “one single slip…will stop the whole process, easy and painful alike, and I will have to shrink back into my own circle again.” In a vicious parody of a self-help manual, Kafka’s speaker offers a prescription for how to “keep” a resolution:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;So perhaps the best resource is to meet everything passively, to make yourself an inert mass, and, if you feel that you are being carried away, not to let yourself be lured into taking a single unnecessary step, to stare at others with the eyes of an animal, to feel no compunction, in short, with your own hand to throttle down whatever ghostly life remains in you, that is, to enlarge the final peace of the graveyard and let nothing survive save that.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, if I am not to fuck up I must renounce life itself in all its contingency. If I am to begin again and conclude in a single stroke—as the term “resolution” implies—I must become an “inert mass,” impervious to whatever might threaten my resolve.</p>
<p>Now, one could object that I’ve taken this too far, and treated “resolution” too literally. After all some New Years resolutions seem to succeed, and moreover, there are degrees of success. I resolve to quit smoking and slip up once or twice during the year, but surely even this counts as an improvement, and hence testifies to the value of the resolution. The point of Kafka’s tale, however, is not that, empirically, all New Years resolutions will fail. Instead, Kafka suggests that “resolution” might be the wrong concept to employ.</p>
<p>I shall propose an alternative—<em>repetition</em>. Those “resolutions” which succeed are actually repetitions, fueled by neither gimmicky symbolic rituals nor by delusions of completion or perfection.</p>
<p>To repeat is to have done with the fantasy of absolute beginning and absolute ending. It is to exist in the middle of things, unanchored by temporal markers, and nonetheless persist in some passionate engagement. If “resolution” evokes the cruelty of what Freud called the superego—that internalized, punishing force that constantly monitors your activity—then repetition evokes the difficult work of <em>love</em>. Kierkegaard saw the intimate connection between love and repetition: If I am to authentically repeat, I must love, that is, commit myself to some object or pursuit without the crutch of recent novelty or future guarantee. Moreover, I must not only learn to love what I repeat; I must learn to love repetition itself. For, by repeating, I am not simply doing some<em>thing</em> over and over, but on a second-order level, repeating the act of repetition itself. If resolution can’t be loved, it’s because it is over too quickly. A flash as bright and ephemeral as a firework in Times Square. Repetition, on the contrary, is loveable, on the condition that we can love the banality of commitment.</p>
<p>Like Kierkegaard, Nietzsche possessed an unusual passion for repetition. In one of my favorite passages from <em>Gay Science</em>, “By doing we forgo,” Nietzsche attacks moralities that enjoin us to “renounce!”—moralities that invariably underpin New Years resolutions—in favor an ethos of repetition. Nietzsche praises “moralities that impel me to do something again and again from morning till evening, and to dream of it at night, and to think of nothing else than doing this <em>well</em>, as well as <em>I</em> alone can.” For Nietzsche, one should seek to “forgo,” not “renounce.” What is the difference? Renouncing begins with a prohibition (and again, it’s no accident that New Years resolutions most often, implicitly or explicitly, take the form of self-imposed laws). Forgoing, on the other hand, is an effect of an alternative, <em>positive</em> pursuit. To forgo is to allow exhaust to dissipate while doing something else. A bad habit does indeed fall off, but as a result of repetition rather than prohibition. By doing we forgo, and by repeating we transform.</p>
<p>Take this not as an attack on the aspiration undergirding New Years resolutions, but on the form of resolution itself. The conceptual shift from resolution to repetition may seem trivial, but sometimes trivial shifts can produce the greatest consequences. Could 2013 be a year of repetitions rather than resolutions? One can only hope and hope and hope…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>punctum’s aliens &#8211; a poem</title>
		<link>/h-b/punctums-aliens-a-poem/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 11:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[here’s to missing the point and not because it would make our story endless our story of color and vain of black pixel droplets flying towards these impenetrable dark surfaces of yours, as if they belonged to us &#160; and not because it is better to brush up against them come up at or toward [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>here’s to missing the point</p>
<p><span id="more-265"></span></p>
<p>and not because</p>
<p>it would make our story endless our story</p>
<p>of color and vain</p>
<p>of black pixel droplets flying towards</p>
<p>these impenetrable dark surfaces of yours, as if</p>
<p>they belonged to us</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>and not because</p>
<p>it is better to brush up against them</p>
<p>come up at or toward</p>
<p>a gentle something greeting what had left already, left</p>
<p>with a kissing regret, and not because</p>
<p>fear would have us</p>
<p>clawing at this mystery as you, as I</p>
<p>pull ourselves toward some even darker spaces</p>
<p>shrouded in</p>
<p>blue,</p>
<p>music files its missing-tune reports and yet</p>
<p>they will, I know, be coming like us all too soon</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>and not</p>
<p>because</p>
<p>we ever shared the same crime, that there was ever a time</p>
<p>where we shared the same crime</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>no time was broken</p>
<p>a miracle said something and left, and someone</p>
<p>always some <em>one</em></p>
<p>failed toward its grasp and</p>
<p>not because</p>
<p>this fault</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>all other punctuations do point toward</p>
<p>the same one point &#8211; &#8211; missing the point</p>
<p>since that would make us criminals in time, it could</p>
<p>make us disappear into each other</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PH. 101</title>
		<link>/h-b/phenomenosophy-101/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 18:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Not I]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://phlocalwp.com/?p=10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-262" title="Phenomenosophy4" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Phenomenosophy42-500x374.png" alt="" width="500" height="374" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Phenomenosophy42-500x374.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Phenomenosophy42.png 953w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
