<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Coprophagia &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/coprophagia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Random Access Pocket: Can Daft Punk Find the Pocket?</title>
		<link>/peaty/random-access-pocket-can-daft-punk-find-the-pocket/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 13:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Peaty]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1416</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tom Hawking’s recent drubbing of Daft Punk’s new “Random Access Memories” LP in Flavorwire (“Why Daft Punk’s ‘Random Access Memories’ Won’t Save Electronic Music”: Flavorwire) enjoys the distinction of having ignited a small fire under the rears of some millennial, electronic music fans. That said, my response is less about Daft Punk, and least of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tom Hawking’s recent drubbing of Daft Punk’s new “Random Access Memories” LP in Flavorwire (“Why Daft Punk’s ‘Random Access Memories’ Won’t Save Electronic Music”: <a title="flavor" href="http://flavorwire.com/391419/why-daft-punks-random-access-memories-wont-save-electronic-music/" target="_blank">Flavorwire</a>) enjoys the distinction of having ignited a small fire under the rears of some millennial, electronic music fans. That said, my response is less about Daft Punk, and least of all about Hawking’s harangue. <span id="more-1416"></span>Call it a non-writer’s excuse (my excuse) to vent about the proliferation of the “Indie-Electro Pop” landscape.</p>
<p>Having recently gotten sucked into a corner of the EDM vortex myself, I found Hawking’s piece admittedly provocative. To start, I violated one of my most sacrosanct conventions: I read the review <i>prior</i> to listening to “Random Access Memory.” Mea culpe. <i>Meae culpae’ing</i> aside, I feel any “artwork” that elicits such a visceral kneejerk response from critics – whether it be visual, auditory, etc. – is at least doing <i>something</i>. So I figured I had to go listen to the new Daft Punk.</p>
<p>Hawking’s vitriol nudged me to revisit and articulate a recurring, yet formative theory I’d cobbled together last year about the current state of “Indie-Electro Pop” and “EDM” – well, more accurately, a rant inflicted on poor friends. At the risk of gross generalization, I’d say that these “indie EDM” genres (even though they sell out large stadiums now) have predominantly “lost the pocket,” to appropriate the jazz slang. How is “the pocket” empirically exposed to the non-musician / music-aficionado? Well, first off, it’s not such an “empirical” thing, rather an electric, magical feel generated by musicians interlocking on the deepest of levels (please refer to “Pocket Philosophy” by Tyra Neftzger in <i>All About Jazz</i>: <a href="http://www.allaboutjazz.com/php/article.php?id=17487#.Uaa3AJV5jWF">http://www.allaboutjazz.com/php/article.php?id=17487#.Uaa3AJV5jWF</a>).</p>
<p>Having first “felt the pocket” in a college band and then later having a rigorous jazz ensemble director attempt to technically deconstruct it, I came to one major conclusion: the pocket (for me, at least) not only pertains primarily to the rhythm of a tune, but more to the metaphysical, nuanced feeling generated by the synergy of the rhythm players themselves (bass and drums at the core, yet often including guitar, and keys as well). Some electronic producers or DJs attempt to approach this by syncopating their beats. Either way, call it a magical “groove within a groove,” or a “meta-groove” for the semiotic nerds in the house.</p>
<p>I had subsequently become obsessed with seeking this “rhythmic pocket” – both as a musical aspiration in my own playing and as something I sought as a listener. I realized it was something achieved by the best live performers, those who enjoy a seemingly telepathic connection through the art of actually <i>listening</i> &amp; <i>responding </i>to one another in a completely unconscious way. This is not to say that the pocket does not exist in electronic music; look no further than the groundbreaking, progressive proto-EDM beats of Amon Tobin of the Chemical Brothers (although they’re often electronically sampling O.P.P. – other people’s pockets). For instance, one fundamental, technical facet of the pocket concerns the most nuanced of rhythmic-interpretation within a given 4/4 time signature: suppose the drummer is consistently hitting the “one” (first beat of a measure) precisely <i>on top</i> of the beat like a metronome, while the bassist is interpreting the “one” a millisecond <i>behind</i> the beat. Swing music would not exist – nor be “swung” – without this rhythmic device. This nearly imperceptible <i>rhythmic-hiccup</i> can generate the most intoxicating tension and is typically deployed by any competent band, even on the most intuitive of levels. Shifting of the pocket within a tune sometimes occurs when the most competent players consciously switch up roles regarding who is counting before, on top, or behind the beat. A classic example in popular music: Miles Davis inaugurated the super-cool, often phrasing his horn licks <i>behind the beat</i>, just like Daft Punk or the Chemical Brothers inaugurated the “Superstar DJ” by producing their keen, electronic sound. Once the pocket is established, it is inevitably perceived by the entire band, therefore feeding the audience, an excitement which then returns back into the band itself.</p>
<p>Call it a meta-pocket feedback loop. This is the rhythmic stuff of magic.</p>
<p>So back to my primary complaint: i.e. my not <i>feeling the pocket</i>, or “magic” in so much of the contemporary indie roundup I otherwise enjoy. While admitting a certain predilection for the zeitgeist sound typified by groups like Phantogram, MGMT, Washed Out, Justice, Cut Copy, Vampire Weekend, LCD Soundsystem, Sh*t Robot, RAC (Remix Artist Collective), Purity Ring, M83, and of course the Daft Punk party hits of the last decade, I leave most tracks feeling malnourished or unsatisfied; as if I’ve been seduced by an entity who at most wishes to deliver their beats in the most rhythmically deadpan way possible – dare I say “soulless”.</p>
<p>One way I think about this zeitgeist’s place in music is by trying to identify the moment when Indie-Pop and EDM’s timely arrival caused such music to explode. I would consider it a counter-movement, or antidote to the funky, gratuitous, and live instrumental “noodling” that came to typify and ultimately bore the “jam band” followers. But at least a lot of the improvised music from the “jam band” period was humanistic and full of life – it had “pocket.”</p>
<p>I perceive Daft Punk’s new album as an obvious attempt to reintroduce the pocket to the masses. Of course it’s sad that it takes contemporary pop artists such as Daft Punk to merely recycle / regurgitate previous trends in music, a practice which can unfortunately be compared to those of the fashion industry. You’ve been around for a little while when you start noticing your favorite shirts from college or even highschool hanging on racks in “vintage” stores, or music from your childhood being sampled by the latest “EDM” DJ superstars.</p>
<p>The “best moments” of Random Access Memories (of which there are too few) can never hold a candle to the more nuanced, harmonically advanced pockets of say Herbie Hancock classics from the 70s or 80s, such as “Secrets” or “Mr. Hands” (or a plethora of other more innovative talent from both past and present). However, I must mildly applaud these mainstream DJs (golf clap style) for a humble attempt to sew the pocket back into the pants of popular music. Those more ambitious music fans are likely aware of the relatively big underground DJ scene in most cities that has been consciously ignoring EDM in favor of soulful beats (such as Scottie B, DJ Scribe, etc).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not a critique of online dating, not exactly a critique of Marx, definitely a critique of Alain Badiou&#8217;s theory of love</title>
		<link>/j-r/not-a-critique-of-online-dating-not-exactly-a-critique-of-marx-definitely-a-critique-of-alain-badious-theory-of-love/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 23:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wealth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=881</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two readings have shunted me (it is not willful!) in the direction of this essay about online dating. (Though, in truth, this essay merely defends the ambiguous status of online dating and is by no means a phenomeno-cultural study.) The first is a passage written by Karl Marx in his now very much published “unpublished [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-897" title="okcupid" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/okcupid-500x313.png" alt="" width="360" height="226" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/okcupid-500x313.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/02/okcupid-1024x642.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/02/okcupid.png 1130w" sizes="(max-width: 360px) 100vw, 360px" /></p>
<p>Two readings have shunted me (it is not willful!) in the direction of this essay about online dating. (Though, in truth, this essay merely defends the ambiguous status of online dating and is by no means a phenomeno-cultural study.) The first is a passage written by Karl Marx in his now very much published “unpublished Manuscripts” <span id="more-881"></span> wherein he all too briefly, yet rather provocatively, asserts that we can perceive the justice of the material relations of a society by observing the relationship between men and women in said society. To put it starkly, he states, “…this relationship reveals in a sensuous form, reduced to an observable fact, the extent to which the human essence has become nature for man or nature has become the human essence for man. It is possible to judge from this relationship the entire level of development of mankind (Marx, p. 347).”</p>
<p>I intend to put this statement into context with the second reading, which I associate with this first one because it comes from perhaps the most famous (or second most famous) Marxist writer of our age, Alain Badiou, who offers in a published interview <em>In Praise of Love</em> (a title borrowed from Godard’s movie) a rather glib dismissal of online dating.  Quite simply, he believes that online dating prevents the chance-encounter necessary for the event of love.  In what will be a concentrated refutation of this assertion, I must dissuade anyone from believing my central wish is to recover the sanctity of online dating from the ideas of philosophers; more interesting to me is the utter lack of thought or critical aptitude on which this bold and manly logic subsists, so much so that it reveals Badiou’s particularly unscientific Marxism, a Marxism which does not even turn to Marx for assistance, but instead siphons from Marx nothing but the crudest of utopic (perhaps Christian) notions, Badiou’s famous truth-procedure concept, in the ‘brain-act’ of valuing the chance-encounter over the online one. So my interest in these two texts in coordination with online dating and my own experience of it lies in the question of material alienation in its most abstract sense (is it absolute? etc.), and the way in which we or specifically Badiou like to imagine that certain events can occur to help overcome this condition. I will state from the outset that alienation is indeed exemplified by online dating, but not in such a way to make online dating exceptionally alienating; for me, online dating has always been just as alienating, just as inorganic, just as unromantic as every other method of sexual pursuit. I mean, is the oldest profession not the gold standard for this kind of alienation?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s contextualize Marx&#8217;s quote above: his conclusion about bearing witness to the relationship between men and women follows a critique of what he calls “vulgar communism [<em>rohen Kommunismus</em>]”, a communism which instead of eradicating private property transforms it into a (<em>sui</em>)societal venture (what Marx calls <em>universal</em> private property). Though Marx often bashes these unscientific utopic visions <em>ala</em> Proudhon, here he seems to generalize his critique by imagining that a vulgar communist world would institute a “community of women” prostituted among all the men of the community. “One might say that this idea of a community of women is the revealed secret of this as yet wholly crude and unthinking communism. Just as women are to go from marriage into general prostitution, so the whole world of wealth – i.e. the objective essence of man – is to make the transition from the relation of exclusive marriage with the private owner to the relation of universal prostitution with the community (Marx, p. 346).”</p>
<p>I in no light intend to compare online dating to this conceit (certainly men and women are both universally prostituting themselves on some level in virtual space), what I would like to stress is that Marx’s final conclusion about the relationship between men and women is a conclusion that has both the merit and flaw of suggestion: he intimates a possibility that transcends both marriage and social prostitution, while, very much like the communist vision itself,  leaving the details in the dark.</p>
<p>I mean to say, we have nothing if not one of these tautological moralisms: when man is at his best so will his relation to women be at its best. Marx uses the term “species-being [<em>Gattungswesen</em>]” to suggest this tautology, to suggest the <em>natural</em> social order of man. Since our best would be a state (non-state) with neither private nor public (universally private) property, we can transcribe this logic onto Marx’s general theory of labor, where, in the <em>Manuscripts</em>, he uses the term “species-being” once again, and even more generally, in order to define both the problem of capitalist labor (that it strips the laborer of his or her product) and the potential of the Communist world, where man is at last, in the vein of a harmony between men and women, acting in accordance with his nature as species-being.  Opposing the error of capitalism to the potential of communism he states, “But productive life is species-life. It is life-producing life. The whole character of a species, its species-character, resides in the nature of its life activity, and free conscious activity constitutes the species-character of man (Marx, p. 328).”</p>
<p>The mode of production in capitalism, due to the fetishization of the object in its exchange-value, and due to the fact that the laborer no longer works in freedom for his own species but for another individual man, is the cause of exploitation, which is not simply the alienation of the object or product, exploitation is the alienation of the species-being of man, where man is stricken from his universal capacity.</p>
<p>In other words, we would not be amiss, nor hasty, to utilize Marx’s general critique against capitalism as a way to shed light on the specific issue of sexuality, of gender, etc. As such, however, we hit the same wall in our conception of the ‘correct’ species-being orientation between men and women as we do when we try to conceive the correct species-being orientation towards production. Sure, we have the critique, the alienation, the fact that man seems to be driven further apart from himself and from others in the “anarchy” of capitalism but, given the purported totality of its function in our life, we also cannot describe the ‘correct way, the natural one’ without falling-prey to the fantasy of suggestion. This too seems to explain why Marx’s critique of vulgar communism just like his critique of capitalistic marriage does not produce any picture of the ‘correct way’; rather, it wanders off into the very type of ideological abstraction Marx is well known to despise (see Althusser’s essays in <em>For Marx</em>).</p>
<p>That which is outside of the conceptualized totality of our alienation thus becomes a dialectical ideal, a tautology, a flimsy gust of thought. This fact, and I do believe it is a fact, that Marx (well, anyone for that matter) can never successfully, or let’s say scientifically, expose to light the unalienated experience of human reality, gives us at least some traction to think about online dating.  Quite simply, if capital itself has caused an alienating construct that prevents the ‘correct’ relation between the opposite sexes or relations of the same sex variety (clearly Marx is not a Queer theorist, though I don’t doubt his ambiguity leaves open the potential to treat him as such), can we actually conclude that online dating is this evil, modern, capitalistic mode of affection and that stumbling drunk towards someone at a bar, meeting a mate at an Intellectual conference, or even crossing paths with him or her on some poetic crossing of the street  defies the logic of capitalistic alienation and allows for the “truth-procedure” of love? Can we, that is, draw lines in the sand within a greater structure of species-being perversion? Can we say that an inherent quality of modern life soils our interactions but not in such a way where authentic experience is prohibited? And then, too, we start to wonder whether or not this wholesome species-being, this communist, has led us off track, perhaps instead we should state that alienation is not simply the workings of capital, but the essence of man. Still, let us look closer at what Badiou has to say, about what is gained in the chance-encounter and what is lost in online dating.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>As stated, Badiou believes that online dating eliminates the risk central to the truth-procedure that is love, a gainsay he defends by quoting the slogans of the French dating service Meetic: “Love without suffering”, “Love without chance” and the even more ridiculous “Love without love (Badiou, p. 31)”. Honestly, these slogans are all rather surprising to me here in New York as a general user of OkCupid, a site whose main slogan demands “join the best dating site on earth”, and whose mascot Cupid is nothing more than the symbol of chance. Perhaps I am reading the name incorrectly, but it would seem that an Okcupid user is saying “Ok, Cupid, let’s take a chance”. Now, I am not trying to argue that Badiou simply made deductions from a unique example; no, I am saying instead that given the various possibilities of advertisement, I do believe that Badiou does not “go to the phenomenon itself” by judging online dating through the lens of a rather “odd” campaign.  First off, and I can’t believe I even have to say this!, nobody would ever dare to directly equate the desire for a product with its advertisement. What does Badiou think, that Meetic users say,  “Why, yes, I don’t want any chance, I want to find the perfectly suitable woman/man, I don’t want any suffering, so Meetic seems the perfect site for me.” This is a terrible misreading of the seduction of online dating.  One only needs to read the first lines of every other profile to discover why we use this <em>dispositif </em>(apparatus): 1) looking for a new scene: “I am tired of the bar scene”, “All my work colleagues are gay”, “My friend circle is not cutting it for me” etc. and 2) contagion: “Everyone is doing this, so I thought I should give it a try”. Not to mention probably the most common reason, which is rarely conceded, “I am shy, I am hoping my chances are better in this forum”/  Perhaps if we look at couples who are trying to play out some fantasy, or men and women trying to fulfill their less vanilla inclinations, we observe the desire to ‘curate’ a specific experience. Even this final example, which may seem to align itself more closely with Badiou’s critique, certainly has the potential of a great number of risks, the least of which is the contraction of STD’s. This unique usage of online dating aside, I think the most common experience of online dating is one where all the usual ‘butterflies’ and ‘insecurities’ are transmitted through this apparatus. Badiou himself seems to give us exactly the logical refutation we are looking for when he states: “Nothing enables one to prearrange the encounter – not even Meetic, and all those long, preparatory chats!: in the end, the moment you see each other in the flesh, you see each other, and that’s that, and it’s out of control!  (Badiou, p. 31)”. Moreover, the flesh is extended into these “preparatory chats” which, yes, sadly, are capable of transmitting the <em>frisson</em> Badiou can only imagine occurring in the flesh.</p>
<p>Much of this seems quite self-evident and rather fruitless as such, do we really need to demonstrate the artificial <em>techne</em> through which we approach reality? Do we really believe that the digital is less authentic then the chemical? Anyone who even hesitates before these questions must have a hard time with Hegel. In fact, Badiou’s somewhat curmudgeonly dismissal of online dating vitiates any rigorous assessment of the manner in which capitalistic production encroaches on our life. To escape the psychic influence of technology is it really as easy as “Let’s just meet in the library stacks like we used to”? It is the danger of the reactionary, the danger of a father telling you how he used to do things—and how well it worked out for him, that I find must appalling about Badiou’s now famous critique of online dating.</p>
<p>Badiou neglects the far more disturbing investigations concerning how our new technology in fact does transform our relations to each other, to the point where the noble reader of Badiou who opts to close his or her online account and pursue love the old-fashioned way finds that the world in which online dating can exist renders this puritanical endeavor entirely impotent in the totalizing structure of fiber-optic capital. This is a very clear example of where Badiou leaves what we can call, in concert with Althusser, the science of historical materialism behind, opting instead to cull from Marx the much less dependable ‘vision of the future’.  As Bruno Bosteels explains in his introduction to Badious’s <em>Theory of the Subject</em>: “… Badiou repeatedly rejects any notion of a &#8216;science of history&#8217; that would be embodied in Marx&#8217;s own study and critique of the political economy of advanced capitalism, in favour of a militant definition of the reference to texts by Marx, Lenin, and Mao in concrete political experiments (Bosteels in Badiou, p. xix).” Bosteels describes this inclination as a partiality towards the logic of the <em>Communist Manifesto</em>, which we can align with the period of the <em>Manuscripts</em> discussed above, over that found in <em>Das Capita</em>l.</p>
<p>Suffering from the same fever for revolution (dangling modifier), for Badiou, the question of the relationship between man and woman is not a question of a general habit induced by the artifacts of modernity but a question of love itself, an authentic event, a “truth-procedure”. In other words, Badiou is only interested in how we break out of the mold, which would explain why he can respond to the technologies disseminating love without any dialectical finesse.  It is thus that I view Badiou’s dismissal of online dating as symptomatic of a concept of love that continues to favor “militancy” and “revolution” over a “critique of the political economy of advanced capitalism,” a symptom which also reveals its error in the vacuous descriptions that we are compelled to make when describing the ‘correct way’ to either love or live.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> ***</p>
<p>First, then, we must describe Badiou’s theory of love, hoping to discover how it relates to the militant politics of communist revolution (despite his own denial that there is anything political about love) and how this concept necessitates the chance-encounter online dating somehow forecloses entirely. Let me just say for all those who have not glanced through <em>Being and Event</em> recently that Badiou designates 4 loci of truth-procedures, love is one of them, and the other three are politics, science, and art. Each of these loci are capable of producing events: with science it is very much an epistemological shift in the sense of Kuhn or Foucault, with politics it is essentially the event of communism, with art it is the introduction of a new mode of perception, of thought, of experience, and with love it is, in a mathematical sense, when 1 and 1 becomes 2, when identity becomes difference.  Here in this long quotation we can listen to Badiou explain why ‘true love’ is a truth procedure unique from dissimulating procedures of love such as that of the website Meetic:</p>
<p>“First, there is the romantic interpretation that focuses on the ecstasy of the encounter. Secondly, what we referred to briefly when discussing the Meetic dating agency, the interpretation based on a commercial or legalistic perspective, which argues that love must in the end be a contract. A contract between two free individuals who would presumably declare that they love each other, though they never forget the necessary equality of the relationship, the system of mutual benefits, etc. Finally, there is the sceptical interpretation that turns love into an illusion. My own philosophical view is attempting to say that love cannot be reduced to any of these approximations and is a quest for truth. What kind of truth? you will ask. I mean truth in relation to something quite precise: what kind of world does one see when one experiences it from the point of view of two and not one? What is the world like when it is experienced, developed and lived from the point of view of difference and not identity?  (Badiou, pp. 21-22)”.</p>
<p>Though his first example of dissimulating love places the chance encounter outside of ‘correct’ love, he returns to this point later, clarifying that the first encounter, though not the consummation of love, is indeed a necessary element for “The Arena of Love”. “I think many people still cling to a romantic conception of love that in a way absorbs love in the encounter. Love is simultaneously ignited, consummated and consumed in the meeting, in a magical moment outside the world as it really is. Something happens that is in the nature of a miracle, an existential intensity, an encounter leading to meltdown (Badiou, p. 30).”</p>
<p>From this we glean that ‘something’ of the chance encounter is necessary, and so we can properly conceive of the danger online dating might pose: it eliminates the necessary chance. For Badiou, the “work or labor” of love, which is the truth procedure of love, has a relation or relates to the “moment of destiny” while constitutively moving beyond it.  Thus he explains that those who remain bound by the chance-encounter remain as “One” and have yet to develop, sublate or proceed to the “Two”. We should note here that Badiou claims that many of us today still possess this Romantic idea of love, that we “absorb love in the encounter”—an idea which certainly contradicts the many of us who use online dating to avoid it entirely. I personally believe this is part of the inconsistency of his logic here: nowhere does Badiou systematically oppose the yearning for the encounter with the destruction of it; instead, he simply uses both conceits to delineate what a truth-procedure is not.</p>
<p>What then is this truth procedure, this work of love, where: “an apparently insignificant act, but one that is a really radical event in life at a micro-level, bears universal meaning in the way it persists and endures (Badiou, p. 41).”  Do we find any description in Badiou’s logic more concrete than what we found in Marx’s <em>Manuscripts</em>? Not exactly.</p>
<p>Later in <em>In Praise of Love</em>, Badiou tells us that the disagreements that occur in love “are the sharpest experience of the conflict between identity and difference (Badiou, p. 62 )”. So that love does not “melt” into the fate of the encounter but constantly oscillates within the “dialogue” of the “Two” as they attempt to bring forth this universal act, or “accomodate eternity in life”.  Though Badiou tells us not to confuse love with politics (it seems easier not to confuse it with science or art) since it is not concerned with upsetting the codes of the state but with a private interaction between the “Two”, it is also in this idea of eternity and universality that we cannot miss the metaphysical formula that equates the event of all truth-procedures. “But love, the essence of which is fidelity in the meaning I give to this word, demonstrates how eternity can exist within the time span of life itself. Happiness, in a word! Yes, happiness in love is the proof that time can accommodate eternity. And you can also find proof in the political enthusiasm you feel when participating in a revolutionary act, in the pleasure given by works of art and the almost supernatural joy you experience when you at last grasp in depth the meaning of a scientific theory (Badiou, pp. 48-49).”</p>
<p>This amazing passage, which views eternity as somehow “negotiable”, and which places happiness within our grasp after more then 2000 years of rejecting such a naïve idea, not only brings all the truth-procedures together, it explains that, along with happiness, enthusiasm, pleasure and joy are the affective records or experiences of the event itself.  He also designates “fidelity” the action or subjective orientation towards the event, so that he can later claim that all this pleasure and happiness consummates in “fidelity”, where any “truth procedure” but specifically love: “transition[s] from [a] random encounter to a construction that is resilient, as if it had been necessary (Badiou, p. 44).”</p>
<p>It is exactly here that I think we can appraise a general logic that permeates each event, one that prevails in Badiou’s effervescent confidence in communism, claiming throughout his <em>oeuvre</em> that the Paris Commune, the Shanghai Commune, and May ’68 are political events (or fractions of the major one) to which we must remain faithful. I believe Badiou inadvertently exposes the connection between love and communism in response to a question asking him to distinguish them, thus producing a general theory of capital where both love and communism “escape” alienation.</p>
<p>So, when asked why love is not political, he responds, “When I talk of the Communist hypothesis, I simply want to suggest that future forms of the politics of emancipation must be inscribed in a resurrection, a re-affirmation, of the Communist idea, the idea of a world that isn’t given over to the avarice of private property, a world of free association and equality…In such a framework, it will be easier to re-invent love than if surrounded by capitalist frenzy. Because we can be sure that nothing disinterested can be at ease amid such frenzy (Badiou, p. 73).” So that though love is not identical to the political truth-procedure, the success of the truth-procedure of communism would fashion “new possibilities” for love, a greater potential in other words, a potential no longer hindered by the frenzy of capital.</p>
<p>Here we see how Meetic, the online dating site, is no longer a specific error in the system of capital, it is the epitomizing example, at least within his text. It demonstrates the entire problem with capitalistic identity: “The reactionary project is always the defence of “our values”, casting us in the mold of worldwide capitalism as the only possible identity. The impulse driving reaction is always a crude reference to identity in one form or another. Now, when the logic of identity wins the day, love is under threat. The way it is attracted to difference, its social dimension, and its wild, eventually violent side are under threat. They promote a “love” that is safe, in line with all their other security initiatives. (Badiou, p. 98).”</p>
<p>It is exactly in the fable of online dating that we can see the dimension of alienation up close, in real-time, in such a way that this frenzy of identity grows a callous over any notion of difference.  However, due to the very nature of this example, it can no longer pretend to be anything more than a foreground for the total structure Badiou prophetically rails against. In other words, when Badiou pits love against Meetic at the beginning of the text we find out later that this is a metonymy for a more generic struggle: that between love and capital. And if we also think about how both love and communism are similar, or have “a common resonance” in their ‘breaking eternity’, then we see that love like communism <em>defies</em> capital, which is also why Badiou later concedes “love is the minimal form of communism”.  So that, for Badiou, love is like a little communist revolution you get to have on the side, while you are still waiting for the real one.</p>
<p>If I originally hypothesized that Badiou leaves out the methodical “science” of Marx’s <em>Das Capital</em>, it is only when he uses it in its colloquial form (frenzied capital) that he reveals an analogy I would assume he would rather hide: that all truth-procedures hearken back to the “dream” aspect of Marx, where capital disappears and along with it property, exploitation and alienation. However, by placing love inside capital in the manner implied by a love that simply negotiates capital correctly (does not use online dating), we encounter, I think in a much more blatant manner, the disappointment Adorno felt towards Benjamin when he seemed to place the messianic within the structure of capital, thereby, according to Adorno’s logic, affirming the reactionary structure to some extent. I say Badiou is more blatant because of style, because of the bold face in which Badiou proclaims his own experience of the truth-procedure of love, of happiness, in comparison to the riddle-like messianism of Benjamin. In consequence, we see a glaring contradiction in Badiou’s logic: the event, fashioned around communism, both requires a total usurpation and is also capable of a localized one. By telling us that love is not political though still indeed an event, we deduce that communism is already among us in a sense, though this concept can only function if we maintain the possibility of the total event. In other words, either the localized event of love reduces the aspiration for communism or love is simply not an event, since it is not total.</p>
<p>Just as Marx in his <em>Manuscripts</em> presents a truly aporetic unqualified vision of a “correct” relationship between man and woman, the event of love suffers from the tautology of the beyond or the natural. It is by suffering as much that its resonance with communism proper obtains: events for Badiou are the possibility of moving beyond capital, where at last we could judge the relationship between men and women, between capitalist and laborer, satisfactorily, where, in fact, we must imagine the relation so transfigured that it does not even perpetuate these divisions, which are inherently capitalistic. So that the difference of the “Two” necessitates the same absolution as the disappearance of property itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> ***</p>
<p>Althusser has argued that we must not conflate Marx’s early <em>Manuscripts</em> with the scientific project of <em>Das Capital</em>. He writes, “Marxism should not be simply a political doctrine, a ‘method’ of analysis and action, but also, over and above the rest, the theoretical domain of a fundamental investigation (Althusser, p. 26).” Engels himself was so frustrated by the absence in <em>Das</em> <em>Capital: Volume II</em> of Marx’s youthful fantasies that he initially told Friedrich Adolph Sorge: “The second volume will provoke great disappointment because it is purely scientific and does not contain much material for agitation (Marx, p. 9)”.  But, for Althusser, the science, the critique we find in <em>Das Capital</em>, is Marx’s mature attempt to escape Hegelian Idealism, an Idealism encapsulated in the aporia of Badiou’s event. Though we may find something appealing in Badiou’s rejection of the critical capacity of Marx’s work, in his militant return to Marx’s ‘dreams of communism’, Badiou risks the very vulgarity of the communists Marx was keen to avoid when he eventually grounded his theory in the science of historical materialism. Badiou subsumes Marx’s science into the situation, the state, the one, and oppposes the event of the “truth-procedure” to what is no longer proven to be unjust but is simply presumably so (i.e. we all know capitalism is bad, let’s not even examine why). Badiou’s isolation of online dating corroborates this vulgarity. For he makes a bargain with capital, he tells us to use the “ less” alienating <em>techne</em>.</p>
<p>Badiou’s rejection of online dating thus requires a general lack of thought, the absence of a science, or a dialectic. It is the very “dream” of communism, of the beyond, that permits him this trespassing. Certainly, I have no intention of denying online dating’s implication; however, if we simply deny the way in which all products now before us are implicated in alienation; if we begin to balance ourselves in such a way where a proletariat (read dispossessed) potential need only occur with the right alienating object, we push the problem into the future while making claim that we are fighting back. As such, this whole essay, which I am still at a loss as to why it was written, begins now, where the labor of thought is not shirked by the pleasure of dreaming. I also would simply note that whenever anyone singles out online dating for propagating superficiality, for <em>creating</em> a culture of “love ‘em and leave ‘em”, for demeaning all of us to formulations and cunning photography, this is yet another case of historical amnesia. I truly believe that the only way to recuperate the event of communism, as the total event, would be to deny ourselves love until the time when there is no more property, on that day love will come easy to us, because we will be in tune with our <em>Gattungswesen</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Althusser, Louis. <em>For Marx</em>, 2010.<br />
Badiou, Alain. <em>In Praise of Love</em>, 2009.<br />
Badiou, Alain. <em>Theory of the Subject</em>, 2009.<br />
Marx, Karl. <em>Early Writings</em>, 1992.<br />
Marx, Karl. <em>Capital: Volume II</em>, 1978.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BioShock Aphorism Stills</title>
		<link>/j-r/bioshock-aphorism-stills/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 13:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=850</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[BioShock is a video game I started playing recently, I think it came out 10 years ago. It is apparently a critique of Ayn Rand&#8217;s Atlas Shrugged. Here is the opening of the game: &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-862" title="aesthetics_small" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/aesthetics_small1-500x375.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/aesthetics_small1-500x375.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/02/aesthetics_small1.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><span id="more-850"></span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-853" title="Adam-denies-us-any-excuse-for-not-being-beautiful-Bioshock-Wide-Wallpapers" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adam-denies-us-any-excuse-for-not-being-beautiful-Bioshock-Wide-Wallpapers-500x281.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adam-denies-us-any-excuse-for-not-being-beautiful-Bioshock-Wide-Wallpapers-500x281.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adam-denies-us-any-excuse-for-not-being-beautiful-Bioshock-Wide-Wallpapers-1024x576.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>BioShock is a video game I started playing recently, I think it came out 10 years ago. It is apparently<br />
a critique of Ayn Rand&#8217;s <em>Atlas Shrugged</em>. Here is the opening of the game:</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CVR2gZANx10" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>La politique de l&#8217;autruche</title>
		<link>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/</link>
		<comments>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 18:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[le manque]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adorno]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lacan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wampole]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the contest to mystify what is at least for this worker bee the self-evident object-cause of mass killing—namely, the happiness of a warm gun—Professor Wampole’s latest foray into social criticism at The Stone really takes the cupcake. At first I thought that conventional wisdom—call it “Facebook psychology”—was generally divided into two (maybe three) camps. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/ostrich/" rel="attachment wp-att-669"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-669" title="ostrich" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/ostrich.jpg" alt="" width="412" height="423" /></a></p>
<p>In the contest to mystify what is at least for this worker bee the self-evident object-cause of mass killing—namely, the happiness of a warm gun—Professor Wampole’s <a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/12/17/guns-and-the-decline-of-the-young-man/" target="_blank">latest foray</a> into social criticism at The Stone really takes the cupcake.</p>
<p><span id="more-663"></span>At first I thought that conventional wisdom—call it “Facebook psychology”—was generally divided into two (maybe three) camps. On the one hand, there are those who blame the mass media, either the reporters for sensationalionizing the event (thereby turning it into a non-event) or the culture industry for its representation of violence. On the other, there are those who blame inadequate access to something vague like &#8220;mental health care.” A third possibility is inadequate &#8220;gun control,&#8221; which, to my mind, is just as vague, a political cipher that falls more or less into the same camp as &#8220;mental health care” (but more on this below). (Yes, I’m leaving out of this picture what passes for conventional wisdom on the right—the teachers didn’t have the guns to defend themselves—but I think the best response to that is silence of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tractatus_Logico-Philosophicus#Proposition_7" target="_blank">Proposition 7 variety</a>.)</p>
<p>Now comes Wampole’s ingenious contribution:</p>
<p>&#8220;Limiting access to weapons is certainly a pragmatic albeit incomplete solution to the United States’ propensity for murder. However, were the guns to vanish instantaneously, the specter that haunts our young men would still hover in silence, darkly.”</p>
<p>What’s insidious about this assertion is that it is cloaked in all the demystifying garb of your standard ideological argument. Taking a cue perhaps from Hanna Rosin’s recent <em>The End of Men: And the Rise of Women</em>, which one Time’s book reviewer describes as <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/16/books/review/the-end-of-men-by-hanna-rosin.html" target="_blank">“carelessly apolitical,”</a> Wampole diagnoses a structural, or as she calls it “subconscious,” problem—the “decline of the white male.” Since most of the mass killers happen to be middle class white males, it would then make good sense to assume that it must be a symptom of their fall from social power. As anecdotal evidence, Wampole introduces us to her poor white family in Texas, a “region” where all the women, despite being mostly single moms, are doing “O.K. in the end,” but where all the men abuse “drugs or alcohol” and spend time in prison. “If this pattern is not familiar to you personally,” she assures us, “I am certain it is the lived experience of someone you know.”</p>
<p>Thus Wampole at her most succinct: “The angry white man has usurped the angry black man.”</p>
<p>Now the problem here is not merely that the core of Wampole’s argument is militantly counterfactual. According to the <a href="http://bjs.ojp.usdoj.gov/content/homicide/race.cfm">latest DOJ statistics</a>, while the current homicide rate among non-whites is a little more than seven times that of whites, the <a href="http://www.theatlanticcities.com/jobs-and-economy/2012/12/most-recent-decline-us-violent-crime-different-last-one/4175/">overall trend</a> is that violent crime in general has fallen dramatically over the past two decades. The real problem is that Wampole’s understanding of the event actually partakes in the same logic as those previous types of left conventional wisdom. Let us recall for a second the structure of Poe’s “The Purloined Letter,” in which the Prefect of police assumes that the Minister must have hidden the letter someplace in his apartment—everyone understands that the letter, much like a firearm, is useless if the Minister doesn’t have it ready-to-hand and would leave the Minister impotent if it ever were used. After searching the Minister’s apartment from top to bottom, the Prefect has come up with nothing and thus seeks out Dupin, Poe’s great solver of enigmas, who understands that the secret of the purloined letter is that the Minister, following the path of the signifier set by the Queen, has hidden it in plain sight. As Lacan puts it in his seminar on the story:</p>
<p>“In order to grasp in its unity the intersubjective complex thus described, we would willingly seek a model in the technique legendarily attributed to the ostrich attempting to shield itself from danger; for that technique might ultimately be qualified as political, divided as it here is among three partners: the second believing itself invisible because the first has its head stuck in the ground, and all the while letting the third calmly pluck its rear” (<em>The Purloined Poe, </em>p. 32).</p>
<p>At first, we might be tempted to say that Wampole is a lot like the Prefect with his head in the sand, missing the simple fact that, as I perhaps too casually stated earlier, the purloined letter structures the subject in the same way that possessing a gun does. (Along these lines, Dan Baum’s <a href="http://harpers.org/archive/2010/08/happiness-is-a-worn-gun/">“Happiness is a Worn Gun”</a> remains one of the most insightful essays about guns ever written.) At the same time, Wampole understands this, but in paying attention only to the congenital political blindness around her—fetishizing, as it were, the ordinary, the perennial poor white’s complaint of being, in Dylan’s words, “only a pawn in their game”—she misses the real force of her argument, which is precisely that a gun is a concrete representation of the phallus, perhaps its earthly representative par excellence.</p>
<p>This is why metaphysicalvillain’s <a href="/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/">Adorno quote</a> comes off sounding so psychopathic. A most doctrinaire Marxist in the end, Adorno fails to see the link between surplus-value and surplus-enjoyment, and thus further confuses the machine’s production with its consumption. As he goes on to say in that same section of <em>Minima Moralia</em>: “not least to blame for the withering of experience is the fact that things, under the law of pure functionality, assume a form that limits contact with them to mere operation, and tolerates no surplus” (40). No doubt Adorno pierces through the veil of experience here, but it is the very impotence of ideological critique—of catching a glimpse of the Real, i.e., “the vermin of the street,” while being unable to do a damn thing for them—that leads Adorno to imagine the bottomless irony of vehicular homicide. There is a purity to this kind of negation that would seem to negate even the death drive itself, a place where even those of us who sense the all-too-human limitations of <em>jouissance</em>—what Lauren Berlant has called its “ambivalent whiplash”—realize that in the end it’s all we’ve got in this life (and as <em>Fifty Shades of Grey </em>teaches us, we may as well enjoy its sting). And yes, I am suggesting that mass killers do probably glimpse the Adornian truth of things as at least one condition for pulling the trigger (and this is why Wampole&#8217;s call for empathy is best used as an engine for new legislation, rather than a psychologistic imperative).</p>
<p>Much closer to the mark on this point is Nabokov’s high-and-dry Humbert Humbert, contemplating murdering his <em>Doppelgänger</em>, Claire Quilty—a name that practically invites un<em>veiling</em>—the <em>real</em> and for that reason only possible corrupter of Lolita. Observe him in his final encounter with the now-grown-up nymphet, just prior to the novel’s denouement: “I could very well do with a little more rest in this subdued, frightened-to-death rocking chair, before I drove to whatever the beast’s lair was—and pulled the pistol’s foreskin back, and then enjoyed the orgasm of the crushed trigger: I was always a good little follower of the Viennese medicine man” (274).</p>
<p>Nowhere is Nabokov more Freudian than in his moments of disavowal, a technique that only serves to transport his imagery to the laws, if not the very limit, of signification. For if Lolita is anything beyond the pale quiver of Humbert Humbert’s fantasy, she <em>is</em> the culture industry. Like Adorno—who could never rid himself of his bizarre latent class subjectivism—Humbert Humbert’s answer to the problem of mass culture is to retreat into the nymphet kingdom that is High Art. And this, I want to claim, is part of a much broader post-1945 trend to transform complicity into something like resigned connoisseurship. But what looks like a willful projection of bland android-like critical distance in Adorno is for Nabokov’s alter ego something much more affecting: actual enjoyment. The oscillation between enjoying and failing to enjoy—given voice in his only real encounter with Lolita, the scene of her “oh, <em>no</em>” with a “sigh to heaven” (285)—is where the true pathos of Humbert Humbert resides.</p>
<p>And I think this leads us back to Professor Wampole, the link between her current essay and her previous one on the hipster. What is unbearable for Wampole (and most of her academic ilk) to imagine is that anyone could actually derive a dialectic of enjoyment from popular culture. More specifically, we could say that she is correct that gun violence, especially the genre of mass killing, is a product of males “in decline”—not just white males, but all males. And not just historically, but transhitorically. For being “in decline”—the illusive reverse of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A41CITk85jk">Bach’s endlessly rising canon</a>—is what it means to be male, from Napolean to Woody Allen. As a consequence, male desire ceaselessly turns around the maypole of object a, as we see in just about every scene of “Love and Death”:</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i5Q8AqYLKro" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>The obverse of Wampole&#8217;s argument would need to account for what has emerged as <em>the </em>most horrific genre of female violence, the Casey Anthony who murders her children (often by drowning). But I’ll leave that for an analyst more equal to the task of sexuation.</p>
<p>In the meantime, I think I speak for the Hive in offering a political prescription: in lieu of castration, confiscate the fucking guns. All 270,000,000 of them. <a href="/anti-orpheus/gum-violence/">Pace anti-orpheus</a>, I do think that living under liberalism <em>entitles</em> us to a fuller experience of the every day, a radical ordinary that is capable of rupturing ideology rather than constantly being undermined by it. This lies in the discovery that sometimes all you have to do is see what is staring you plain in the face.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reflections on Sandy Hook: Fantasy and Cinematic Violence</title>
		<link>/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/</link>
		<comments>/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 22:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narrative]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As the descriptions of the events at Sandy Hook become more and more detailed in the media, I find myself &#8212; like probably much of America &#8212; imagining this horrific scene. J.R. mentioned in the comments to metaphysicalvillain&#8217;s post that these scenes are &#8220;infused with the fantasy of some absolute, cinematic gesture.&#8221; This seems quite true, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the descriptions of the events at Sandy Hook become more and more detailed in the media, I find myself &#8212; like probably much of America &#8212; imagining this horrific scene. J.R. mentioned in the comments to metaphysicalvillain&#8217;s <a href="/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/">post</a> that these scenes are &#8220;infused with the fantasy of some absolute, cinematic gesture.&#8221; This seems quite true, but I&#8217;m not sure how we should understand this association. What makes a scene or an act cinematic? <span id="more-648"></span> Are we to think that such extremely violent and tragic acts are, to some extent, in debt to cinema for their origins? Maybe, but I&#8217;m not sure what would be gained by this investigation. What if, instead, the association exists because cinema gives us a <em>language</em> to imagine such scenes? Without the language of cinema, wouldn&#8217;t our capacity to &#8220;play out&#8221; scenes such as these be quite different?</p>
<p>And yet a scene like this is something cinema has never really given us. We&#8217;ve seen plenty of people slaughtered senselessly on film, but never children so young. It&#8217;s usually a moment only implied, where the camera &#8220;looks away.&#8221; As I sat on my couch this morning listening to NPR and drinking coffee, I thought about all of these small bodies piling up, their little legs so inadequate to the task of running away, the looks of terror and disbelief, the smoke and the deafening cracks of a gun fired indoors &#8212; all pieced together in a tight montage, something with a David Fincher-feel, perhaps.</p>
<p>As odd as this might sound, what resulted from this little flight of fancy is even more odd. I remembered something that, frankly, I hadn&#8217;t remembered for a long time: a violent daydream I had had in the 2nd grade. I remember sitting in class and getting enormous pleasure from imaging this scene. Put your analysis caps on (and let me reiterate that this is <em>not</em> a dream, but a daydream).</p>
<p>In the middle of the school day, my teacher&#8217;s husband and their two small children suddenly burst through the doors of my school. They are completely naked and headed straight for our classroom. Her husband is muscular and powerful and sprints down the hallway. The two children follow behind, running and laughing. As he reaches the classroom door, my teacher&#8217;s face transforms from her usual cheerful smile to something insidious. They look at  each other to confirm that now is the moment, as though this had been long planned. My teacher strips to the buff and then presses a button under her desk that causes a metal wall to fall from the ceiling, dividing the classroom in two. I hear the students on the other side of the wall scream as machine guns materialize &#8212; from where I do not know &#8212; and shoot. There is a door on the wall that opens to the other side, and my teacher, her husband, and their two children open it and enter, leaving the door open. They look absolutely serene and righteous, excited and pleased with what is happening. Since the door remains open, the other students and I can see that the other side is filled with white pillows. Just out of view, however, my teacher and her blonde, muscular husband are having sex, while her children watch, giggling and screaming with delight. When several of the students try to enter through the open door to see, they are immediately gunned down by a large remote controlled Gatling gun. And that&#8217;s where it ends, or continues indefinitely. It ends with me watching as student after student tries to enter the door to watch my teacher and her husband have sex, only be be shredded by dozens of high powered rounds.</p>
<p>There is a lot that can be said about this scene, psychoanalytically, and you&#8217;re all welcome to go ahead and offer an interpretation (please do!). But I&#8217;ll just say that the way this scene played out in my daydream was cinematic in a way that the description doesn&#8217;t quite do justice to. There was parallel editing right at the beginning, between the classroom and the husband bursting through the doors and running down the hall. There was shot counter-shot between my teacher and her husband as he entered the classroom door. The shooting scenes happened in slow motion. There was even dramatic music, though I don&#8217;t recall now what it was.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t have &#8220;violent&#8221; fantasies like this &#8212; or whatever this was &#8212; anymore. My libido, eventually, stopped expressing desire with this particular mixture. But it makes me wonder about the cinematic form this fantasy took. I wonder if violent fantasies are not particularly affected by cinematic language, perhaps more so than other kinds of fantasies. Even though my sexual fantasies often have just as much narrative as this daydream, they aren&#8217;t really cinematic. Is this because cinema offers a kind of disembodied perspective that, while not meshing well with my vanilla, sexual fantasies, seems to find an affinity when I confront violent fantasies?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/mouseonthemoon/reflections-on-sandy-hook-fantasy-and-cinematic-violence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Winter in Ithaca: an essay on The Flaming Lips</title>
		<link>/j-r/winter-in-ithaca-an-essay-on-the-flaming-lips/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 04:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flaming Lips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamlet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hegel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ithaca]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=346</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was living in Ithaca, NY when I was first introduced to The Flaming Lips. Ithaca has the privilege of steep hills, large, healthy trees, and imposing Gorges that gush with waterfalls. At the time nothing was more exciting than walking through this landscape with headphones on. Whatever is playing in your ears has a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-390" title="guitar_jesus" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/guitar_jesus3.jpeg" alt="" width="193" height="240" /></p>
<p>I was living in Ithaca, NY when I was first introduced to The Flaming Lips. Ithaca has the privilege of steep hills, large, healthy trees, and imposing Gorges that gush with waterfalls. At the time nothing was more exciting than walking through this landscape with headphones on. Whatever is playing in your ears has a way of seeping into everything surrounding you—my heartbeat would grow heavy, and my legs would feel lighter than ever. <span id="more-346"></span>In the dead cold of winter, The Flaming Lips&#8217; triumphant songs resonated especially well. They are one of those bands who despite having gone through major transformations over their career always express—whether in their mid 80s grungy punk or their late 90s psycho-pop—the same enthusiasm, the same rebellion, the same philosophic longing.</p>
<p>At the time, to explain this phenomenon to myself, I concluded that Wayne Coyne, the songwriter and inspirator of The Flaming Lips, had a mystical connection with the world—and since I was young, and desirous of intensity and power, I wanted to become Wayne Coyne. I wanted to exist in his body, and every song gave me the opportunity to imagine what it would be like to do so. Soon this obsession started to terrify me, I would wake up, look out at the snow-filled window, and instead of perceiving what I perceived, I would add to the frame whatever it was I imagined Wayne Coyne would see when he looked out the window; and since many songs were about ‘spacemen and their guns’, ‘elephants and kangaroos’, ‘hypnotists’, ‘aliens’, and more, the possibilities seemed so limitless that I would always grow despondent after a few minutes, certain that the trapeze artist I had conjured was nowhere near as detailed as the full circus Wayne would surely have been capable of imagining.</p>
<p>I always had a notion that I was sick for having this obsession, that all my fears were only within me. Since I was corrupted by psychedelics, the odd guitar timbers and multi-layered melodies stole my mind off to an expansive oblivion. So I decided that this feeling of indeterminacy that came over me would only disappear if I became the creator of it. Wayne Coyne represented the limit of both a fear and a euphoria inside of me. He was the one who existed outside the infinite. What made this obsession even more difficult to shake was that while I was raising Wayne up to this holy distinction, Wayne himself, in his youth, constantly sang about Jesus, and I just assumed that he was referring to himself, especially when he sang, “Jesus was a rock star who destroyed all he’d seen.&#8221; It took me over three years to shed myself of Wayne Coyne, and when I finally realized I was out from under his spell, I was never entirely certain why he had left—it may have been that I replaced him with another vision of omnipotence, a friend, a lover… But I continued to listen to his music, because it always reminded me of a formative stage of my existence. Not to mention that those aspects of the music that had always appealed to me&#8211;the sense of humor, the honesty, and the absurdity&#8211;continued to suit my mood. So, it was not without a certain irony that, deep within Hegel’s <em>Phenomenology of Spirit</em>, I turned back on some old tunes by the Flaming Lips only to discover anew what the songs meant to me back then, why they swallowed me whole, and why, still to this day, they represent that late adolescent struggle immortalized by Hamlet’s schizophrenic consciousness.</p>
<p>I have decided to lead you through my &#8216;juvenile hangups&#8217; by discussing the first five songs on the album <em>In a Priest Driven Ambulance Car</em>, considered by many to be their first masterpiece. I should also explain the rarified Hegelian logic that I subscribe to these songs. One of the central themes in Hegel&#8217;s <em>Phenomenology</em> is the oscillation between the object and the subject. In certain instances of the &#8220;Spirit&#8221;, Hegel describes how our self-consciousness overemphasizes its subjectivity, that there is too much ego, and in other instances he observes the opposite, that the object is given too much value. I read the songs to follow along these lines, where each one overemphasizes or downplays the ego of the singer, Wayne&#8217;s ego. Like Hegel, who ends the <em>Phenomenology</em> with the perfect balance between ego (subject) and object, I will argue that the 5th and final song in this essay achieves such a balance.</p>
<p>The first song on this album is entitled <em>Shine on Sweet Jesus on Me</em> (Jesus Song #5):</p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-01-Shine-On-Sweet-Jesus-Jesus-Song-No.-5.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>Waitin&#8217; for my ride</em><br />
<em>Jesus is floatin&#8217; outside</em><br />
<em>(shine on, sweet jesus, on me)</em><br />
<em>Watchin&#8217; the water rise</em><br />
<em>I&#8217;m gettin&#8217; lost in the tide</em><br />
<em>(cry all your teardrops on me)</em><br />
<em>While I&#8217;m still myself,</em><br />
<em>Your blankets covered me</em><br />
<em>Covered me while I was still asleep</em></p>
<p><em>Watchin&#8217; the planets shine</em><br />
<em>Reflecting yourself in the sky</em><br />
<em>(shine on, sweet jesus, on me)</em><br />
<em>Scraping these smiles of mine</em><br />
<em>Impossible one at a time</em><br />
<em>(cry all your teardrops on me)</em><br />
<em>While I&#8217;m still myself,</em><br />
<em>Your blankets covered me</em><br />
<em>Covered me while I was still asleep</em></p>
<p><em>Jesus is at my side,</em><br />
<em>Wondering what he will find</em><br />
<em>(shine on, sweet jesus, on me)</em><br />
<em>Watchin&#8217; the water rise</em><br />
<em>I&#8217;m gettin&#8217; lost in the tide</em><br />
<em>(cry all your teardrops on me)</em><br />
<em>While I&#8217;m still myself</em><br />
<em>Your blankets covered me</em><br />
<em>Covered me while I was still asleep</em></p>
<p>As a secular Jew, songs about Jesus remained a mystery that I assumed had some cultural significance, one which I was lucky enough to be exempt from. So what struck me back then was the way Jesus symbolized Wayne’s desire to toy with truth. The sight of Jesus &#8220;floatin’ outside’&#8221; somehow surpassed the surreal images on earlier albums, such as: “Brains falling out of my head.” To sing about Jesus instead of &#8220;monkeys humping holes in brains&#8221; transcends the vain and circular fight of the artist who thinks that extreme picture-thoughts provide the greatest impression. In singing about Jesus, Wayne externalizes his conception of himself and refuses to project his particular genius. So, to me, this song represents the refusal to make a great work of art. Jesus is floating outside not because a single consciousness has pictured him, Jesus is floating outside because the artist has sacrificed his personality and decided to bear witness to what is there when he is not there at all. This is why Wayne sings, “While I’m still myself/Your blankets covered me/Covered me while I was still asleep.” Often obsessed with describing the rancor of dreams, Wayne removes his ego completely from the process, eliminates all his dreams, and observes himself as a mere object in the care of a transcendent figure. Still, this figure is not exactly anonymous, it is someone who is much like Wayne himself (look at the picture of young Wayne), someone long-haired, whose exuberance, well, this is how I saw him, could forgive all sin.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-391" title="wayne" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/wayne.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="212" /></p>
<p>Wayne’s ego returns in this unavoidable identification, but does so in the form of a living God who is immune to the vanity of dreams. You only need to listen to these songs, recognize the playful marching beats and the wistful nature of Wayne’s crooning, to convince yourself that these songs are indeed a joyful act of self-annihilation. This is why Wayne does not maintain a common theism throughout the whole album or even the song itself. He possesses as many ways to  abandon himself as the boundless picture-thoughts he now sacrifices.</p>
<p>The first  line of the second verse &#8220;Watchin’ the planets shine/reflecting yourself in the sky&#8221;—is not inspired by any Christian notion that I know of, and this complicates Wayne’s gesture, since he is not grasping for a stagnant mediator of objectivity but for the process of objectification itself—so that the vastness of the Universe, either in its scientific module or in the module of ancient heroes and gods, now replaces Jesus, but recreates for Wayne the objectivity necessary to reflect not into his ego—but out of it.</p>
<p align="center">***</p>
<p>When I was obsessed with the Flaming Lips, I was also obsessed with hallucinogens, most specifically mushrooms, but I did a good amount of acid as well. I had a friend who was attending Cornell for free because of his peculiar genius and instead of working to assure safe passage through the world, he became the biggest drug dealer on campus. Psychedelics tend to promote communities in which everyone seeks to project themselves as nearest to the heart of a great mystery. “Knowing” in its most naked element was what we all desired, and my friend Darian seemed to be at the top of this Caste system, handing out pieces of advice for cash. He also managed to ace his chemical engineering classes while staying up all night preaching the messages whispered to him in the nearby forest. Being with him, doing acid, and listening to The Flaming Lips—all these things interwove to spur on my personal reinvention—and I took all these things much more seriously than my literature classes.</p>
<p>In Hegelian terms, my classes were all limited to reflective thinking, to boundaries, to limits, to qualifications of what knowledge was supposed to mean, whereas, at night, by the waterfalls, in the infinite melodies, speculative thinking tore away all stationary manifestations of existence. I was religiously attune to these methods.</p>
<p><em>Unconsciously Screamin&#8217;</em>:</p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-02-Unconsciously-Screamin1.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>Seeing the unseeable,</em><br />
<em>Filling down the void</em><br />
<em>We&#8217;re not what we used to be</em><br />
<em>We&#8217;re not really boys</em></p>
<p><em>Screaming till our lungs are full</em><br />
<em>Kicking down the teeth</em><br />
<em>We&#8217;re not what we used to be</em><br />
<em>We&#8217;re just paranoid</em></p>
<p><em>Unconsciously screaming</em><br />
<em>And whispering at everything she brings</em></p>
<p>This song is violent. It begins with loud hits on the snare, strong distorted guitars, and Wayne’s shouting voice. The band is laboring in search for knowledge—they do so by negating all objects of perception. Sight is unseeable, the human is no longer human, no longer a child, and teeth are breaking. And what else is all this but paranoia—but then all this breaking down is negated too. So that the void, instead of causing vertigo, fills up with this non-sight, the void solidifies. Unconsciousness destroys the volition of the punk rocker raging against the machine, it turns his cries into a mere whisper. This unconscious whisper is then identified with She, with nature, with Mother Mary, who “brings” despite the repetition of unsight and the damaged ego of drug-addled youth. What in the first song appeared in a vision arrives in this song as the process of lost vision. The identifying object is not the Lord but the vicious circle—a movement one must continually exert.</p>
<p>“We do it wrong, being so majestical, To offer it the show of violence, For it is as the air, invulnerable, And our vain blows malicious mockery.”</p>
<p>My favorite line in this song was always &#8220;We’re not what we used to be/We’re not really boys.&#8221; Fearfulness and liberty alike inform this transformed idea of identity. It is both a reflection on maturation into adulthood and on how the human grows out of its categories. There is not a period of one’s life that is more prescient of what will become the constant dissatisfaction of self-identity than the one that forces the boy to reinterpret himself outside of his parental instructions. This is the limbo where one MUST, if one is to approach liberation, ask the timeless question in Hamlet. It is also the limbo where one must accept that Being will never be forthcoming with an answer. The Flaming Lips transgress this limbo—they proudly assert the negation of all categories—they are growing out of their youth, and yet maintaining it with the rebellion of infinite resignation, letting IT take them wherever their violence and non-sight brings them. And this leads them back into themselves.</p>
<p><em>Rainin&#8217; Babies:</em></p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-03-Rainin-Babies.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>What I&#8217;m thinkin&#8217; is so delicate</em><br />
<em>If I breathe, you know, I&#8217;m gonna lose it</em><br />
<em>It&#8217;s just a drop in the biggest ocean I know I&#8217;ve ever seen</em><br />
<em>And in a moment it&#8217;s big enough to drown the whole world</em></p>
<p><em>This is my present to the world</em><br />
<em>And I want you to take it</em><br />
<em>This is my present to the world</em><br />
<em>Take it from me, please please take it from me</em></p>
<p><em>All I know is I don&#8217;t know it</em><br />
<em>It&#8217;s rainin&#8217; babies from the sky down on me</em><br />
<em>Tiny drops on my windshield</em><br />
<em>And in a second it&#8217;s rainin&#8217; rainin&#8217; all over the whole world</em></p>
<p><em></em>I used to think that Wayne was such an arrogant, fucking asshole for singing this song, for regarding himself in these messianic terms. Now I see how reaching unflinchingly for the messianic immediately overcomes the very psychic limitation that made me so angry that these words were spoken by someone else, who was not me. In other words, these lyrics forced me to face my own desire and failure to be messianic. In the ever-changing confrontation with what is alien in the self we find a way to refuse our own vanity at the exact moment when this vanity expresses itself.</p>
<p>If we think chronologically about the psyche of the artist within the structure of these particular songs, the urge for the surreal, for the shocking, constitutes the first moment (the moment before the most successful expressions in this album)—in such cases,value is given to an external marker (that of pyrotechnic mental capabilities), so that the contradictions inherent to the act of expression are not accounted for in the work itself. Next we found that the artist replaces the pyrotechnic image with Jesus, but at the very moment Jesus triumphs over all picture-thoughts, he becomes one himself, and so we return to the unconscious screaming, that place where nothing yet has been proffered.</p>
<p>With the internalization of the offering, the song above speaks solely to the skeletal structure of singing, of art. That which is desired will be destroyed if one single breath is taken, if one word is uttered. This word is singular, it is one drop, and yet, in that it “arrives”, it becomes universal, it swallows the whole world, and it is this paradoxical breathtaking moment that is Wayne’s present to the world.</p>
<p>“Please please take it from me…” is an elemental prayer, one which prays for language to continue mediating. This notion of presence, the one that will be destroyed in becoming Word, is no longer the great weight that burdens the artist. It CAN be transmitted, but what do we transmit if nothing is ever spoken? The gift offered by the artist is in reality a plea by the artist to maintain possession of himself without fearing that in not speaking he sacrifices all transmissions… the gift given is the realization of the paradox of subject and object, the singer refuses to identify with a concrete image or even a word. Encircling the dialectic in this way, Wayne can in fact be heard praying to himself, “This is my message to the world…take it from me, please please, take it from me.” He can be heard voicing the plea of the universal, take me into you, this is my message, just this, my plea.</p>
<p>I was not able to possess this gift immediately. I heard Wayne cajoling me to believe in him. Looking back, I don’t know what I could have thought I was supposed to believe in. While Wayne sings of sacrifice, I refuse to do the same—I project (give, present) him with my own self-consciousness, one which still believes that my utterances have particular relation to myself…Wayne is broken apart, refusing to give anything, and all I could hear back then was my own particularity were I to sing such a song and tell everyone how great I was because I had a present. I was unable to realize the irony of that which was present.</p>
<p align="center">***</p>
<p>My friend Darian and I rarely talked about the Flaming Lips, mainly because Darian was always talking about himself, and his music taste was different than mine—he liked punk music and The Grateful Dead. Whenever he spoke madly and convinced me that he was omnipotent, it was always a nice consolation to know how bad his taste in music was. I remember one night he started to obsess over his connection with Hamlet—this was like a challenge everyone in my school seemed to take up at one point or another. And though Darian was illiterate, and had only the <em>Celestine Prophecy</em> on his bookshelf, he too found his way onto the ego trip the Prince of Denmark symbolizes. On one of those cold nights of which there must have been over a hundred each winter, Darian and I ended up taking two chairs into the co-ed bathroom shower stall and turning all four faucets on to the highest heat so we could smoke a joint in a makeshift steam room. While we were in there, Darian stood up and began illustrating to me the way his energy takes him by the reins and whips him about in every direction. It was then that he compared himself to Hamlet. He had no control over himself, he said. He feared that he was going to kill someone one day, and he made a point of asking me how I deal with all the pain and rage, and I just said that I must not feel as much as him, that things must be easier for me, and he consoled me for having submitted myself as such, saying I was a really good friend. But at that moment I had conquered him, I had experienced his ego and refused it; instead of projecting my own suffering, I remained silent.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-392" title="mars" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/mars.jpg" alt="" width="266" height="199" /></p>
<p><em>Take Me Ta Mars</em>:</p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-04-Take-Me-Ta-Mars.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>Yeah, &#8217;cause when I drive in my car</em></p>
<p><em>We put heads into jars</em><br />
<em>So take me please, take me to mars</em><br />
<em>I wanna go where they are [2x]</em><br />
<em>I wanna go</em></p>
<p><em>Yeah, and if I&#8217;m lost, well I don&#8217;t care</em><br />
<em>&#8217;cause I walk on endless stairs</em><br />
<em>You say it&#8217;s me, I think it&#8217;s you</em><br />
<em>Who can blame us for thinkin&#8217; the way we do</em><br />
<em>&#8217;cause we don&#8217;t care what we are [2x]</em></p>
<p><em>Take me please, take me to mars [3x]</em><br />
<em>Take me to mars [5x]</em></p>
<p>I would say that this song is not as brave as the other songs, this is a song about ego-tripping off of alienation. It is about returning the gratuitous violence of existence with one’s own gratuitous violence. But I always loved this song the most exactly because it asked for the least amount of sacrifice; as such, I could remain within myself while feeling utterly different. This was the kind of song that inspired me to imagine all sorts of bloody disfigurations of the people I was passing by. Everyone was guilty of not being different like me, and so to maintain this satisfaction, I had to rid the world of everyone but myself. This then brought me to a barren world, bloodied red, but I didn’t care—and who could blame me for thinking the way I do. As Wayne once sang on an earlier album: &#8220;If you don&#8217;t like it, go write your own song.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I did in fact believe I was the messiah for a few hours one evening. Darian brought over these spidermen acid tabs and while we were waiting for the drug to kick in, and while Darian fussed about with the stove, I desperately needed to be alone. It was only a week after September 11th, so there must have been a lot of gravity in the air. When I made it down to what we called the &#8220;meditation bridge&#8221; the yet to be frozen-over water roared so immensely, and the stars above were crystalline. It was a very metaphysical experience. I drew out my plans for salvation across the cosmos. Darian seemed somehow an asset to me in this frame of mind, somehow it was up to me to harness his power in the correct geometric shape. I don&#8217;t exactly know how to describe what I felt then, I guess it was just an extreme rush, a full-frontal confidence. I was the falling water and I was also whole, specifically me. When the drug finally wore down I felt a tremendous and rather relieving collapse back into myself.</p>
<p><em>Five Stop Mother Superior Rain</em>:</p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-05-Five-Stop-Mother-Superior-Rain.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>I was born the day they shot JFK</em></p>
<p><em>The way you look at me sucks me down the sidewalk</em><br />
<em>Somebody please tell this machine I&#8217;m not a machine</em></p>
<p><em>My hands are in the air</em><br />
<em>And that&#8217;s where they always are</em><br />
<em>You&#8217;re fucked if you do, and you&#8217;re fucked if you don&#8217;t</em><br />
<em>Five stop mother superior rain</em></p>
<p><em>I was born the day they shot john lennon&#8217;s brain</em><br />
<em>And all my smiles are gettin&#8217; in the hate generation&#8217;s way</em><br />
<em>Tell &#8217;em I&#8217;m gonna go out, shoot somebody in the mouth</em><br />
<em>First thing tomorrow</em></p>
<p><em>[chorus]</em></p>
<p><em>I was born the day they shot a hole in the jesus egg</em><br />
<em>Now the rain, it&#8217;s all so random</em><br />
<em>What does free will have to do with it at all?</em><br />
<em>And you can&#8217;t cry, but</em><br />
<em>It really don&#8217;t matter, y&#8217;end up cryin&#8217; anyway.</em></p>
<p><em>[chorus]</em></p>
<p>I believe that this song incorporates all the variants of subject and object from the four prior songs into a metempsychotic journey that, though abandoning the self, remains transparently grounded in such a way that the specific human comes forth in all his love and hatred. No matter where the self originates, no matter where it transmigrates or disappears, it always returns to originate, disappear, or transmigrate. All its nascent forms are historical figures (John Lennon, Jesus, JFK) who represent hope and possibility, each of whom was killed for their revolutionary message. But the message, the same one that remains unspoken in <em>Rainin’ Babies</em>, returns in the disaster of self that loses itself only to arise anew. Now, at last, with the internalization of the external presence of the self, Wayne has self-consciously raised his hands in the air in a gesture of hope and hopelessness… pleading, praying and embracing that which inhibits him from crying, and then makes him cry all the same. Five Stop Mother Superior Rain, who I imagine as the same figure referred to in <em>Unconsciously Screamin’</em>, is neither outside of each figure nor inside. Wayne’s hands are in the air not in prayer to this Rhea or Mother Mary like figure; no, the hands are SHE…whose Reign is all so random that the ultimate freedom is only achieved in the question of free will itself.</p>
<p>This song attains an overemphasized utterance that pulls the slates out from under every ground, so that the movement itself becomes the only mode of beginning and end. And in what is a triumphant call to arms to the musical generation singing all around Wayne and the Flaming Lips—this song calls attention to the impossibility of refusing the smile, the one which decimates the skepticism of the punk rockers, and thusly explains why Wayne later re-titled this album: <em>Finally the Punk Rockers are Taking Acid</em>.</p>
<p align="center">***</p>
<p>My friend Darian ended up trying to kill himself. He had me chase him for five hours in the middle of the night, threatening to use the butcher knife he stole from the mess hall’s kitchen. He had a letter for me that I was supposed to send to his parents—but I ended up calling them right away and they drove up from Pennsylvania and took him out of school for a few days. He never did anything, and when he returned he was exposed, and he knew it. Unable to realize the limitless in his own life, he bound himself to the image of suicide as that which would prove his ego limitless—but, unable to accomplish this action, he had to face his own limitations. And he was humiliated as a result. For me, whatever glory I once attributed to his psyche was also demolished. He had been posturing all along. He had always wanted to be that ‘no longer boy’ who walks on mars, and this resulted in a denial of the ground actually beneath his feet.</p>
<p align="center">***</p>
<p>I guess all of these ideas help me understand Hamlet&#8217;s indecisiveness. Hegel seems so useful because, even without fully grasping his language, he always exposes the various ways a self-consciousness, an ego,  can remain stuck in a flawed identity. I remember my teacher at the time, who was old and hunched over and uninspiring, made a big point of explaining that the ghost of the father was a real figure on the stage—you couldn&#8217;t diagnose Hamlet with madness without implicating yourself in his affliction. If Wayne Coyne and the Flaming Lips have, in their own quirky way, successfully mastered the process of self-alienation, Hamlet is a complete failure—his failure is caused because he can never rid himself of the real objective existence of that which terrifies him. Whereas that which haunts the singer in Wayne’s songs is always unmentioned or impossible to grasp, Hamlet is confronted by a real crime and a real ghost. As a result, he is unable to dislocate from his particular mother and particular father—this creates for him his alarming self-consumption. It is as if the mother and father figures in his life so fully embody the universal metaphor of self and object that he is imprisoned on the dead end street of teenage angst. Hamlet reveals his fixation when he wonders about the dreams that come after death. These dreams, he worries, still might come to the particular, tarnished, battered self… It is of course those who cannot &#8216;break down the molecules&#8217; of selfhood in their own self-consciousness while still alive that have the bravado to wonder about the possibility of eternal torment. The eternal IS already, in the figure of the waving hands, and in the rebirth of souls—a self taken into and out of itself in a persistent dispossession of both full selfhood and pure selflessness. Hamlet&#8217;s indecisiveness occurs because he confines the philosophy of the world to his small little stage—he can find no recourse to shirk his desire to be a self. The resurrection of the father is not the image of the external Jesus but a vain reflection of familial insularity. Hamlet is one of those brats who continually reminds his friends that his family fucked him up…</p>
<p>I don’t remember if I ever contemplated suicide. I know that I would lie in bed and imagine axes splitting off my head, but this just felt like therapy. Many times I would take my headphones down to the Gorge and listen there for hours, screaming along to the lyrics, and this was helpful, I think, much more than trying to make believe I was some tragic hero. <em></em></p>
<p><em>God Walks Among Us Now</em>:</p>
<div class="codeart-google-mp3-player"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://prac-gadget.googlecode.com/svn/branches/google-audio-step.swf" quality="best" flashvars="audioUrl=/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-07-God-Walks-Among-Us-Now-Jesus-Song-No.-6.mp3"  width="350" height="27"></embed></div>
<p><em>How does it feel to be breakin&#8217; apart</em></p>
<p><em>Breakin&#8217; down molecules</em><br />
<em>How does it feel to be out of control</em><br />
<em>Another ring around this ball</em></p>
<p><em>Used to be all right</em><br />
<em>But things got strange</em></p>
<p><em>How does it feel to be fallin&#8217; apart</em><br />
<em>Sinkin&#8217; from the bottom down</em><br />
<em>It&#8217;s not so easy holdin&#8217; it up</em><br />
<em>With everything fallin&#8217; down</em></p>
<p><em>Used to be all right</em><br />
<em>But things got strange</em><br />
<em>Used to take all night</em><br />
<em>But things&#8217;ve changed and God walks among us now</em></p>
<p>“O that this too too sullied flesh would melt, Thaw and resolve itself into dew, Or that the Everlasting had not fix’d his canon ‘gainst self-slaughter. O God! God!”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-01-Shine-On-Sweet-Jesus-Jesus-Song-No.-5.mp3" length="3750225" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-02-Unconsciously-Screamin1.mp3" length="3260518" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-03-Rainin-Babies.mp3" length="3762635" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-04-Take-Me-Ta-Mars.mp3" length="2710476" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-05-Five-Stop-Mother-Superior-Rain.mp3" length="5319496" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/1-07-God-Walks-Among-Us-Now-Jesus-Song-No.-6.mp3" length="4104604" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apocalypse and Democracy</title>
		<link>/mouseonthemoon/apocalypse-and-democracy/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 21:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wealth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=239</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The new NBC series Revolution imagines an apocalyptic fantasy wherein electricity simply stops working, all at once, without scientific explanation. Physics has gone haywire, and no one seems to know why. The opening scene of the first episode stages this event with no shortage of dramatic flourish. Rachel Matheson talks to her mother on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new NBC series <em>Revolution</em> imagines an apocalyptic fantasy wherein electricity simply stops working, all at once, without scientific explanation. Physics has gone haywire, and no one seems to know why. The opening scene of the first episode stages this event with no shortage of dramatic flourish.<span id="more-239"></span> Rachel Matheson talks to her mother on the phone while checking email. Her children, meanwhile, are engrossed in screens, watching cartoons and playing on tablet computers. When Rachel holds the phone to her daughter&#8217;s ear to talk to grandma, the child can&#8217;t be bothered to disengage from her distractions. At this point, Ben Matheson rushes home and tells his wife to fill up the bathtubs. He finishes uploading data onto a flash drive just before Chicago goes dark in increasing scale: home, block, city, countries, continents. Planes drop out of the sky. The headlights of cars stopped on the freeway click off in quick succession.</p>
<p>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JwfCRAtkYEI</p>
<p>The narrative picks up 15 years after the event. Humans have reverted to a pre-industrial economy and landmarks of the capitalist era linger on as anachronisms. Wrigley Field, along with Chicago’s skyline, has been swallowed by vegetation. Meanwhile, the Matheson&#8217;s suburban cul-de-sac has turned into a thriving communitarian enclave: people are herding sheep, teaching school children outdoors, and tending to gardens (one of them planted in a now useless Toyota Prius). Charlie, the daughter who once languished in front of screens, now springs through the forest, hunting with bow and arrow. However, in <em>Revolution</em>, the loss of electronic technology invites both fantasies of utopia and dystopia, existing side by side. It&#8217;s not long before a militia shows up, demanding to take away Ben, leading to a skirmish and Ben&#8217;s death (this we can presume has something to do with the flash drive that Ben uploaded data onto right before the blackout).</p>
<p>While a local economy putters on in small MacIntyrean communities, the vacuum of national political power has resulted in a fractured nation run by several despotic militias (in one episode we see a map in which the United States is divided into five independent territories). The &#8220;Monroe&#8221; militia, under which our protagonists live, does not allow those residing within its borders to own firearms, and in one scene a man caught killing a deer with a rifle is executed. People live in fear of the militia and soon our protagonists find themselves allied with an underground resistance, who are determined to resurrect the constitution of the good ol&#8217; United States of America. Much like CBS&#8217;s <em>Jericho</em>, and TNT&#8217;s <em>Falling Skies</em>, apocalypse brings the opportunity to appreciate the value of democracy. In all of these shows, an event has caused the loss of both the wealth of industrial capitalism and national democratic cohesion. Faced with the loss of the American Dream, the protagonists must restage the American Revolution to recuperate that loss.</p>
<p>What I want to think about regarding <em>Revolution</em> is the knot it ties between the anxieties surrounding our dependence on technology to reproduce wealth (which might also be read as the symbolic displacement of our dependence on a world-wide proletariat), the effects of technology on our capacity to remain human (our daily preference for screens over people, etc.), and the attachment to democracy as that which guarantees a wealth above and beyond any material concerns, something like freedom or justice.</p>
<p>Democracy in this show, however, is understood in a rather narrow sense: as a government that protects private property, that protects the right to bear arms, and that holds elections. The democracy that our protagonists fight for is a Jeffersonian fantasy, one that steels itself against tyranny and oppression from without, but that, of course, does not concern itself with oppression from within (i.e. the effects of the modernity that capitalism enacts). What’s remarkable about <em>Revolution</em>, and this genre in general, is the way in which the post-apocalyptic world is already suited to match this fantasy. It isn&#8217;t necessary to bother with class conflict here, because it simply no longer exists. The reproduction of wealth (food, clothing, etc.) is now located in the immediacy of a local community. The industrial/capitalist structures that served to maintain a ‘normal’ level of wealth prior to the blackout, and the class antagonisms inherent to them, can no longer be construed as the fault line of a societal weakness. This provides the series unfettered access to a fantasy in which our political problems might actually be solved by providing small self-sustaining communities with protection from easily visible tyranny. The fantasy is then concretized by an abundance of tattered flags, muskets, and other Revolutionary War paraphernalia.</p>
<p>When a hallowed version of democracy no longer seems to apply to the world, fiction steps in to provide the world instead, leaving the fantasy unchanged. In this way, the show “contains” (in Jamesonian parlance) the structural by transforming it into the moral. I don’t know where the show is going, but if it’s anything like <em>Jericho</em> (a show about an American nuclear holocaust, which is later discovered to be perpetrated by a Blackwater-type organization), and it seems to be heading in that direction, the blackout is not the result of the contingent natural world, or an environmental or economic catastrophe caused by capitalism, but rather some kind of government or corporate conspiracy, whose pursuits are often the banal desire for power as such (there is a post I should write about ‘bad guys’ in various genres, and the necessary deferral of a banal desire that retroactively becomes the cause of an event). The loss then is imagined to be democratic in the narrow sense, as the loss of some form of government transparency in which either a government is accountable or in which a true democratic government holds others accountable (but of course, only for being crony-capitalists, not simply capitalists).</p>
<p>However, the loss of all the wealth that capitalism provides has a dual purpose. For one, this loss provides a world in which a reinstantiation of a Jeffersonain democracy is somehow adequate to fight injustice, unlike in our world, in which it’s not. But it also provides the opportunity to negotiate our anxieties as consumers, as humans who are afraid that we’ve lost something human as a result of our proliferating non-human attachments. Much is made of how characters cope with and understand a world in which it is no longer possible to access to a wealth that is not the product of one’s own labor. The problem does not reside in, of course, the social structures necessary for its production and for its uneven distribution, but rather, the way in which it distracts us from what ‘really matters.’ The show never questions the assumption that we should have and that we deserve all of this wealth (if only we had antibiotics!, what I wouldn’t give for a Twinkie and a hot shower!), it’s just afraid that wealth and technology have turned humanism into an atavism. We’ve lost, for one, an obligation to the Jeffersonian fantasy of democracy, and two, an obligation to human and natural relationships.</p>
<p>The logic is that an excess of one kind of wealth, like absorbing screen technology, distracts us from our commitments to another kind of wealth, the enlightenment ideals of freedom and justice, the love of friends and family, the pleasures of a non-digitally-mediated childhood, etc. So, you know, let’s not let go of these things that make life worth living while we drool over keyboards and internet pornography. In one scene a female character carries around an old and now useless iPhone. When another character confronts her about it, she explains, with great sentiment, that the only pictures that she has of her children are somewhere inside of it, and that she spends hours staring at it, vainly hoping that it will turn on. This is less a ludic plea for analog technology than a reminder of all that we have to lose when we forget the democratic and humanistic ideals that we (wrongly) imagine hold modernity together, now more fragile than ever. The show plays with the anxiety that technology is crowding out family, that we’ve placed our children in the hands of a precarious way of life, but it’s precarious not for any unsustainability built into the logic of its mode of production (economic or environmental) but because we’ve let our human obligations founder amongst the bright shiny toys of modernity. In other words, the negative effects of the wealth that capitalism provides are also moral and not structural.</p>
<p>This working-through of our anxieties regarding the effects of wealth and technology are clear: the consequences of this loss at a local scale are liberating (finally we recovered the values that wealth obscured) while on a national scale they are disastrous (an American democracy compromised by a world inadequate to its Jeffersonian ideals regresses to a pre-modern despotism). But, of course, the stage is then set for a pointless repetition of an American revolution, and both ideals are recovered. For <em>Revolution</em>, The solution to modernity is a return to the authentic values and habits of a pre-modern or early-modern world, but only so that we never have to lose the modern world, in order to keep it afloat, as though we can have it both ways. We can’t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lana Del Rey, Failing</title>
		<link>/mouseonthemoon/lana-del-rey-failing/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 22:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coprophagia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the wrong moment to comment on Lana del Rey, especially for a blog about contemporary culture. Her national infamy occurred nearly a year ago and was short lived after a widely panned performance on SNL. Even Brian Williams was tweeting about it. But my belatedness is, I suppose, fitting for what I want [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the wrong moment to comment on Lana del Rey, especially for a blog about contemporary culture. Her national infamy occurred nearly a year ago and was short lived after a widely panned performance on SNL. Even Brian Williams was tweeting about it. But my belatedness is, I suppose, fitting for what I want to say about her. <span id="more-119"></span> That her lyrics are all about failing to meet expectations. They are about trying to inhabit a genre of femininity and failing, or rather, the genre of femininity failing her. Her music, a slow and fatigued dirge, is the symptom of this failure. And her out-of-tune performance on SNL? Well, it was both bad singing and exemplary of her entire persona.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take her first breakthrough single, &#8220;Video Games&#8221;.</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="500" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HO1OV5B_JDw" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The music video cuts back and forth between a close-up of a gaunt looking Lana standing against a white wall and a variety of old super-eight movies and clips of old Hollywood. Her lips are artificially enlarged. She looks like an undead pin-up girl. She sings in a low contralto voice: &#8220;Swinging in the backyard / Pull up in your fast car / Whistling my name / Open up a beer / And you say, get over here / And play a video game.&#8221;  Here, a courting scene is evoked between a young girl, still on the swing set, and a careless man in a car, who simply whistles for her to come. These characters are rehearsing what has become one of the most clichéd scenes of Americana: a young innocent girl waiting to be taken away by a dynamic man in a muscle car. But by the end of the phrase, this scene of expectation becomes a tragedy of failed romance. The man drinks, yells, and ignores her.</p>
<p>The rest of the song is filled with the hollow expressions of sentimental romance: &#8220;I say you the bestest / Lean in for a big kiss, put his favorite perfume on.&#8221;  Only to collapse the hope of expectation with, &#8220;Go play a video game.&#8221;  Also, these scenes of failure are accompanied by the ideological supplementations of romantic self-help books and women&#8217;s magazines. For example, &#8220;They say that the world was built for two / Only worth living if somebody is loving you.&#8221;  These cliches, however, always undercut themselves: &#8220;Heaven is a place on earth with you / Tell me all the things you want to do.&#8221; The image of romantic utopia, that this character is so desperately trying to cling to, twists into the acquiescence to a masculine will.</p>
<p>Most pop music is not cynical about love, but there are plenty of songs that sing the praises of tempering expectations. Songs about heartbreak sometimes take on this mode, but they rarely question the value of love in itself. What I find so strange about Lana de Rey, however, is the starkness of the irony, the large discrepancy between the flat fatigue of the music and the seemingly endless repetitions of romantic clichés and Americana icons. Her music expresses the affect of disappointment, while her lyrics bubble from the shattered desires of a feminine unconscious that does not know it&#8217;s broken.</p>
<p>She has recently posted a music video to a new single called, &#8220;Ride&#8221;, wherein she sings about &#8220;freedom,&#8221;  all the while riding with a disgustingly old and overweight biker gang.</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="500" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Py_-3di1yx0" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The video is nearly ten minutes long, and begins with her swinging on a giant tire swing in the middle of the desert (ahem, much like the beginning of &#8220;Video Games&#8221;) and then street walking in high heels in front of roadside motels. A long voice-over begins, in a quiet, babyish tone: &#8220;I was in the winter of my life, and the men I met along the road were my only summer, at night I fell asleep to visions of myself dancing and laughing and crying with them. Three years down the road … my memories of them were the only things that sustained me.&#8221;  But mind you, these men are bearded, leather-clad bikers in their 50s. When the song kicks in, she sings about being on &#8220;that open road. She sings, &#8220;you can be my full time daddy&#8221;  while wrapped in a dusty American flag. In one scene, she&#8217;s standing in front of a pinball machine, smoking and glassy-eyed, while one of these grisly bikers stands behind her. She leans forward on the table while he humps her. The song ends in an enormous bonfire, while Lana wears a Native American headdress and holds a pistol. The bikers drive their bikes in and out of the fire and swill whiskey.</p>
<p>The critical question is how do we read this irony and can we safely read it as such? One could just say that Lana thinks that old gross bikers are sexy. Or that the bikers are simply symbolic of freedom <em>tout court </em>and their fatness and their world of masculine insularity are beside the point. Maybe. After all, she ends the song by asking, &#8220;Have you created a life where you can experience your darkest fantasies?&#8221;  But I&#8217;m not sure this changes anything. The point is not to expose the fantasies as illegitimate because of their origins, but to show what it means to be trapped somewhere in between the genres that sustain us and the world that refuses them. At one point in the voice-over, she says, &#8220;they [who have a home] have no idea what it&#8217;s like to seek safety in other people.&#8221;  They who have a home have no idea what it&#8217;s like having to seek safety under the thin shades of romance and femininity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
