<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Moloch &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/moloch/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Neoliberalism and Its Discontents</title>
		<link>/le-manque/neoliberalism-and-its-discontents/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 06:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[le manque]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1338</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On September 11, 1973—now referred to as the “other 9/11”—Augusto Pinochet staged a successful coup to oust Chile’s democratically elected president, Salvador Allende. Backed by the CIA, American business interests, and the blessings of Henry Kissinger, Pinochet, enlisting economists trained under Milton Friedman and the so-called “Chicago boys,” restructured the Chilean economy in the image [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1349" alt="Margaret Thatcher and Ronald Reagan" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Margaret-Thatcher-and-Ron-0101.jpg" width="460" height="276" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">On September 11, 1973—now referred to as the “other 9/11”—Augusto Pinochet staged a successful coup to oust Chile’s democratically elected president, Salvador Allende. Backed by the CIA, American business interests, and the blessings of Henry Kissinger, Pinochet, enlisting economists trained under Milton Friedman and the so-called “Chicago boys,” restructured the Chilean economy in the image of what has now come to be known as “neoliberalism,” that state apparatus which seeks to deregulate markets, privatize formerly public assets, minimize the power of unions, unleash all manner of austerity measures—in short, to ensure, in the name of freedom, an increasingly frictionless flow of capital across borders and into the bank accounts of those in power.</p>
<p><span id="more-1338"></span>As David Harvey recounts the whole affair in <i>A Brief History of Neoliberalism </i>(2005), which reads like an update to <em>The Condition of Postmodernity </em>(1990), the experiment in Chile, while continuous with many other foreign ventures in which the United States has installed a “strongman” to manage its economic interests, was a kind of primal scene of neoliberal state formation, a blueprint for the structural readjustments that would soon be implemented on New York City as a solution to its own fiscal crisis in the mid-1970s. These reforms were nothing short of a “coup by the financial institutions against the democratically elected government of New York City” (45). The policies that would subsequently flourish under the Reagan and Thatcher governments of the 1980s were, each in their own way, in the words of William Tabb, “merely the New York scenario, writ large” (qtd. in Harvey 48). For Harvey, neoliberalism amounts to a “political project to re-establish the conditions for capital accumulation and to restore the power of economic elites” (19), and <i>A Brief History</i> is a by turns devastating, demoralizing, and downright despairing account—the “political-economic story”—of how this all came to pass, “so comprehensively on the world stage” (4), and what, if anything, anyone (not to speak of any <i>one</i> liberal academic) can do about it.</p>
<p>Of crucial interest, as far as concerns the other two books under consideration here—Cyrus Patell’s <i>Negative Liberties: Morrison and Pynchon and the Problem of Liberal Ideology </i>(2001) and Lauren Berlant’s <i>Cruel Optimism</i> (2011)—is the way Harvey tracks how the “impoverished condition of public discourse” (183) has perverted the meaning of words like freedom and individualism, as the political and economic constraints of embedded liberalism, the system of more-or-less Keynesian policies that largely dominated the post-war period until the 1970s, have everywhere given way to the free-market exuberance of neoliberalism. Here the book’s second chapter, “The Construction of Consent,” is particularly useful, charting the ways in which the neoliberal ethos &#8220;had to be backed up by a practical strategy that emphasized the liberty of consumer choice, not only with respect to particular products but also with respect to lifestyles, modes of expression, and a wide range of cultural practices. Neoliberalism required both politically and economically the construction of a neoliberal market-based populist culture differentiated consumerism and individual libertarianism. As such it proved more than a little compatible with that cultural impulse called ‘post-modernism’ which had long been lurking in the wings but could now emerge full-blown as both a cultural and an intellectual dominant&#8221; (42).</p>
<p>This passage undoubtedly resonates with the work of Walter Benn Michaels, who, poor Atlas, has taken it upon his shoulders to enlighten his brethren in English departments across the land as to the &#8220;synergies&#8221; (the word is Berlant&#8217;s) between neoliberalism and all those post-&#8217;68 ideologies of desire—Walter&#8217;s constant refrain: &#8220;we are not as liberal as we like to think we are&#8221;—but one is in due time relieved to find that Harvey does not have a similar axe to grind. Instead, what comes across is a kind of sober critical pathos, but also something like optimism, especially in his pointed observations concerning the contradictions between neoliberal theory and practice. “Given the volatility,” Harvey writes with much prescience, “there is no reason to rule out the resurgence of popular social democratic or even populist anti-neoliberal politics within the US in future years” (199). One thinks with tragic irony of the Occupy Movement—along with its more febrile, if more successful, cousin, the Tea Party—which did manage to register, and perhaps leave more than a few traces behind of, the various species of discontent voiced, at ever louder decibels, behind the juggernaut of finance capitalism. While Obama’s reelection is a sign that, at least for the time being, the <i>center</i> of American politics has held together, as Jonathan Alter has recently claimed (with an implicit dig at Yeats’s less implicit variety of fascist apocalypticism), Harvey nevertheless puts what looks like hope in the ability of Occupy and other “such movements [to] shift the terrain of political organization away from traditional political parties and labour organizing into a less focused political dynamic of social action across the whole spectrum of society” (200). But in no way is Harvey advocating, despite his own affinities with Fredric Jameson, some kind of “utopian Marxian fantasy to which we can retire” (202); in fact, he ends up endorsing, as a starting point, a return to the policies of Franklin Roosevelt, that is, to something like embedded liberalism, with its focus on social welfare, full employment, and the ability for the government to intervene, forcefully, when things go wrong. Indeed, we are left with a sense that history did not have to turn out quite the way it did. To combat the spiraling stagflation and unemployment of the 1970s, notes Harvey with notable poignancy, we had a debate “between those ranged behind social democracy and central planning on the one hand”—at one point even Richard Nixon, hamstrung as he was by a Democratically controlled Congress, had said “we are all Keynesians now”—“and the interests of all those concerned with liberating corporate and business power and re-establishing market freedoms on the other” (13). In stressing how much of a “minority political, ideological, and intellectual position” the latter was before it entered the mainstream (62), Harvey, more than anything, demonstrates just how fluid and unpredictable even mainstream politics can become in times of crisis—a profound opportunity, assuredly, but also a grave danger.</p>
<p>How might American, global, and transnational subjects <i>live</i> the experience of the neoliberal demolition of the welfare state? By turning her astonishing critical intelligence to this archive of alternative voices, Lauren Berlant stages an entry into what she calls the “scene of neoliberal restructuring within the ordinary” (16). Her overall project here is to “track the fraying relation between post-Second World War state/economic practices and certain postwar fantasies of the good life endemic to liberal, social democratic, or relatively wealthy regions” (15). For Berlant, the “good life” fantasy has become “<i>more</i> fantasmatic” than ever, “with less and less relation to how people can live—as the blueprint has faded—its attrition manifest[ing] itself in an emerging set of aesthetic conventions that make a claim to affective realism derived from embodied, affective rhythms of survival” (11). In plainer language, now that the most recent financial crisis has exposed the progressive disappearance of all kinds of liberal assurances since the Reagan era, structures of fantasy, or a “collectively invested form of life,” can no longer “disavow” or “mask” the “precariousness of the present” (11).</p>
<p>Now one of the first things to note about Berlant’s book is its style, even the fact that it <em>has </em>a style (however impersonal), its attention to the way its own language recombines so many different critical idioms in new, unusual, and often surprising ways, a tight-rope act that manages to balance, <i>precariously </i>now, just on the other side of catachresis. We encounter phrases like “gestural economies,” “situation tragedy,” “impasse of adjustment,” “crisis ordinary,” “the stretched-out present moment,” “surrealistic affectsphere,” to name a few, phrases that you would by no means expect to hear in everyday language, but what must percolate into the writing mind as a formal solution to the unbridgeable gap that separates tenure from precarity as it is actually lived. We learn that in “the impasse induced by crisis, being treads water; mainly it does not drown” (10). Sometimes she uses a transitive verb intransitively and vice versa, as in “when he returns home his body <i>perturbs</i> and requires adjustment,&#8221; and in “the subject’s desire to <i>temporize</i> an experience of the loss of an object” (205, 24, my emphases). All too often one suspects that Berlant is merely stating the same <em>thing</em> over and over again, but only the words themselves seem to change, swiftly passing by on the conveyor belt of syntax, metonymy and metaphor on the verge of collapse. Some may find these quirks rebellious, even as they perturb others, but I point all this out to emphasize the hyper-linguistic atmosphere Berlant strives to create, as if her very subject matter—i.e., the “fantasmatic, affective, and physical adjustments” which measure “survival in the impasse of the present” (16)—demands from the academic reader a new kind of affective orientation toward language, as if in some hitherto unimaginable way the wish-fulfilling forces of the Imaginary just might be able to do what Kafka&#8217;s man from the country could not: bribe the incorruptible guard at the entryway to the Law in order to reorganize, if not downright abolish, the Symbolic order—were it not for the fact that, in Fredric Jameson&#8217;s resounding sentence, &#8220;History is what hurts&#8221; in the end.</p>
<p>What is it that is so <i>cruel</i> about optimism, anyway? In its most succinct formulation, cruel optimism names a “relation of attachment to compromised conditions of possibility whose realization is discovered either to be <i>im</i>possible, sheer fantasy, or <i>too</i> possible, and toxic” (24). It would be too easy to claim that this is about as good a description as there is with respect to what keeps most of us attached to &#8220;the life of the mind,&#8221; and many a low-income graduate student, forever questioning the sanity of a career path that bars all but the most market-driven from participating in the &#8220;good life,&#8221; may at this point lean closer to the non-chlorinated page. Yet it is true that any number of non-intellectual attachments are also optimistic, insofar as they would seem to hold out a “cluster of promises” which could be “embedded in a person, a thing, an institution, a text, a norm, a bunch of cells, smells, a good idea—whatever&#8221; (24); but as Berlant points out, some are <i>crueler</i> than others: “where cruel optimism operates, the very vitalizing or animating potency of an object/scene of desire contributes to the attrition of the very thriving that is supposed to be made possible in the work of attachment in the first place” (25). Suffice it to say that in this and other places Berlant never does quite distinguish how &#8220;cruel optimism&#8221; modulates desire any differently than the way the poets have always described it. The book thus examines many different <em>contemporary</em> flavors of desire&#8217;s optimistic double bind, even though at times what seems to be at stake is not really desire but a basic need just barely articulated, the good life so easily modifiable into a life of, for, and after all the mass-produced &#8220;goods&#8221; that this uncertain moment in the information age has begun to withhold from more and more of us—in return at least for more virtual, or shall we say &#8220;skeuomorphic,&#8221; pleasures. From the obesity epidemic to Hurricane Katrina, Berlant seeks to understand what keeps a person rooted, libidinally or otherwise, to a way of life, in search of the Good or the goods (no matter), in spite of its obvious, increasingly avowed dangers to the self. A chapter that illustrates this particular slippage with what we can only call success is one entitled “After the Good Life, An Impasse,” which analyzes the “precarious cinema” of Laurent Cantet, particularly <i>Ressources humaines </i>(1999)<i> </i>and <i>L’Emploi du temps </i>(2001). With striking clarity, these films depict a “precarious public sphere” composed of that new “affective class,” the precariat, which cuts across ordinarily fixed lines of racial, class, gender, and privilege: what members of this class all share is an “affective imaginary,” in which “an adaptation to a <i>sense</i> of precarity dramatizes the situation of the present” (195). Here Berlant explores the link between the macroeconomics of neoliberalism, or “the fraying of norms, that is, of genres of reliable living” and the microeconomics of the aesthetic, or the “politico-effective condition [which arises] mainly in messy situations, episodes, incidents, and gestures” (196). Her reading of the father’s quivering lip at the end of <i>Ressources humaines </i>(211), in which the scene of “facial drama reminds us that disbelief can be a political emotion” is one of the book&#8217;s best demonstrations of the way gesture, in finding a form, is as much an opening out onto a new scene of potentialities as an indication of the precarity within. It may not be desire, but hey, it&#8217;s &#8220;not nothing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Like Berlant and Harvey, Patell also registers a crisis at the level of the individual, but what is remarkable, in this regard, is that his critique of individualism does not spring from a neoliberal framework; this is both the book’s strength, freeing him from all the problems inherent in tarrying with the “narcissism of the now,” but this is also its primary weakness. He begins by recounting one of his student’s observations in the ‘80s that <i>these guys</i>—namely, Emerson and Whitman—sound a lot like Reagan, and he sets out to understand how “so many Americans could find Ronald Reagan’s rhetoric to be so persuasive when I found it to be so patently full of rationalizations and deceptions” (ix). So whereas Harvey traces the origins of neoliberalism’s “construction of consent” back to Frederick von Hayek and the Mount Pelerin Society, whose founding statement with its “commitment to the individual” famously confuses personhood and corporation (Harvey 20), Patell reaches much further back in history, providing a genealogy of individualism from Locke through de Tocqueville to Rawls and Kateb, in order to understand the “continuing persuasiveness of individualism as an ideology” (19). But it is what he describes as “Emersonian liberalism” that is “perhaps the most powerful version of U.S. liberal ideology,” the “ground upon which contemporary U.S. liberal theory is built” (xv), and also the “tradition that has arisen in the United States around the idea of self-reliance, a tradition that represents the crystallization of what might be called the <i>official narrative</i> of U.S. individualism” (xiii). Moreover, this “official narrative” sets negative liberty and positive liberty in a teleological relationship: that is, care for the self leads to care for the community. The problem here, for Patell, is that in the passage from negative to positive liberty, categories such as race and gender tend to disappear. In the case of race, for instance, “the ostensible universality of the nation’s founding principles serves to prolong the nation’s inability to recover fully from the evils of slavery” (25). Patell thus registers how the universalist rhetoric of the official narrative “prevents many Americans from being able to recognize that systemic discrimination does exist in the United States” (25). In this instance, followers of Walter Benn Michaels might be tempted to point out that, as far as class inequality goes, Emerson’s “Self Reliance” could not be more disdainful of capital accumulation; but Patell’s point, I take it, is that Emerson’s essay lays the groundwork for individualism’s perversion.</p>
<p>What does this have to do with Thomas Pynchon and Toni Morrison? And what do Pynchon and Morrison even have in common, aside from their affiliation with Cornell University (left curiously unremarked by Patell)? Taking a cue from Linda Hutcheon, Patell sees postmodernism, at least its incarnation in certain strains of American literature, as an exercise in “aesthetic prowess” whose “outlook” is “deeply political” (xvii). Thus Pynchon and Morrison, writers who so manifestly occupy separate “subject positions” are rarely considered <i>together</i> as working in a postmodern aesthetic “engaged,” in Hutcheon’s words, “in contesting the modernist (humanist) premises of art’s apolitical autonomy and of theory and criticism as value-free activities” (qtd. in xvii). In this way, Patell would seem to offer something of an antidote not only to David Harvey’s indictment of postmodernism but also to Sean McCann and Michael Szalay’s widely debated article from 2005, “‘Do You Believe in Magic’: Literary Thinking after the New Left,” which argues that American critics and novelists since the sixties have abandoned “public debate and civic engagement,” instead espousing a “political vision” predicated on “the spontaneous, symbolic, and, ultimately, the magical” (436). According to McCann and Szalay, <i>The Crying of Lot 49</i>, for example, is complicit with the kind of “libertarian sympathies” endemic to the counterculture of the sixties, and Oedipa Maas emerges as a kind of libertarian anti-hero (a self-avowed Young Republican whom the authors link rather hastily with “Pynchon as well,” strangely unable to perceive how the novel stages her political conversion). For Patell, however, <i>The Crying of Lot 49</i> “debunks the official narrative of individualism by revealing narcissism in place of individuality and paranoia in answer to Emerson’s call for self-reliance. . . .Pynchon’s novel confirms the communitarian diagnosis of the ills of individualism, but it also dramatizes the hopeless inadequacy of the communitarian prescription for social healing” (152). Patell’s reading of <em>The </em><i>Crying of Lot 49 </i>is representative of his procedure throughout the book; everywhere Patell seeks to demonstrate how Pynchon and Morrison contest the “official narrative” and, while their characters might not be able to, the authors themselves manage to evade out-and-out complicity.</p>
<p>The problem with all this is that the game seems rigged from the start, for Patell begins by admitting that he is in “agreement with Chantal Mouffe’s belief that we must ‘redress the negative consequences of individualism’ by dissociating ‘the liberal ideals of individual freedom and personal autonomy’ from ‘the other discourses to which they have been articulated’” (xv-xvi). In this way, Pynchon’s and Morrison’s novels do not really stand a chance to do anything <i>but</i> provide critiques of individualism on the one hand and communitarianism on the other, to occupy Mouffe’s not-too-hot/not-too-cold politics, someplace between Habermas and Sandel. In fact, Patell ignores some of the more problematic racial passages in Pynchon’s novels. In <em>V.</em><i>, </i>for instance, we now know that Pynchon lifted much of his African material almost verbatim from his sources, but Patell cites these passages approvingly to demonstrate Pynchon’s critique of “racial violence” (90), when something more unsettling seems to be taking place at the textual level that we shall refrain from calling authorial enjoyment at the reader’s expense. Even more odd, Patell only briefly mentions <i>Mason &amp; Dixon</i>, a novel in which he claims “Pynchon makes his closest approach to Morrison’s territory” (196). A critic cannot do everything, it is true, but the fact that Patell makes no mention of one of Pynchon’s most outrageous creations in <i>Mason &amp; Dixon</i>, Gershom, George Washington’s African-Hebrew slave, who embodies a fair number of black and Jewish stereotypes that would seem to go fetishistically beyond what a realist presentation of the period itself calls for, is a shocking but ultimately telling absence.</p>
<p>Despite their vastly different archives and critical approaches, Harvey, Berlant, and Patell each establishes a relation to their objects of critique that are optimistic, insofar as they participate in a liberal tradition whose vitality, as Raymond Geuss would put it, stems from its discontent with the way things are now. For Harvey, “there is a far, far nobler prospect of freedom to be won than that which neoliberalism preaches” (206). For Berlant, the impasse of the self-encounter in the “crisis ordinary” might allow us “to produce some better ways of mediating the sense of a historical moment that is affectively felt but undefined in the social world that is supposed to provide some comforts of belonging, so that it would be possible to imagine a potentialized present that does not reproduce all of the conventional collateral damage” (263). And for Patell, postmodern novels like Pynchon’s and Morrison’s help “to imagine a new cosmopolitanism able to promote the ideals of self-autonomy and self-expression <i>and </i>to expose and defeat slavery and oppression wherever they exist” (196). To quote Portia from the <i>Merchant of Venice</i>, perhaps Shakespeare’s most cruelly optimistic character: “if to do were as easy as to know what were good to do, chapels had been churches and poor men&#8217;s cottages princes&#8217; palaces” (1.2, 15-17). In the meantime, the search for alternatives continues.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Berlant, Lauren. <i>Cruel Optimism</i>. Durham: Duke University Press, 2001.</p>
<p>Harvey, David. <i>A Brief History of Neoliberalism</i>. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2005.</p>
<p>McCann, Sean and Michael Szalay. “Do you believe in Magic? Literary Thinking after the New Left.” <i>The Yale Journal of Criticism</i>.18.2 (2005): 435-468.</p>
<p>Patell, Cyrus R.K. <i>Negative Liberties: Morrison and Pynchon and the Problem of Liberal Ideology</i>. Durham: Duke University Press, 2001.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Koons Erects another Chuckle</title>
		<link>/j-r/koons-erects-another-chuckle/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 16:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is probably one of Koons&#8217; minor works at his new solo show at the Gagosian. I don&#8217;t know what it is called: &#8220;Flower Power&#8221;? I always tell people Koons is my favorite artist and it makes them upset. Recently, I tried to defend myself and say that he &#8220;always erects something that has an irrefutable presence, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1269" title="0604131617" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131617-500x375.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131617-500x375.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131617-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131617.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>This is probably one of Koons&#8217; minor works at his new solo show at the Gagosian. I don&#8217;t know what it is called: &#8220;Flower Power&#8221;? I always tell people Koons is my favorite artist and it makes them upset. Recently, I tried to defend myself and say that he &#8220;always erects something that has an irrefutable presence, and it always makes me chuckle.&#8221; And she said, &#8220;I think the erection is the problem here.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1270" title="0604131622" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131622-500x375.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131622-500x375.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131622-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/0604131622.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Age Culture, or the Metastases of Neoliberalism</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/new-age-culture-or-the-metastases-of-neoliberalism/</link>
		<comments>/anti-orpheus/new-age-culture-or-the-metastases-of-neoliberalism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=922</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Brought to you by Lululemon.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brought to you by Lululemon.</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/new-age-platitudes-or-neoliberalism/photo-13-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-924"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-924" title="photo-13" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-131-375x500.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-131-375x500.jpg 375w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-131-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-131.jpg 1224w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/anti-orpheus/new-age-culture-or-the-metastases-of-neoliberalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Museums as the Cathedrals or Mausoleums of Post-Modernity?</title>
		<link>/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/</link>
		<comments>/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Peaty]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Etch-A-Sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(Above Left: St. Peter&#8217;s Basilica in Rome / Above Right: MoMA in NYC) While visiting MoMA last Sunday to convene with a small group of friends, I mused upon a recurring inquisition: has the contemporary art museum usurped the church’s position as a surrogate “place of worship”, at least for certain culture-craving demographics? Aside from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img class=" wp-image-803" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/montage1-500x165.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="132" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/montage1-500x165.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/01/montage1.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><br />
(Above Left: St. Peter&#8217;s Basilica in Rome / Above Right: MoMA in NYC)</p>
<p>While visiting MoMA last Sunday to convene with a small group of friends, I mused upon a recurring inquisition: has the contemporary art museum usurped the church’s position as a surrogate “place of worship”, at least for certain culture-craving demographics?</p>
<p>Aside from the palpable communitarian ethos at a popular museum on any given weekend, such as the Metropolitan, MoMA, or Guggenheim (to name but a few), I am always struck by the flocks who congregate amidst the hallowed halls, quite possibly in search of transcendence, if not the sublime. <span id="more-800"></span></p>
<p>The formal and aesthetic parallels are myriad and obvious. To name a few, consider the architectural scale and layout of two iconic institutions, e.g.: the vastness of the nave, transepts, and dome structure in St. Peter’s Basilica with MoMA&#8217;s (NY) endless corridors, galleries, and colossal, luminous atrium. With a seemingly metaphysical combination of scale and ethereal illumination, both spaces conjure a strong sense of the spiritual, whether that is “spiritual” in the religious or non-religious sense. Aside from the fact that the architectural plan of each environment tightly governs the physical procession of the masses, it is worth noting how peoples’ otherwise more instinctual postures and perambulations become acutely affected, if not suddenly self-conscious upon encountering an object of veneration. Just envision visitors nimbly, yet reverently circumnavigating the Papal Alter and Baldacchino of St. Peter’s transposed with how one might negotiate a Torqued Ellipse by Richard Serra at MoMA.</p>
<p>In short, if we can agree on this analogy – that modern museums have become the “developed” world’s primary sites for a spiritual form of cultural-worship – then museums are replete with professional curators and trustees who consecrate “art objects” and offer wall didactics, just as priests have consecrated religious icons and reliquaries, while having provided sermons for congregations. And of course the style of delivery and presentation varies greatly, whether we are discussing a Pentecostal, Gospel, or Protestant ceremony, versus the Louvre, MoMA, or New Museum.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I have little interest in debating if one format is better than the other, for that seems a futile discussion. However, since many museum-goers seem to seek a sort of “spiritual fulfillment” afforded by ritual visitations (for instance, I have heard a young painter fervently describe his “weekly pilgrimages to Mattisse” at MoMA), how might we critically unpack the many layers of viewer worship, participation, and aptitude (or lack thereof)? For instance, do most viewers engage the museum experience with a critical approach — a methodology which not only allows one to deconstruct an art object within its own system of logic, but also a way with which to analyze the context (both physical and historic), and to therefore heighten one’s awareness of curatorial strategies, juxtapositions, or even exhibition design itself? Or are the majority of visitors equally, if not predominantly, drawn to the more fundamental experience, e.g, the: elevation of visiting an “ivory tower”; collective activity of spectatorship; communal “appreciation” of the aesthetic transcendence not theoretically attainable in daily life; and perhaps even a docile acceptance of curatorial judgement? Plus, this does not even address the fundamental issue of a museum, which necessitates the stripping of a work from its original context (no longer in situ). These are but a few questions that might allow us to better dissect the contemporary museum-goer’s range of experience in relation to its religiosity or spirituality. Why in essence do we visit museums? Interestingly, we might note the English etymology of “curator” derives from the late Middle English term for an ecclesiastical pastor. But I digress and wish to defer the debate surrounding the contemporary use of “curate” and “curator”.</p>
<p>That aside, if museums are places of cultural worship and validation, where does this leave the contemporary artist? The phenomenon of the living artist (often young) who aspires to “place” work in a museum collection – not only as a form of self-preservation, but as “cultural consecration” and/or validation (whether cultural, market-driven, or both) – is a relatively new phenomenon originating in the 20th Century. This trend presents an inevitable reversal of the old guard, Eurocentric stereotype where art museums are institutions premised upon “storing and exhibiting the work of dead people”. Or in the words of Robert Smithson, “The Museums…are graveyards above the ground – congealed memories of the past that act as a pretext for reality”. Point taken. So in today’s world, with a fair number of young artists finally exalted in museum exhibits and collections around the globe (as an ostensible antidote to what Smithson would have previously regarded as the “graveyard” mentality), is the “new” museum atmosphere truly reinvigorated for both audiences and the living artist? As a young artist, is it healthy (let alone realistic) to seek the “holy grail” of imprimaturs from the high priests of culture (museum curators), along with the implicit promise of artistic immortality in one’s own lifetime? Or on the contrary, if “contemporary museums” are more like glorified mausoleums, is it righteous for the living artist to literally and metaphorically burry themselves in the museum vaults – a “death-by-institution” per se? Apropos, we might recall Gertrude Stein’s response to former MoMA Director, Alfred H. Barr’s plea that she bequest her collection to the museum: &#8220;You can be a museum, or you can be modern, but you can&#8217;t be both.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Use and Abuse of Cleavage</title>
		<link>/j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/</link>
		<comments>/j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 16:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baroque]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cleavage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dialectical image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lacan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walter Benjamin]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;[…W]hat Proust experienced in the phenomenon of remembrance as an individual, we have to experience in regard to fashion.&#8221;                     &#8211;Susan Buck-Morss, The Dialectics of Seeing: Walter Benjamin and the Arcades Project, p. 39 By the end of Walter Benjamin’s life, the concept of ‘the dialectical-image’ [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;[…W]hat Proust experienced in the phenomenon of remembrance as an individual, we have to experience in regard to fashion.&#8221;      <em>              </em></p>
<p><em>&#8211;</em>Susan Buck-Morss, <em>The Dialectics of Seeing: Walter Benjamin and the Arcades Project</em>, p. 39</p>
<p>By the end of Walter Benjamin’s life, the concept of ‘the dialectical-image’ became the focal point for his unfinished <em>Arcades Project</em>. The development of this concept began early in his life when he resurrected the value of allegory, distinguishing it from the symbol. Studying baroque theater in <em>The Origin of German Tragic Drama</em> Benjamin writes, “Allegorical personification has always concealed the fact that its function is not the personification of things, but rather to give the concrete a more imposing form by getting it up as a person” <span id="more-714"></span>(<em>The Origin of German Tragic Drama</em>, p.187). Benjamin’s difficult dissertation, and the subsequently fragmented nature of his work on the transition from the baroque allegory to the modern dialectical-image, has challenged academics to make sense of his intentions. In Christine Buci-Glucksmann’s <em>Baroque Reason</em>, she argues that Benjamin’s dialectical-image revolved around a particular interest in modern femininity. She reads Benjamin’s fascination with strolling down the ‘spectacular’ arcades as an attempt to recuperate the <em>flaneur</em> sensibility of Charles Baudelaire—in whose poetry Glucksmann discovers an idealization of the lesbian and the prostitute. For Glucksmann, these antipodal figures allegorize the dialectic that interests Benjamin by “[their] potential for otherness and transgression” (Buci-Glucksmann, p. 109). The former represents the hero who defies the laws of modernity, while the latter represents the very image of modernity’s <em>lure</em> (Glucksmann, pp. 106-109).  Benjamin himself offers a blunt interpretation of this feminine transgression: he refers to it as death. And for him, nowhere are the living manifestations of death more prevalent than in women’s fashion:</p>
<p>&#8220;Fashion is the medium that ‘lures sex ever deeper into the inorganic world’—the ‘realm of dead things.’ It is ‘the dialectical switching station between woman and commodity—desire and dead body.’ The woman who adorns the newest fashions is nothing more than a ‘gaily decked-out corpse’&#8221; (Buck-Morss, p. 101).</p>
<p>Benjamin develops this idea by arguing that death is the very condition of society, and that the natural productivity of the female threatens society as such. He echoes Freud’s remark: “Woman is the greatest enemy of civilization.” In what seems a decadent reversal, woman’s supposed threat now functions so as to disseminate society’s newest fashions. Benjamin transfers Marx’s inorganic, fetish object onto the body of the living. Baudelaire’s prostitute epitomizes modernity and capitalism as the product who literally asks to be bought. Desire is no longer directed at an organic body but at the inorganic technology that produces what Benjamin calls a wish-image. The wish-image, in its dead-stillness, resonates with a utopic longing for a primal history, that is to say,</p>
<p>&#8220;In the dream in which every epoch sees in images the epoch that follows, the latter appears wedded to elements of ur-history, that is, of a classless society. Its experiences, which have their storage place in the unconscious of the collective, produce, in their interpenetration with the new, the utopia that has left its trace behind in a thousand configurations of life from permanent buildings to ephemeral fashions&#8221; (Benjamin quoted in Buck –Morss, p. 114).</p>
<p>The wish-image, however, is not yet the dialectical-image. The difference is not within the image itself: if fashion is the site of the dialectical-image, fashion is also the site of the wish-image. Benjamin’s dialectical-image thus earns its added dimension of <em>revolutionary</em> potential only after the perceiver of the image recognizes its lure by inferring the entire trajectory of the image.</p>
<p>One of the easiest ways to get lost in the <em>Arcades Project</em> is to forget that Benjamin intended to consummate his ideas through the use of images. The images themselves, juxtaposed in montage, could, ideally, activate<strong> </strong>the revolutionary potential that Benjamin continually aspired towards throughout his life. Thus, in order to understand Benjamin, it would seem impossible to think through his theory without considering it through an image. Given the importance of fashion and the centrality of women’s fashion, I want to study the phenomenon of cleavage as a baroque allegorical object, as a wish-image and as a possible site of dialectics.</p>
<p>The dialectical-image reveals the entire history of its production. One can look at the Eiffel Tower and recognize within it the workers who laid his or her hands on it, the architect who designed it, and the politician who thought it wise to construct it. However, it is not only the history of labor that is found in an image, the history of human perception is present as well. So it goes for cleavage, it is an example of an image manifested by a historical period (feminine liberation) and, as I will argue, by an advance in visual perception achieved in baroque art. Given cleavage’s pronounced implication as a visual phenomenon, I believe that cleavage functions as a central wish-image within Benjamin’s philosophy; not only because of its proliferation and mundane insistence, but also because the constructs of its visuality evoke the very possibility of vision (as understood by Merleau-Ponty), thereby offering us a transition from the advertisement of the wish-image to the revolutionary potential of the dialectical one.</p>
<p>Historically, cleavage plunges deeper than its ‘predecessor’ décolletage, a form of dress where a woman reveals the skin below her neckline. At its inception in the High Middle Ages décolletage was associated with prostitutes and women of loose morals (Williams, p. 48). The mistress of King Charles VII of France, Agnes Sorel, who earned the sobriquet <em>La Dame de Beauté</em>, is one of the earliest women renowned for her bosom, which she displayed in décolletage fashion. A woman of means and high-intelligence, the records and her portraits all confirm that her bosom was one of the essential features attracting King Charles (D’Orliac, p. 17).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-715" title="agnes-sorel" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/agnes-sorel.jpg" alt="" width="366" height="488" /></p>
<p>Here we see a contemporary portrait of Agnes that accentuates this famous bosom by revealing one breast and hiding another beneath a décolletage style. This is not yet cleavage. In fact the efficiency that cleavage provides is absent from this picture. We might also distinguish décolletage from cleavage by saying that a different mode of invisibility is at play. In the picture of Agnes Sorel the invisible, the other, breast lies hidden as if part of a story. Whereas with the depiction of cleavage, by hiding more, the image reveals a more immediate invisibility. What is of particular interest to me, visually, is how the baroque phenomenon of cleavage accomplishes its suggestive invisiblity by complicating the perspectival vision usually associated with Renaissance painting, in which, it is well known, the vanishing point in the center of each picture creates a seemingly 3-dimensional reality.  (For example, Leonardo’s <em>Mona Lisa</em> exhibits what we might call proto-cleavage, a tiny slit heralding the transition from décolletage style to cleavage [Fig. 2].)</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-717" title="mona-lisa" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/mona-lisa1.jpg" alt="" width="317" height="480" /></p>
<p>In <em>The Rhetoric of Perspective</em>: <em>Realism and Illusionism in Seventeenth-Century Dutch Still-Life Painting</em>, Hanneke Grootenboer looks at still life paintings from the Golden Age of Dutch art in order to demonstrate that the type of purity often presupposed by the invention of perspective is nothing more than a rhetorical device or an allegorical conception of sight. This latter notion returns us to Benjamin’s distinction between symbolism and allegory and directly refutes the art historian Erwin Panofsky who wrote <em>Perspective as Symbolic Form</em>. For Benjamin vision has a flaw, a decaying, ruin-like quality that renders the image’s form inadequate to its concept or idea. Grootenboer reiterates the allegorical (decaying) structure of vision by referring to Jacques Lacan, who tells us that there is always an absence in sight. ‘Perspective as symbolic form’ would ‘ideally’ manifest the complete equation between image and idea, whereas Lacan, staring directly at the vanishing point that makes perspective possible, sees the incompletion of vision as its very possibility. As Benjamin understands, “allegory is never saturated by meaning” (Benjamin quoted in Grootenboer, p. 136). So Grootenboer interprets the techniques of still life, baroque style <em>par excellence</em>, as paintings that confront and toy with the vanishing point; instead of hiding this point in the distance, still life paintings function to bring the viewer directly before it.</p>
<p>&#8220;The combination of a lack of depth and a lack of narrative with the extreme lifelikeness that we repeatedly see in these images raises the question whether these aspects mutually influence each other. The operation of perspective is obvious in pictorial scenes that stage a view into a landscape or an interior. It remains unclear, however, how perspective can be responsible for the lifelikness of relatively flat images such as these still lifes. The still lifes I investigate here deploy a rhetoric of perspective that enables scenes to emerge under a gaze that is not the gaze of a person. We, as viewers, do not look into a pictorial depth that offers itself to us, but rather the objects are pushed forward by their shallow space and actively confront our gaze&#8221; (Grootenboer, p. 32).</p>
<p>This last statement borrows its conceptual implications from Lacan’s renowned interpretation of the gaze from <em>The Four Fundamental Concepts of Pyschoanalysis</em> where Lacan tells a droll story about a can that gazes at a boy. Grootenboer understands the still life as a technique of perspective that confronts its own representational limitations, where the still life painter paints into the frame his or her own awareness of a picture’s ability to gaze back. The harmlessness and fantastical reality of a landscape painting, which places the vanishing point deep into the center of the frame, is frustrated by a work such as “Feigned Letter Rack Painting” by Samuel Van Hoogstraten where the image has a depth of only a couple inches (Fig. 3).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-718" title="still_li" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/still_li-500x373.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="373" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/still_li-500x373.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/12/still_li-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/12/still_li.jpg 1070w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Grootenboer argues that this technique turns the vanishing point’s potential inside out, so that whereas in Renaissance landscapes the vanishing point permits a view of a scene, in baroque still lifes the vanishing point comes forward to haunt the viewer.</p>
<p>As such, baroque art interrogates the nature of its own representation, so much so that Grootenboer believes that this interrogation mirrors Merleau-Ponty’s phenomenology of vision (Grootenboer, p. 47), that is to say, the baroque painter touches up against the canvas with the same bracketed query we find formalized in prose or philosophy. Merleau-Ponty thus argues what still lifes suggest: that depth is essential for making any object visible, and that visibility, any visibility, presents “an intertwining of vision and touch.” This latter logic brings cleavage back within our sights, as it leads Merleau-Ponty to equate depth with flesh (Grootenboer, p. 39).  “It is that the thickness of flesh between the seer and the thing is as constitutive for the thing’s visibility as for the seer’s corporeity; it is not an obstacle between them, it is their means of communication” (Merleau-Ponty quoted in Grootenboer, p. 39). To feel one’s vision is to be within a flesh that gives the presence of depth, thus the viewer, because his or her gaze places him or her inside the depth of the image, is also, aside from <em>being gazed at</em>, <em>being touched</em> by what is seen. The hyper-reality of still life is a style of painting that forces the viewer to confront this concept of vision. In contrast to the initial use of perspective, which created a breadth of distance that allowed for narrative and figure, baroque art subtracts these ideologies from the picture in order to direct our attention to the ideology of perspective itself. Now, the viewer must confront his or her own desire to see.</p>
<p>It is thus no surprise that one of the greatest baroque painters, Rembrandt, is one of the first painters to lushly depict a woman’s cleavage (See fig. 4).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-720" title="rembrandtvanrijn_portrait_of_hendrickje_stofells" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/rembrandtvanrijn_portrait_of_hendrickje_stofells1-425x500.jpg" alt="" width="425" height="500" /></p>
<p>In Heinrich Wollflin’s seminal work <em>Principles of Art History</em>, he situates the transition between Renaissance art and baroque art within five different principles. The first principle that Wollflinn provides to differentiate the two regimes of art is the move from the linear to the painterly. He annotates this move as follows: “Painterly. Volumes and outlines merge. Edges blur, creating a shifting or moving quality” (Minor, p. 29). The painterly technique of the baroque uses light and shade as a way to emphasize the tactility of each figure. Rembrandt, a consummate baroque master for Wolflinn, famously used the process of chiaroscuro to paint rich, directed light into each of his pictures. Rembrandt used thick strokes of dark paint and bright paint to invest figures in his painting with a tactile presence. In Rembrandt’s painting of Hendrickje Stoffels (Rembrandt’s housekeeper and most likely his mistress), this thick shade of black, which executes the technique of chiaroscuro, brings startling definition to Stoffels’ cleavage. Remembering Grootenboer’s argument above, we can now gaze at this space of cleavage in the same way Grootenboer gazes at still lifes. Here, with cleavage, we have a very shallow depth that conveys the very possibility of depth itself. The wall of flesh behind cleavage, the sternum, replaces the blank walls in still life paintings. And the protruding food, which once inspired Schopenhauer to denounce still lifes for being so realistic that they stirred his appetite, is replaced by the protrusion of flesh itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>Though flesh and depth sound ripe with meaning, it is hard to accept these notions blindly; in truth, to say depth is flesh is little more than a tautology. We must stop and ask: how does this depth create meaning? How does depth maintain or transmit its allegorical constitution? Gilles Deleuze helps us make some headway with these questions in his book <em>The Fold: Leibniz and the Baroque</em> when he writes,</p>
<p>&#8220;Inflection is the ideal genetic element of the variable curve or fold. Inflection is the authentic atom, the elastic point. That is what Klee extracts as the genetic element of the active, spontaneous line. For Klee…the point moves along an inflection. It is the point of inflection itself…&#8221; (Deleuze, p. 12).</p>
<p>Deleuze describes the visual experience of this inflected point or fold by comparing it to the ogive, or the pointed arch: “The ogive expresses the form of a moving body that espouses the configuration of lines of flowing liquid, and the return, the profile of the depth of a valley when waters are brought together following the line of a single course” (Deleuze, p. 16). Deleuze’s book includes a picture of a series of ogives that look surprisingly similarly to a series of breasts (Fig. 5).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-721" title="ogives" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/ogives-333x500.jpg" alt="" width="333" height="500" /></p>
<p>So I read the ogive as the “matheme” of cleavage, like the ogive it evokes a spontaneous line that inflects itself into <em>an infinity</em> of variable curvature, where a shadow, or “profile of the depth of a valley”, conveys the bending capacity of the line. Deleuze argues that the inflective or folding nature of the line creates two floors, two planes, which can be interpreted as the two effects any line has on a viewer. The first floor is the appearance, the lure, the immediate integration of the image—and it leads directly, in baroque architecture for example, to the transcendental plane of the second floor. A Church tempts the viewer into its walls, gazes down, pulls the viewer into its center, only to have the viewer look up at a dome that instills a feeling of otherness in such a way so as to carry the viewer out of the Church’s structure altogether. Cleavage, which possesses the same visual fold, mimics this process of the church.</p>
<p>The first psychoanalytic theorist of fashion, John Carl Flügel, tells us, “clothing is a compromise between the fear of, and the desire for, nudity” (Flugel quoted in Barthes, p. 26). Thus, instead of inflecting us towards God, cleavage inflects us towards the hidden plane of nudity. Given that cleavage is decidedly feminine, it not only conveys to the viewer an intimation of nudity but also transmits the transcendental otherness of feminine sexuality. This reveals, again, why the flesh and depth duality offered by Merleau-Ponty does not convey the whole picture. Flesh and depth lead outside of themselves towards an otherness beyond sight. We might hedge this critique, however, by noting that flesh and depth seem to be the most suggestive of that which is beyond sight, they are that which has the power to be perceived as flesh and depth. The perspective or <em>trompe l’oeil</em> of cleavage perfectly, in the sense of the Ancient <em>telos</em>, disorients its viewer.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>A sight of absence, cleavage constantly shifts between the presentation of a vertical line and a horizontal one. In this sense cleavage depicts the very illusion of the Renaissance perspective, where, technically, the painter used vertical lines to create the horizon. The trick of depth is the truth of depth and from this depth vision overflows with flesh. Depth is thus made possible by the inflection of the line, by the shadow, and finally by its inclusion of a bracketed absence. This little black line drawn between the two ogive formations is enough to lure almost any gaze in its direction, thereby encouraging the viewer to see or desire beyond the flesh. (Look at the deep black line in one of El Greco’s many depictions of Jesus’ chest [Fig. 6]).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-772" title="new greco" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/new-greco1-292x500.jpg" alt="" width="292" height="500" /></p>
<p>As we have already mentioned, the terminology <em>lure</em> and <em>being gazed at</em> originate from Merleau-Ponty’s friend Jaques Lacan, the foremost thinker of feminine alterity. If Merleau-Ponty introduces an immanent phenomenology of vision, and Deleuze introduces the manner in which vision pulls us beyond what we see, Lacan invests vision with the Freudian theory of libido. For Lacan, the vanishing point is the absence that makes vision possible just as the castrated phallus is the lack that makes sexuality possible. Lacan conflates these two ideas in his small section ‘On the Baroque’ in <em>Seminar XX: On Feminine Sexuality</em>. There he claims that Christianity has always been baroque, or that it consummated its vision in the baroque because it was always obsessed with the body, well&#8230; Christ’s body, which  is essential for disseminating the tenets of Christianity: it is through Christ’s body that the faithful achieve absolution. For Lacan, the importance of the body culminates in the obscenity of the baroque.  “… ‘baroquism’ with which I accept to be clothed—everything is exhibition of the body evoking <em>jouissance</em>.” (Lacan, p. 113) Lacan adds that there is no copulation taking place in the ‘orgy’ of churches in Italy. That is to say that these obscenities of the body refrain from consummation, they always remain incomplete, they never satisfy. Cleavage is constituted identically. There is no touching cleavage despite its visual capacity to evoke tactility. Cleavage also disappears in the act of consummation.</p>
<p>Though it would seem impossible to make a definitive statement about the allure of cleavage, it is indisputable that cleavage is situated within the modern psyche of sexuality and vision. If it is true that, “the other appears to hold the ‘truth of the subject and the power to make good its loss,” then cleavage exists halfway between the other and the viewer (the desirer). “In fashion, the phantasmagoria of commodities presses closest to the skin… Now clothing is quite literally at the borderline between subject and object, the individual and the cosmos” (Buck-Morss, p. 97). A close up of cleavage includes the flesh of the partially exposed breast and the brassiere or blouse that produces this ‘special’ effect. Like the staging of ghosts via light projections in baroque theater, with cleavage the technology that produces the effect is exposed, it becomes part of the excitement and titillation of the effect: as if the presentation of what fabricates desire makes the image even more desirous. The temptation of cleavage excites the viewer by blatantly exposing its trick. At last, in the deceptive bluntness of modern fashion and modern special effects, man no longer conjectures about what is behind the curtain. It is the mere fact that there is a curtain which excites modern man.</p>
<p>This distinction is important to Benjamin, who theorizes a metaphysical transition from the baroque allegory to the modern one. Baroque allegory, like the example above with the church, through its ruin or fragmentation (inflection), compels our gaze towards a second floor that evokes the absolution of God. Modern allegory, however, evokes a nihilistic spirituality. “Between <em>law</em> and <em>justice</em>, the theological metaphor embodies a critical-utopian distance, a different idea of politics which Benjamin, influenced by Nietzsche, calls ‘nihilist’” (Buci-Glucksmann, p. 66). This transition implies a complex dialectic between progression and stagnation. On the one hand, the proliferation of fashion democratizes allegory. It is no longer disseminated by some all-powerful king in order to captivate his citizens. Once the fashion of cleavage is accessible to all classes, every woman can now display the virtues of feminine liberation. On the other hand, “‘Fashion prescribed the ritual by which the fetish commodity wished to be worshipped’” (Benjamin quoted in Buck-Morss, p. 98). Such Liberation does not preclude the capacity for allegory, it merely transvaluated baroque metaphysics into nihilistic ritualism. It is here that the difference between the wish-image and the dialectical-image surfaces again.</p>
<p>As a wish-image, cleavage represents a ritual site of worship in Benjamin’s unique logic of commodity fetishism. “‘The souvenir is the relic secularized’… Thus allegory finally discovers all its depths of forgetting and being forgotten, its true destructive principle, its ‘most precious booty’: woman” (Buci-Glucksmann, pp. 77-78). If the dialectical potential of cleavage remains buried within it, then, cleavage, as a wish-image, reinforces the tenets of the ‘new religion’ that is commodity fetishism. However, if the <em>souvenir</em> of the forgotten is brought to the attention of thought, the construct of the allegory potentializes a revolutionary dialectic. (See opening quote about Proust above). This is Benjamin’s ultimate hope, and it is one that, to this day, remains incomplete. If a theoretical discussion of a wish-image, such as the one taken up in this essay, treats cleavage dialectically, as an image that informs the viewer both of its presence and of the forgotten history that actualizes its shocking value, it seems unlikely that such articulations have much impact on the general order of things. Since the advent of the Internet, cleavage has been distributed exorbitantly. It is secretly and blatantly (the dual logic of all special effects) used to advertise innumerable commodities, not to mention its proliferation on profile pages such as Facebook, where it advertises an individual (her)self.</p>
<p>Jacqueline Rose argues, reading Lacan, that the woman must look perfect to prevent the man from encountering his lack. Perfection demands stasis, it demands inorganicity. This echoes the frozen dialectic essential to Benjamin. We all know that breasts move, yet within modern brassieres, the cleavage line remains stagnant. This aligns the female body with the commodity, in that both project a freshness and imperturbability that defies the decaying nature of life. Baroque architecture is colloquially renowned for adding movement to the façade of a building; however, it is only by the juxtaposition against the stillness of deep, shaded lines that this movement appears. The flesh accentuated by the fading line of cleavage moves towards the viewer. By invading, projecting forth as a <em>gazing at</em> that lures subjects in, cleavage incites a secular spirituality. Vision itself becomes the rhetorical device through which the allegory of otherness protrudes; its folds pull us into a depth that compels a nearness to flesh that is never consummated.</p>
<p>In this sense, cleavage, today, is a mere object of desire that the woman dresses herself in. If cleavage is the signifier, its signified is sexual otherness. Like slacks or skirts, ‘<em>she</em> with the anatomical possession of breasts’ is able to dress <em>her</em>self in cleavage. Once cleavage is arbitrarily agreed upon as a site of sexuality, the complexity of its visual impact, and the excluded history of its production, no longer have any relevance. Cleavage, like other marks of sexual difference, influence the production of clichés such as: ‘men love cleavage’ or ‘women are essentially constituted to lure men to their bedside’. The technological developments of cleavage since the High Middle Ages are forgotten in the visual pleasure of cleavage.</p>
<p>However, because of the artificial qualities of cleavage’s allure, the logic of the dialectical-image asserts itself, striking a chord with feminist theory. That is not to say that cleavage should be banned. Any prescription prohibiting cleavage would only highlight the sexual difference cleavage produces. Treating cleavage as one of Benjamin’s dialectical-images allows us to perceive cleavage’s legacy, its <em>souvenir</em>.  Benjamin believed that writing could only activate the potential of revolution by maintaining a constant political register. By accomplishing this, the wish-image, the site of secular ritual, renounces its essentialism, entering the realm of speculative thought. The presumption that cleavage possesses a ‘genetic’ allure is proven false by the historical development of its possibility. In this sense both men and women are united again in the democracy of thought. On the other hand, abiding within the logic of the wish-image reasserts the lame duality of gender where man seeks to consume cleavage and woman seeks to provoke this consumption.</p>
<p>If baroque allegory was staged in Churches, in paintings, and in theater, modern allegory is found in the mundane. “‘We penetrate the mystery only to the degree that we recognize it in the everyday world, by virtue of a dialectical optic that perceives the everyday as impenetrable, the impenetrable as everyday’”  (Benjamin quoted in Buci-Glucksmann, p. 45). It is this acceptance of unfufillment that ruptures the insistent reproduction of the fetish object. “‘What is involved here is that the expectation roused by the look of the human eye is not fulfilled. Baudelaire describes eyes of which one is inclined to say that they have lost their ability to look’” (Benjamin quoted in<strong> </strong>Buci-Glucksmann, p. 75). Cleavage’s ‘primal past’ suggests the impossibility of vision, the impossibility of a consummate sight. Every subject is confronted with the chance to remove him or herself from the implication of desire’s alteration of self by seeing in plain vision the simultaneous lure and lack of sight.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>BIBLIOGRAPHY</strong></p>
<p>Barthes, Roland. <em>The Language of Fashion</em>, ed. Andy Stafford and Michael Carter, trans. Andy Stafford (Oxford: Berg, 2004).</p>
<p>Benjamin, Walter. <em>The Arcades Project</em>, trans. Howard Eiland and Kevin McLaughlin (London: The Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 2002).</p>
<p>Benjamin, Walter. <em>The Origin of German Tragic Drama</em>, trans. John Osborne (London: Lowe &amp; Brydone Printers Ltd., 1977).</p>
<p>Buck-Morss, Susan. <em>The Dialectics of Seeing: Walter Benjamin and the Arcades Project</em>. (London: The MIT Press, 1989).</p>
<p>Deleuze, Gilles. <em>The Fold: Leibniz and the Baroque</em>, trans. Tom Conley (Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 2007).</p>
<p>D’Orliac, Jehanne. <em>The Lady of Beauty</em>, trans. M.C. Darnton (London: J.B. Lippincott Company, 1931).</p>
<p>Grootenboer, Hanneke. <em>The Rhetoric of Perspective</em> (London: The University of Chicago Press, 2005).</p>
<p>Lacan, Jacques. <em>Seminar XX: On Feminine Sexuality, The Limits of Knowledge, 1972-1973</em>, ed. Jacques-Alain Miller, trans. Bruce Fink (London: W.W. Norton &amp; Company, 1998).</p>
<p>Minor, Vernon Hyde. <em>Baroque &amp; Rococo</em>. (London: King, 1999).</p>
<p>Rose, Jacqueline. <em>Sexuality in the Field of Vision</em>. (London: Verso, 1988).</p>
<p>Williams, Julia Lloyd. <em>Rembrandt’s Women</em> (Edinburgh: National Gallery of Scotland, 2001).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Appendix or an Example of Italian Baroque Cleavage:</em></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-778" title="caravaggio_img2" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/caravaggio_img2.jpg" alt="" width="448" height="328" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Gum&#8221; violence</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/gum-violence/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 22:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Costas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deleuze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guattari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Rosen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Night Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandy Hook Elementary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an op/ed titled “‘Gums’ control for Bob Costas,” a piece written prior to Friday&#8217;s mass shooting, sportscaster Mark Rosen criticized his better-known colleague for a segment aired on Monday Night Football following the Jovan Belcher murder-suicide in which Costas firmly asserted the necessity for gun control. “I read about, hear about, write about, talk about [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-614" title="Costas" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Costas3.jpg" alt="" width="341" height="255" /></p>
<p>In an <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/opinion/ci_22179264/rosen-gums-control-bob-costas">op/ed</a> titled “‘Gums’ control for Bob Costas,” a piece written prior to Friday&#8217;s mass shooting, sportscaster Mark Rosen criticized his better-known colleague for a segment aired on Monday Night Football following the Jovan Belcher murder-suicide in which Costas firmly asserted the necessity for gun control.<span id="more-602"></span></p>
<p>“I read about, hear about, write about, talk about and think about politics for much of my waking — and oft-times sleeping — hours,&#8221; wrote Rosen, &#8220;Sunday Night Football on NBC is a time to get away from that for me and 20 million other American viewers. It&#8217;s an NFL sanctuary. Sportscaster Bob Costas stirred a national controversy when he violated that sanctuary to comment on the suicide of Kansas City Chiefs linebacker Jovan Belcher&#8230;It was annoying and inappropriate.”</p>
<p>Mark Rosen is a part of the problem. His reference to Monday Night Football as a “sanctuary,” is not just &#8220;annoying and inappropriate,&#8221; it suggests the same consecrating attitude towards sports institutions that allowed the atrocities at Penn State to take place repeatedly over several decades without intervention. But there are broader and more troubling principles underpinning Mr. Rosen&#8217;s ire.</p>
<p>The notion that one is entitled to ritualized spaces of psychological isolation from unsettling “real world” events is deeply woven into the fabric of “ordinary,” socio-economically secure American life—indeed, it may well be the sine qua non of the ideology of the &#8220;ordinary&#8221; itself. This regime of entitlement, foundational to suburban existence, feeds a project of empathic divestment that greases the gears of the western war machine and its profiteers and figures centrally in the technocapitalist conspiracy to transform the children of the twenty-first century into affectively conditioned test subjects in a digital age Pavlovian laboratory. (The true eventuation of the &#8216;Becoming-Animal&#8217; misguidedly envisioned by Deleuze and Guattari, at the cusp of the personal computing era, as an emancipatory proposition is the subject subsisting permanently within the <em>intermezzo</em> of the technological apparatus.) It is only when such currents manifest themselves locally, as in the tragedy that occurred yesterday in Connecticut, that the cycle is momentarily interrupted before being re-subordinated to the spectatorial anesthetization that inevitably ensues in the wake of what are thereby rendered non-events.</p>
<p>If there is a cruel fortuity to the close succession of recent nationally visible gun tragedies perhaps it is in the conversation having finally directed itself, in acknowledgement of a long-disavowed repetition compulsion, to the mechanisms of temporalization that allow disavowal to continue unabated. In this sense, Costas demonstrated foresight and courage not for breaking out of the narrow definitions of what constitutes sports reporting, nor even for profaning the sanctity of a cherished American institution, but for reminding us, in the too-soon-ness of the moment, of our propensity for staying the same. Traumatic events are too-frequently assimilated by the neoliberal subject according to a sacralizing convention whose deleterious effects are felt from Newtown, Connecticut to East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Here’s Costas:</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="500" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/B1ijkccD9_8" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moloch rears its mangled head above Central Park</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Moloch! Moloch! Robot apartments! invisible suburbs! skeleton treasuries! blind capitals! demonic industries! spectral nations! invincible madhouses! granite cocks! monstrous bombs! They broke their backs lifting Moloch to Heaven! Pavements, trees, radios, tons! lifting the city to Heaven which exists and is everywhere about us! Call it Frankencrane. In the midst of Cyclone Sandy’s assault on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/image-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-299"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-299" title="image" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/image2-e1352155421512-375x500.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="500" /></a><br />
<em></em></p>
<p><em>Moloch! Moloch! Robot apartments! invisible suburbs! skeleton treasuries! blind capitals! demonic industries! spectral nations! invincible madhouses! granite cocks! monstrous bombs!<br />
</em></p>
<p><em>They broke their backs lifting Moloch to Heaven! Pavements, trees, radios, tons! lifting the city to Heaven which exists and is everywhere about us!</em></p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/image-4/" rel="attachment wp-att-297"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-297" title="image" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/image-e1352154579859-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>Call it Frankencrane.</p>
<p>In the midst of Cyclone Sandy’s assault on the Eastern Seaboard, a fifty-ton crane attached to the top of One57—a building slated to be the tallest  residential building in Manhattan—partially collapsed under the storm’s powerful winds. For several days it dangled precariously over 57<sup>th</sup> street<span id="more-296"></span>, forcing the city to close off and evacuate the surrounding area. It has since been tethered to the side of the building, allowing the street to re-open. Many residents, however, have yet to return to their apartments.</p>
<p>One57 was a monstrosity well before it became a source of imperilment to thousands. As the salesperson in this promotional video masquerading as an editorial brags, the building’s 90 stories dwarf anything in the nearby vicinity:</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="450" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YgtObfxp8U0" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>Viewed from Central Park, One57 towers above the buildings along Central Park South like a gigantic blue-green Pez dispenser dealing sugary square feet of prestige to the high priests of Moloch. What better symbol of the misguidedness of acquisitive desire and phallic pomposity than a mangled, detumescent appendage dangling from the thousand foot tall skyscraper’s penthouse?</p>
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="450" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/TH5uGItSLHc" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p>One57 stands nearly two-hundred and fifty feet taller than neighboring Carnegie Hall Tower, the building previously holding the distinction of being 57<sup>th</sup> street’s greatest offence to the New York City skyline. Based on a 1987 design by World Trade Center architect César Pelli, that building’s stuffy brick exterior and anachronistic details pay superficial homage to the <em>actually</em> load-bearing masonry of the venue it is named after. Carnegie Hall Tower’s sole purpose appears to be to nurture the Gilded Age nostalgia of millionaires witless enough to be lured by a building that advertises itself on its homepage as “A SYMBOL OF SUCCESS.”</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/screen-shot-2012-11-05-at-1-44-50-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-304"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-304" title="Screen shot 2012-11-05 at 1.44.50 PM" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Screen-shot-2012-11-05-at-1.44.50-PM-500x330.png" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>But while One57 has appropriate company in Carnegie Hall Tower, its loathsomeness far exceeds that of its smaller neighbor.  Multiplying the inflated market value of One57’s apartments (the most expensive of which are priced at around $100 million) by sheer architectural misguidedness, one comes out with a figure surpassed only by 15 CPW, the one building in town that could make its neighbor, Columbus Circle’s Trump Tower, the architectural centerpiece of <a href="http://collider.com/wp-content/uploads/tower-heist-movie-poster-hi-res-01.jpg">Hollywood’s repackaging of 99% discontent</a>, seem déclassé by comparison. Dubbed “Jesus in Limestone” by real estate insiders, 15CPW (foreground below) was designed by architect Robert A.M. Stern.</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/image-5/" rel="attachment wp-att-298"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-298" title="image" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/image1-e1352160120612-375x500.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/image1-e1352160120612-375x500.jpg 375w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/11/image1-e1352160120612-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></a></p>
<p>A shameless peddler of suburban taste for urban dwellers, Stern is known for contributing to the Disneyfication of Times Square, blighting a number of street corners in uptown Manhattan, and serving as the head of the Yale Architecture school, where he has garnered a reputation for discouraging thought that conflicts with his own traditionalist leanings. Having designed the master plan for Disney’s <a href="http://www.celebration.fl.us/">Celebration</a> village, Stern was an obvious choice for lead architect of the first library for an illiterate president: the George W. Bush Presidential Library and Museum at Southern Methodist University in Dallas. Situated at the edge of a major freeway and across from a strip mall, the project promises to be yet another multi-hundred million dollar architectural turd in the manure cart that is Stern’s resume. <a href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/culturemonster/2009/11/no-bravado-as-plans-for-bush-presidential-library-are-unveiled.html">Here</a> is the LATimes reviewing Stern’s plans and finding them failing to measure up even to the exceedingly low standard set by Dubya himself.</p>
<p>Astonishingly, unlike 15CPW, One57 was designed by an architect not only of actual talent but of what might once have appeared to be conscience. Christian de Portzamparc, the first French recipient of the <a href="http://www.pritzkerprize.com/">Pritzker Architecture Prize</a>, professes a longstanding commitment to conscientious urbanism and to honoring the interrelation between ethical and aesthetic practices. His <a href="http://www.chdeportzamparc.com/content.asp?LANGUEID=2">website</a> makes proud mention of research carried out during the 1960s on “the social aspirations and quality of life in the large scale urban developments of that era” while highlighting his track record for projects that are “woven into the urban fabric, transforming a site rather than denaturing it.” Nothing could be further from the case when it comes to One57, which has not only denatured but also depopulated its surroundings within a five block radius. What is more, the building flagrantly violates any notion of aesthetics as an “ethically conditioned” realm.</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/portzamparc/" rel="attachment wp-att-305"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-305" title="portzamparc" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/portzamparc.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="296" /></a></p>
<p><em>“CdP is concerned with research, he avoids pure speculation. For him, architecture Is concerned with the quality of life. Within this realm, aesthetics themselves are conditioned by ethics, and he maintains that we have too often dissociated one from the other.” </em></p>
<p><em>–The website of &#8216;Starchitect,&#8217; Christian de Portzamparc </em></p>
<p>The developer behind One57 is diamond-merchant-turned-developer, Gary Barnett. As numerous recent articles have attested, Barnett epitomizes the greed and fecklessness of high end New York real estate, an industry that comes closer, with each passing year, to rendering the city unlivable for everyone but the super-wealthy. Extell, the company that Barnett heads, has been accused of a wide range of immoral practices, including <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/randalllane/2012/11/01/inside-extell-the-immoral-developer-behind-hurricane-sandys-dangling-crane/2/">“tak[ing] food from the mouths” of orphans of 9/11</a> in their efforts to sell multimillion dollar condos.</p>
<p>Exemplifying the worst aspects of 1% privilege, Extell has tried to use a shady loophole to garner tax-breaks that would give wealthy buyers an incentive to invest in One57’s outrageously priced condominiums. As NBC News has <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/business/billionaires-get-low-income-tax-breaks-nyc-condo-tower-1C6403983?streamSlug=businessmain">reported</a>, this would mean that owners of 90 million dollar properties could pay as little as 18,400 dollars a years (instead of the normal 200,000+) in taxes on their apartments. That’s 180,000+ dollars per owner <em>not </em>going to things like schools, health, infrastructure, and the massive cleanup that Cyclone Sandy will undoubtedly necessitate. These tax breaks are normally extended to developers who commit to providing low-income housing. The loophole allows developers to benefit from the tax incentives offered to millionaires on 57<sup>th</sup> street while fulfilling their obligation to the low-income housing stipulation by erecting buildings in the Bronx.</p>
<p>With Cyclone Sandy drowning low-lying parts of Manhattan and turning the island into a tale of two cities—a metropolis starkly divided between the uptown “haves” and the downtown “have-nots”—many New Yorkers, including those of considerable privilege, had a chance to reflect on what it means to live without the basic amenities they ordinarily take for granted. It is unconscionable that close to 50,000 people (a third of them children) should be living in homeless shelters while the super-wealthy—many of whom primarily reside overseas—benefit from tax loopholes and drain the city of its lifeblood.</p>
<p>Halfhearted applause for Mayor Bloomberg breaking ranks with the free market Mitt-ology of his billionaire peers in supporting “that one.” But before New York is completely suffocated under shiny prefab façades, what the city really needs is a representative of the Rent is Too Damn High party.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="450" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/x4o-TeMHys0" frameborder="0"></iframe><br />
The endgame of the New York real-estate race is a metropolis stripped not just of everyone but rich people, but of all the things that make any town an appealing place to live in the first place. As it stands, astronomical New York rent prices have already deprived downtown of its last great <a href="http://www.stmarksbookshop.com/">bookstore</a>, which now hobbles on—at least for as long as its lease-extension holds—a shadow of its former self. It is possible that some of the hardest hit galleries in Chelsea, a neighborhood basking for years in the crepuscular light of cultural decadence, will be forced to close in the wake of Sandy if not in the wake of their 10 year leases. They doubtless won’t be those that make ends meet several times over hawking the second-tier works of certified blue chip artists from the last century. It is a cruel irony that the <a href="http://www.zachfeuer.com/">gallery</a> that appears to have suffered some of the worst devastation at the hands of Sandy recently mounted a show whose message to Chelsea and everything it represents was essentially: I hope you drown in your own sewage. The artist’s name? <a href="http://www.zachfeuer.com/artists/mark-flood/">Flood</a>.</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/mf_endlesscolumn12_194x49_s/" rel="attachment wp-att-310"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-310" title="MF_EndlessColumn12_194x49_s" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/MF_EndlessColumn12_194x49_s-395x500.jpg" alt="" width="395" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>New York in the 21<sup>st</sup> century is a place where the cops blockade the parks at midnight and the seemingly most principled members of the cultural elite sell their souls to satanic real estate moguls. An air-conditioned nightmare for the privileged few, a miserable toilet for the rest. Literally or figuratively, sooner or later, everything becomes a Starbucks.</p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/starbucks/" rel="attachment wp-att-311"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-311" title="starbucks" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/starbucks-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><em>What sphinx of cement and aluminium bashed open their skulls and ate up their brains and imagination?</em></p>
<p><em>Moloch! Solitude! Filth! Ugliness! Ashcans and unobtainable dollars! Children screaming under the stairways! Boys sobbing in armies! Old men weeping in the parks!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Moloch! Moloch! Nightmare of Moloch! Moloch the loveless! Mental Moloch! Moloch the heavy judger of men!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Moloch the incomprehensible prison! Moloch the crossbone soulless jailhouse and Congress of sorrows! Moloch whose buildings are judgement! Moloch the vast stone of war! Moloch the stunned governments!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Moloch whose mind is pure machinery! Moloch whose blood is running money! Moloch whose fingers are ten armies! Moloch whose breast is a cannibal dynamo! Moloch whose ear is a smoking tomb!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Moloch whose eyes are a thousand blind windows! Moloch whose skyscrapers stand in the long streets like endless Jehovas! Moloch whose factories dream and choke in the fog! Moloch whose smokestacks and antennae crown the cities!</em></p>
<p><em>Moloch whose love is endless oil and stone! Moloch whose soul is electricity and banks! Moloch whose poverty is the specter of genius! Moloch whose fate is a cloud of sexless hydrogen! Moloch whose name is the Mind!</em></p>
<p><a href="/anti-orpheus/moloch-rears-its-mangled-head-above-central-park/photo-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-400"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-400" title="photo-7" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/photo-7-500x375.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/photo-7-500x375.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/11/photo-7-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Obey</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/lindsay/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 23:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moloch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[http://www.gagosian.com/exhibitions/richard-phillips--september-11-2012]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=93</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.gagosian.com/exhibitions&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-218" title="photo (5)" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/photo-52-500x375.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/photo-52-500x375.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/10/photo-52-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><a href="http://www.gagosian.com/exhibitions/richard-phillips--september-11-2012" target="_blank">http://www.gagosian.com/exhibitions&#8230;</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
