<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: The Trouble with Resolutions</title>
	<atom:link href="/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: H.B.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/#comment-69</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 02:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=784#comment-69</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#039;s the wrong time and the wrong place - who makes New Year&#039;s resolutions? Everyone else. Who saw this post in time? Not I. Maybe I&#039;ll make a resolution some other year. 
Maybe the occasion is the result of an economy of restriction - isn&#039;t it an individualized, economized categorical imperative? If I had my Jewish way I&#039;d resolve every second of the day - but a Greek would also recognize the curse of hope (if points repeat their protest in the face of punctuation, projected lines do not fare better in the face of being drawn)

Speaking of bad habits: are they bad habits in the sense of being bad at being &#039;habits&#039; (inconsistent; unreliable), or that they are habits having something like a bad value/content? Neither fall exactly under &quot;commitment&quot; for their twisted ontological structure: the latter keeps repeating a value-judgment in the &quot;fetishistic disavowal&quot; of the act itself (to act according-to symptomatizes this fetish); the former keeps (a) failing repetition, hurling its-self towards its ontological criterion but only rarely making it across. 
They both share in the duplicitous chicaneries of the &quot;something else&quot; - &quot;To forgo is to allow exhaust to dissipate while doing something else&quot; - or something other. For it is this other that repeats, the other that is repeated.
What Deleuze calls &quot;difference without concept&quot; is itself a bad habit, in both the above senses. It repeats its failure to be; it arouses neglect and harsh judgment (also, but not exclusively, as the &quot;trivial&quot;): it is itself the flaring up of (an avowed) repetition whose fetishized identity disavows it after the (f)act

This post reminds me of a poem by the israeli poet David Avidan (I hurriedly translate it here from Hebrew):

The Moment Before / David Avidan
This liminality between
a leap and free-fall is
the most terrible, and precisely because
you know - who else but you would know -
as you&#039;ve already made a point in mentioning, on
some other occasion, that
there isn&#039;t, there is no power that would halt
this final, most decisive of your leaps. And yet
this liminality is all the more terrible for -
you do not know, but guess,
you do not guess, but hope,
you do not
hope, but guess, you
do not guess, but know that -
there is,
there is a power that will halt your final leap,
and this power is none other than your final leap.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s the wrong time and the wrong place &#8211; who makes New Year&#8217;s resolutions? Everyone else. Who saw this post in time? Not I. Maybe I&#8217;ll make a resolution some other year.<br />
Maybe the occasion is the result of an economy of restriction &#8211; isn&#8217;t it an individualized, economized categorical imperative? If I had my Jewish way I&#8217;d resolve every second of the day &#8211; but a Greek would also recognize the curse of hope (if points repeat their protest in the face of punctuation, projected lines do not fare better in the face of being drawn)</p>
<p>Speaking of bad habits: are they bad habits in the sense of being bad at being &#8216;habits&#8217; (inconsistent; unreliable), or that they are habits having something like a bad value/content? Neither fall exactly under &#8220;commitment&#8221; for their twisted ontological structure: the latter keeps repeating a value-judgment in the &#8220;fetishistic disavowal&#8221; of the act itself (to act according-to symptomatizes this fetish); the former keeps (a) failing repetition, hurling its-self towards its ontological criterion but only rarely making it across.<br />
They both share in the duplicitous chicaneries of the &#8220;something else&#8221; &#8211; &#8220;To forgo is to allow exhaust to dissipate while doing something else&#8221; &#8211; or something other. For it is this other that repeats, the other that is repeated.<br />
What Deleuze calls &#8220;difference without concept&#8221; is itself a bad habit, in both the above senses. It repeats its failure to be; it arouses neglect and harsh judgment (also, but not exclusively, as the &#8220;trivial&#8221;): it is itself the flaring up of (an avowed) repetition whose fetishized identity disavows it after the (f)act</p>
<p>This post reminds me of a poem by the israeli poet David Avidan (I hurriedly translate it here from Hebrew):</p>
<p>The Moment Before / David Avidan<br />
This liminality between<br />
a leap and free-fall is<br />
the most terrible, and precisely because<br />
you know &#8211; who else but you would know &#8211;<br />
as you&#8217;ve already made a point in mentioning, on<br />
some other occasion, that<br />
there isn&#8217;t, there is no power that would halt<br />
this final, most decisive of your leaps. And yet<br />
this liminality is all the more terrible for &#8211;<br />
you do not know, but guess,<br />
you do not guess, but hope,<br />
you do not<br />
hope, but guess, you<br />
do not guess, but know that &#8211;<br />
there is,<br />
there is a power that will halt your final leap,<br />
and this power is none other than your final leap.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Anti-Orpheus</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/#comment-36</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anti-Orpheus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=784#comment-36</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GET ORGANIZED.
http://www.openculture.com/2012/12/the_top_10_new_years_resolutions_with_bob_dylan.html]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>GET ORGANIZED.<br />
<a href="http://www.openculture.com/2012/12/the_top_10_new_years_resolutions_with_bob_dylan.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.openculture.com/2012/12/the_top_10_new_years_resolutions_with_bob_dylan.html</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Anti-Orpheus</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-trouble-with-resolutions/#comment-35</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anti-Orpheus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=784#comment-35</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&quot;On the inside cover, Mr. Delchef had written the word for hope. Bird intended to look up forbearance.&quot; -Kenzaburo Oe, A Personal Matter]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;On the inside cover, Mr. Delchef had written the word for hope. Bird intended to look up forbearance.&#8221; -Kenzaburo Oe, A Personal Matter</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
