<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Quotations &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/quotations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Guess who&#8230;</title>
		<link>/j-r/guess-who/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 21:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1405</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I am utterly disturbing, and I create only perplexity.&#8221;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;I am utterly disturbing, and I create only perplexity.&#8221;Note: There is a poll embedded within this post, please visit the site to participate in this post's poll.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>take my honey</title>
		<link>/j-r/take-my-honey/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 02:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1397</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Behold! I am weary of my wisdom, like the bee, which has gathered too much honey; I need hands which stretch outwards. [Siehe! Ich bin meiner Weisheit überdrüssig, wie die Biene, die des Honigs zu viel gesammelt hat, ich bedarf der Hände, die sich ausstrecken.]&#8221; &#8211; Nietzsche (Part 1 of Thus Spoke Zarathustra)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Behold! I am weary of my wisdom, like the bee, which has gathered too much honey; I need hands which stretch outwards. [Siehe! Ich bin meiner Weisheit überdrüssig, wie die Biene, die des Honigs zu viel gesammelt hat, ich bedarf der Hände, die sich ausstrecken.]&#8221; &#8211; Nietzsche (Part 1 of <em>Thus Spoke Zarathustra</em>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>honey of your words</title>
		<link>/j-r/honey-of-your-words/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 17:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1298</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;O You, Who came upon me once Stretched under apple-trees just after bathing, Why did you not strangle me before speaking Rather than fill me with the wild white honey of your words And then leave me to the mercy Of the forest bees.&#8221; — Amy Lowell, &#8220;Carrefour&#8221;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;O You,<br /> Who came upon me once<br /> Stretched under apple-trees just after bathing,<br /> Why did you not strangle me before speaking<br /> Rather than fill me<br /> with the wild white honey of your words<br /> And then leave me to the mercy<br /> Of the forest bees.&#8221;</p>
<p>—</p>
<p><strong>Amy Lowell,</strong> &#8220;Carrefour&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oliver Sacks&#8217; Hexagons of the Mind</title>
		<link>/peaty/oliver-sacks-hexagons-of-the-mind/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 01:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Peaty]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Etch-A-Sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=828</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Perhaps such experiences [ hallucinatory forms ] are at the root of our human obsession with pattern and the fact that geometrical patterns find their way into our decorative arts. As a child, I was fascinated by the patterns in our house&#8211;the square colored floor tiles on the front porch, the small hexagonal ones in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Perhaps such experiences [ hallucinatory forms ] are at the root of our human obsession with pattern and the fact that geometrical patterns find their way into our decorative arts. As a child, I was fascinated by the patterns in our house&#8211;the square colored floor tiles on the front porch, the small hexagonal ones in the kitchen&#8230;These geometric and scrolling motifs seemed somehow familiar to me, though it did not dawn on me until years later that this was because I had seen them in my own head, that these patterns resonated with my own inner experience of the intricate tilings and swirls of migraine&#8230;Do the arabesques and hexagons in our own minds, built into our brain organization, provide us with our first intimations of formal beauty? There is an increasing feeling among neuroscientists that self-organizing activity in vast populations of visual neurons is a prerequisite of visual perception&#8211;this is how seeing begins.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8211; Oliver Sacks (from &#8220;Hallucinations&#8221;)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bees Don&#8217;t Labor</title>
		<link>/j-r/bees-dont-labor/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 23:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;We presuppose labour in a form that stamps it as exclusively human. A spider conducts operations that resemble those of a weaver, and a bee puts to shame many an architect in the construction of her cells. But what distinguishes the worst architect from the best of bees is this, that the architect raises his [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;We presuppose labour in a form that stamps it as exclusively human. A spider conducts operations that resemble those of a weaver, and a bee puts to shame many an architect in the construction of her cells. But what distinguishes the worst architect from the best of bees is this, that the architect raises his structure in imagination before he erects it in reality.&#8221;</p>
<p>Marx, Karl,  <em>Capital</em> (Kindle Locations 2918-2920).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strangely Ordinary</title>
		<link>/anti-orpheus/strangely-ordinary/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 01:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anti-orpheus]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a prelude to a discussion about &#8220;the ordinary&#8221; in its various guises i.e. (1) its illusory manifestation as a privileged space impermeable to the threatening uncanny of &#8220;real world&#8221; politics; (2) as the radical ordinary reclaimed from the seeming greyscale of the neoliberal West and its culture industry: &#8220;Themes of &#8220;wonder&#8221; and the &#8220;marvel [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a prelude to a discussion about &#8220;the ordinary&#8221; in its various guises i.e. (1) its <a title="“Gum” violence" href="/anti-orpheus/gum-violence/">illusory manifestation</a> as a privileged space impermeable to the threatening uncanny of &#8220;real world&#8221; politics; (2) as the <a title="La politique de l’autruche" href="/le-manque/la-politique-de-lautruche-2/">radical ordinary</a> reclaimed from the seeming greyscale of the neoliberal West and its culture industry:</p>
<p>&#8220;Themes of &#8220;wonder&#8221; and the &#8220;marvel of Being&#8221; are suspect if they refer to an ecstatic mysticism that pretends to escape the world. The theme of scientific curiosity is no less suspect if it boils down to a collector&#8217;s preoccupation with rarities. In both cases, desire for the exception presupposes disdain for the ordinary.<span id="more-691"></span> Hegel was un-­ doubtedly the first to have this properly modern consciousness of the violent paradox of a thinking whose own value is as yet un-­ heard of, and whose domain is the grayness of the world. This or-­ dinary grayness, the insignificance of the everyday—which the Heideggerian &#8220;one&#8221; still bears the mark of—assumes an absent, lost, or far away &#8220;grandeur.&#8221; Yet, truth can be nothing if not the truth of being in totality, that is, the totality of its &#8220;ordinariness,&#8221;just as meaning can only be right at <em>[à même] </em>existence and no-­ where else. The modern world asks that this truth be thought: that meaning is right at. It is in the indefinite plurality of origins and their coexistence. The &#8220;ordinary&#8221; is always exceptional, however little we understand its character as origin. What we receive most communally as &#8220;strange&#8221; is that the ordinary itself is originary. W i t h existence laid open in this way and the meaning of the world being what it is, the exception is the rule. (Is this not the testimony of the arts and literature? Is not the first and only purpose of their strange existence the presentation of this strangeness? After all, in the etymology of the word <em>bizarre)</em><em>1 </em>whether the word comes from Basque or Arabic, there is a sense ofvalor, commanding presence, and elegance.)&#8221;</p>
<p>Jean-Luc Nancy, <em>Being Singular Plural,</em> trans. Robert D. Richardson and Anne E. O&#8217;Byrne (Stanford: Stanford UP, 2000), 10.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guns also kill people</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/</link>
		<comments>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 15:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[metaphysicalvillain]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Adorno: &#8220;Technology is making gestures precise and brutal, and with them men. It expels from movement all hesitation, deliberation, civility [&#8230;] which driver is not tempted, merely by the power of his engine, to wipe out the vermin of the street, pedestrians, children and cyclists?&#8221; (Minima Moralia, p. 40) And man-with-gun is a totally different [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adorno: &#8220;Technology is making gestures precise and brutal, and with them men. It expels from movement all hesitation, deliberation, civility [&#8230;] which driver is not tempted, merely by the power of his engine, to wipe out the vermin of the street, pedestrians, children and cyclists?&#8221; (<em>Minima Moralia</em>, p. 40)</p>
<p>And man-with-gun is a totally different beast than man-without.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Franz Kafka, &#8220;Josephine the Singer, or the Mouse Folk&#8221;</title>
		<link>/j-r/from-franz-kafka-josephine-the-singer-or-the-mouse-folk/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 17:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wanted to set the scene briefly. In this short story, Kafka (the narrator Kafka) describes a village of mice folk who all work very hard and &#8216;pipe&#8217; while they work. Josephine is the exception in this community because she sings when she pipes, she has a beautiful voice, though it is not always so clear [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to set the scene briefly. In this short story, Kafka (the narrator Kafka) describes a village of mice folk who all work very hard and &#8216;pipe&#8217; while they work. Josephine is the exception in this community because she sings when she pipes, she has a beautiful voice, though it is not always so clear why. <span id="more-290"></span> In this passage, Josephine has started &#8220;petitioning&#8221; &#8220;for exemption from all daily work&#8221;, a request that the community constantly refuses, doing so however with a &#8220;paternal&#8221; anxiety for their beloved songstress.</p>
<p>&#8220;Suppose that instead of the people one had an individual to deal with: one might imagine that this man had been giving in to Josephine all the time while nursing a wild desire to put an end to his submissiveness one fine day; that he had made superhuman sacrifices for Josephine in the firm belief that there was a natural limit to his capacity for sacrifice; yes, that he had sacrificed more than was needful merely to hasten the process, merely to spoil Josephine and encourage her to ask for more and more until she did indeed reach the limit with this last petition of hers; and that he then cut her off with a final refusal which was curt because long held in reserve.&#8221;</p>
<p>Franz Kafka, <em>The Complete Stories</em>, ed. Nahum N. Glazer (New York: Schocken Books, 1971), p. 373.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
