<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Working Title &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/working-title/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>On Hated Words (an excerpt)</title>
		<link>/s-w-k-c/on-hated-words/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 18:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[S.W.K.C.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Working Title]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1330</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The following is excerpted from the story of a young girl detective, one Clovis Cassidy, who&#8217;s primary jurisdiction lies in crimes of neglect. When a classmate goes missing, unnoticed, in a small town where baby food is the major source of employment, Cassidy is on the case. Mysterious and bizarre elements surround the young girl&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is excerpted from the story of a young girl detective, one Clovis Cassidy, who&#8217;s primary jurisdiction lies in crimes of neglect. When a classmate goes missing, unnoticed, in a small town where baby food is the major source of employment, Cassidy is on the case. Mysterious and bizarre elements surround the young girl&#8217;s disappearance, including a feral family who&#8217;s only order of the day appears to be chaos, a patriarch obsessed with all things Shakespearian, and a curious Lazyboy recliner that may well just be the source of the crime. Not your-regular-Bobsi Twin, not you average-Nancy-come lately-Drew, Cassidy is hard on the trail. Nevertheless one must ask, how will Clovis Cassidy, kid detective, get herself out of this pickle?</em></p>
<p>Precocious. (adj) As in her mother&#8217;s thumb, from which she saw it sucked out, greedily. Pulling the marrow of the word between the teeth. You precocious little bitch, she said (after what kind of incident/accident?). Uttered with foreboding and double meaning by her mother, later a schoolteacher, then a relative, or a stranger; used indiscriminately to describe her behavior, her vocabulary, her manner of dress, her intellect at large. As if the simple addition of a C and an O could occupy a word, like a squatter, forging the former residence into a halfway home. Steal between the letters, post-date itself, wipe out its precious (as in valued/as in affected) existence. <span id="more-1330"></span> Webster’s Eleventh called it one thing, though her mother, who&#8211;had the natural inclination or ability or skill to graft to any leafy stalk a measure of ugliness&#8211;rendered it another way (she would say that she did it to reveal their duplicity, their underlying depravity). From that stalk it grew, a strange bud of three leaves, book-ended on either side by the relevant parts of the word precious, then, outgrowing its pot, it made a desperate crack in the enamel.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Precarious. (adj) An O and a C to an A and a R. As in, when she speaks it, she spells it. Lights up the whole stupid floor of your mouth, her horse-faced sister had accused her. An organization of palate, tongue, molars. A clacking shift in structure that repeats itself (did I repeat myself?, her sister says), haggling over wet space, sliding along side itself to form the word. She would run her mouth, feed the back of her teeth with the tip of her tongue. Constantly sizing up, sussing out,  the bit of space, that tiny median that prevented her incisors from severing her own tongue. Collocation (noun): the act or result of placing or arranging together; specifically: a noticeable conjoining of linguistic elements. Impossible to not speak in tongues.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Precipice. (noun) A hazardous situation. As in, the thing stuck out in such a fashion that it appeared to be sutured to her face by a hairline scar, running just under the lip, binding the whole encasement like a sausage, encasing the entire mouth, disabling articulation. Restriction of a small mouth. When she spoke slowly (excavating) she would suck, tooth and nail, bitterly expelling the hated word. When she spoke quickly, all her words struggled up against an impossible doorway, knocking one another about, losing passageway in the tumble. Or, if they did break through they would acquire oblong shapes, rounded parcels of tone, as if the navigation from the tonsil, to the teeth, to the tepid ear, had shorn off their edges. As she walks, she wobbles.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Precast. (adj) A predisposition to a dogged mouth. The unfailing symptom being an overemphasized philtrum that spreads out into a hang-dog expression. Also, as in dental caps. A nocturnal grinding that would lock the jaw and capsize golden fillers. It would wake her when she choked on them, struggling to dislodge the inverse, until she would finally huff it up onto her pillow. The slippery stone means a gold mine; similar to what she imagined the tooth fairy had in store for her. Her mother, in turn, seized the booty and kept it stowed and hidden for all future accidental deaths/disappearances, a predilection for parsing, a knack for carbon dating.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Parsimony. (noun) The quality or state of being stingy. To become miserly with one&#8217;s actions/words, a disavowal of language, a sleight of hand, a vow of silence, a preemptive strike. As in her penurious identity, her ever-increasing thrift or frugality of &#8216;self&#8217;.</p>
<p>Precocial. (adj) As in certain ducklings with an almost prenatal set of survival skills, but not necessarily applicable to all birds. Some birds; antonymic to altricial; bow-break like saplings do; chicks hatched helpless and carried away quick by the talons of predators. (Definition of carrion (noun): dead and putrefying flesh; also: flesh unfit for food). Born weak, they skirt responsibility. Others, are supposedly born from the branch, ready to fly. This is not the case with human boys and girls who, born helpless, are severed at the meaningful cord; then, incubated in halogen, hot water and hospital detergent. All human children were supposed to be born with the very same infirmary. So wouldn&#8217;t that make a precocious child, in a manner of speaking, an impossibility? And, if yes. Could this impossibility make the very same precocious child disappear completely?</p>
<p>Prelapsarian. (adj) Belonging to or relating to a previous state of innocence. What a ridiculous notion! Having already arrived, one cannot move, with eyes facing forward, back again. As in, chess pieces gliding deftly across the chessboard. As in her sleeping mother, eyelids fluttering, murmuring a desire to be born again.<b id="docs-internal-guid-5f3f342c-f306-aa3b-68d1-d587c63c50f9"> </b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Become King (an excerpt)</title>
		<link>/s-w-k-c/how-to-become-king/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 17:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[S.W.K.C.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Working Title]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The following is excerpted from the story of a young girl detective, one Clovis Cassidy, who&#8217;s primary jurisdiction lies in crimes of neglect. When a classmate goes missing, unnoticed, in a small town where baby food is the major source of employment, Cassidy is on the case. Mysterious and bizarre elements surround the young girl&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!--
/* Font Definitions */ @font-face 	{font-family:Times-Roman; 	panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0; 	mso-font-alt:Times; 	mso-font-charset:77; 	mso-generic-font-family:roman; 	mso-font-format:other; 	mso-font-pitch:auto; 	mso-font-signature:3 0 0 0 1 0;} @font-face 	{font-family:TimesNewRomanPSMT; 	panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0; 	mso-font-alt:"Times New Roman"; 	mso-font-charset:77; 	mso-generic-font-family:roman; 	mso-font-format:other; 	mso-font-pitch:auto; 	mso-font-signature:3 0 0 0 1 0;}  /* Style Definitions */ p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal 	{mso-style-priority:99; 	mso-style-unhide:no; 	mso-style-qformat:yes; 	mso-style-parent:""; 	margin:0in; 	margin-bottom:.0001pt; 	mso-pagination:widow-orphan; 	mso-layout-grid-align:none; 	text-autospace:none; 	font-size:12.0pt; 	font-family:"Times-Roman","serif"; 	mso-fareast-font-family:"Times New Roman"; 	mso-bidi-font-family:Times-Roman;} p.MsoHeader, li.MsoHeader, div.MsoHeader 	{mso-style-priority:99; 	mso-style-unhide:no; 	mso-style-link:"Header Char"; 	margin:0in; 	margin-bottom:.0001pt; 	mso-pagination:widow-orphan; 	mso-layout-grid-align:none; 	text-autospace:none; 	font-size:12.0pt; 	font-family:"Times-Roman","serif"; 	mso-fareast-font-family:"Times New Roman"; 	mso-bidi-font-family:Times-Roman;} p.MsoFooter, li.MsoFooter, div.MsoFooter 	{mso-style-priority:99; 	mso-style-unhide:no; 	mso-style-link:"Footer Char"; 	margin:0in; 	margin-bottom:.0001pt; 	mso-pagination:widow-orphan; 	mso-layout-grid-align:none; 	text-autospace:none; 	font-size:12.0pt; 	font-family:"Times-Roman","serif"; 	mso-fareast-font-family:"Times New Roman"; 	mso-bidi-font-family:Times-Roman;} span.HeaderChar 	{mso-style-name:"Header Char"; 	mso-style-priority:99; 	mso-style-unhide:no; 	mso-style-locked:yes; 	mso-style-link:Header; 	mso-ansi-font-size:12.0pt; 	mso-bidi-font-size:12.0pt; 	font-family:"Times-Roman","serif"; 	mso-ascii-font-family:Times-Roman; 	mso-hansi-font-family:Times-Roman; 	mso-bidi-font-family:Times-Roman;} span.FooterChar 	{mso-style-name:"Footer Char"; 	mso-style-priority:99; 	mso-style-unhide:no; 	mso-style-locked:yes; 	mso-style-link:Footer; 	mso-ansi-font-size:12.0pt; 	mso-bidi-font-size:12.0pt; 	font-family:"Times-Roman","serif"; 	mso-ascii-font-family:Times-Roman; 	mso-hansi-font-family:Times-Roman; 	mso-bidi-font-family:Times-Roman;} .MsoChpDefault 	{mso-style-type:export-only; 	mso-default-props:yes; 	font-size:10.0pt; 	mso-ansi-font-size:10.0pt; 	mso-bidi-font-size:10.0pt;} @page WordSection1 	{size:595.0pt 842.0pt; 	margin:1.25in 1.0in 1.25in 1.0in; 	mso-header-margin:.5in; 	mso-footer-margin:.5in; 	mso-page-numbers:1; 	mso-paper-source:0;} div.WordSection1 	{page:WordSection1;}
--></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><em>The following is excerpted from the story of a young girl detective, one Clovis Cassidy, who&#8217;s primary jurisdiction lies in crimes of neglect. When a classmate goes missing, unnoticed, in a small town where baby food is the major source of employment, Cassidy is on the case. Mysterious and bizarre elements surround the young girl&#8217;s disappearance, including a feral family who&#8217;s only order of the day appears to be chaos, a patriarch obsessed with all things Shakespearian, and a curious Lazyboy recliner that may well just be the source of the crime. Not your-regular-Bobsi Twin, not you average-Nancy-come lately-Drew, Cassidy is hard on the trail. Nevertheless one must ask, how will Clovis Cassidy, kid detective, get herself out of this pickle?</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><em></em><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"><strong>Interlude</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Now she gathers the children around the King Richards. See, she says, how even as they fall from the King’s shoulders, how they are laid out splendidly? See how when a thing falls from the King&#8217;s shoulders it does not fall as a leaf does from a tree, scattered with other leaves, but falls JUST SO.<span id="more-1303"></span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"><span>Like an elephant, says Hermes. Like a feather duster, says Temperance. Like SO, says Patience.</span></span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">See the fur lining, says Hortense, fresh from a hundred-and-one of the most skinned-alive dalmatians.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">Like a Blankie! says Blythe, nuzzling up to the King Richards for as long as it takes Hortense to whack the smile off her face. Don’t you know? she yelps. To NEVER touch a king’s robes. THEY ARE TOO FULL OF POWERS.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">The children gasp and retreat a hop-step back. </span><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">Hortense smirks: Since you have never had anything nice, she says, you don’t know what it means to have powers.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">Oh yes we do, squeal Florences. Let us wear the King&#8217;s Richards! We can both fit, they say. They think they can share the powers.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">Share? Hortense grins wickedly. <span style="color: #262626;">The King is the King because he has EVERYTHING for himself and NOTHING for everyone else.</span> NO ONE shares powers with the King.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">B-b-but, stutters Ashley, Everything is here. But n-n-no one is K-king.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">What’s that sposed to mean, asks Vespasian.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif';">It means, says Hortense, that there will be a new king. A new king! they all gasp. But how will they know who is fit to wear King Richards. Hortense pauses to think this through. The wind will know, she says, pinching up the robes by the scruff like an old, loyal dog.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><strong><span style="font-family: TimesNewRomanPSMT, serif; color: #262626;">How to Become King</span></strong></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Big thoughts come to Septimus Painter in the King Richards.<br />
As he sits in the hairy old Adirondacks chair, crawling with prombley about a million centipedes, he thinks about how it is to be King. You could have a King’s hat, he thinks, and a carry a King’s staff and play a game of chess, which you could solitaire by yourself. And nobody could beat you (nothing beats a King). But could he, Septimus “Tuna Mutt” Painter, be King? Are the stuff Kings are made of, he wonders, moi?</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">His train of thought is interrupted by Nestor roundly thumping the gong. The King has a visitor.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Your Highness! bellies Patience. Persimmon to enter the King’s Court! </span><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">His cousin pulls aside the deerskin flap of the teepee and ducks in with a royal document tucked under her arm.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Tuna Mutt tilts his head up from an empty chessboard. Can’t you see I’m thinking powerful thoughts, regal thoughts! A few sweeping cape-moves have scattered the chessmen to the winds, visited exile upon them.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">At your service, your majesty and I assure you (Patience throws a quick look over her shoulder, as if the hands guiding her first two-wheeler have suddenly vanished, snapped off the trainers, sent her speeding down a very steep hill.) … You will want to hear this.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Tuna Mutt stares intently at Patience. Exhaustively fingering a prawn, he thinks: a King is always burdened with plebeian troubles; a King always has more in his mouth than he can chew. Heavy is the head that wears the crown. Even chewing and swallowing food is harder for a king. Patience, he reminds her, you are my Royal Advisor. By decree of the King, you shall henceforth mas-ti-cate all of my jalapeno-poppers before spitting em to me Royal yap, mama-to-baby-bird style. teeheehee.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">I’m not hungry, she says flatly. We’ll find someone with a superior appetite to do it. Patience makes a gratuitously polite curtsey, then cracks open the spine of the document.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">How to Become King, she reads hastily. Too fast, he says, slurping up the last shrimp in his cocktail. She begins again, this time at a taxingly slow pace.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">How to Become King, she reads, is the story of a kingdom ruled by twelve evil ministers for seventeen years and the Boy-King (who was born on the very night the old King died) who claimed the throne for himself. It is about how the ministers devised the most unlikely and impossible tasks for the King so that he should not be made King.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Tuna Mutt plucks at his chin-hairs, Gooo on, he purrs.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">The boy was very clever, says Patience, and saw through the ministers’ wicked schemes and was resourceful and found ways to complete even the most difficult tasks so that no one could deny him the throne. Tasks? mutters Tuna Mutt, wiping down his hands on his lobster bid. The King shifts in his chair uncomfortably Patience reads to him the deeds of the king and the clever ways he completed each of his tasks. How he quieted the birds of decibel, how he fell from a tower onto a heap of pillows, how he pushed the wandering churches of enoch into a block so that they all crumbled into one another and destroyed no more.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">The deeds of the King pile upon Tuna Mutt’s shoulders and drag him further, deeper into his throne. Therefore, for every King, Septimus proclaims when the story is through … There should be … (hesitating) …. tasks … or rules to becoming King.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Patience nods: If there were not such rules how could one know if one was really guilty of being KING or if one was just faking it?</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Tuna Mutt fishfaces. A King can’t be a King without subjects, right? Patience shakes her head. A King must have subjects. And not just subjects like in school, which are dull and make the hours go slow and waver like hot days, that cook eggs on the pavement in front of your eyes. That hardboil your eyes like eggs. No. Subjects the King&#8217;s entitled to push around as he pleases. Tuna Mutt looks around the teepee, as if not convinced of anything.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Who are my subjects, he asks Patience. </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">She shrugs, How should I know? You’re the King.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Yes, agrees Tuna Mutt. I am King. My subjects are &#8230; they are &#8230; whomever I say they are!</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">OK, says Patience.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">I guess that makes you my subject, he says noncommittally.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">She curtsies. At your service, my liege.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">And what about Clovis, he says wagging his shoulders, Fish-n-sticks style. Saucily. Is she my subject.<br />
</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Sure.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">He plucks lone wolf, his only chest hair, like he always does when he’s nervous about asking something. And-and, what about Horsey. But Patience turns her back like she hasn’t heard. I said: WHAT ABOUT HORTENSE.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Patience wiggles a pringle (pinkie) in her ear. Hortense is invisible in the game. She is out of the game.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Nestor, he demands suddenly, You are my half-brother. Raised in a Russian Orphanage. You are my first subject. (Nestor is a never narrator, he is silent.)</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Fetch me my trusty advisor, Patience. Patience turns back to face him. Ah, he says. Advisor-Subject Patience, Round up all of my subjects. I have questions which need answering.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">Fetch him his subjects! she calls out to Nestor, and the subjects who have all been huddled outside the teepee waiting for the word to rush in, storm Tuna Mutt’s royal court. Temperance, Blythe, Florences, Vespasian, Ashley, Hermes—even Clovis Cassidy, Kid Detective, etc. Everyone, into the tent all at once, causing a great stir. Having gathered all of his subjects into the teepee, Septimus asks a question that a King has never asked his subjects before: </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">What is a King?</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">1. First of all, a King doesn’t ask questions, a King DEMANDS ANSWERS. I see, says Tuna Mutt.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"><span style="font-family: TimesNewRomanPSMT, serif; line-height: 150%;">2. A King is when you reach the end of the board and put another chip on your chip. Yes, thinks Tuna Mutt, a King always wins at the Royal Games.</span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">3. A King is when you pull a legendary sword from a rock. A King is when you find something where it&#8217;s not supposed to be and yank it out. That is a King.<br />
</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">4. A King isn’t a King until he gets smooched by a Princess. Uh. Tuna Mutt blushes and turns away from Clovis. Maybe we’ll save that for later.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 5. A King is when you eat your fill. When everyone has less than you and you have the most. Now you&#8217;re talking! says Tuna Mutt. A royal banquet for all, and I the most. A King doesn’t eat just anything but only what is rare to eat. What the others do not eat.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 6. A King is When you push everyone off the raft at the pond and no one gets on but you.</span><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 7. A King is when you feel a pee beneath you. Through multitudes of mattresses. Yes, says Tuna Mutt, sly like the fox, Nothing else mattress.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"><span style="font-family: TimesNewRomanPSMT, serif; line-height: 150%;">8. Whatever fits a King, is fit for a King. Whatever is the size of a King, is King Size.</span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 9. A King is when you make everyone pay the toll. The King doesn’t need the toll, but he needs to take the toll away from people and HOARD IT as he sees fit.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 10. A King turns everything to gold. Even his Queen? Even.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 11. A King doesn’t play the hero, he PAYS the hero.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 12. A King always has daughters in peril. But, says Tuna Mutt. Has a princess sprung forth from the King&#8217;s loins? Nothing has sprung forth from Tuna Mutt’s loins except his ding dong.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 13. A King always has shoes to fill. Fill with what? How about you start with more shrimp, smart guy!</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> 14. A King has a roundtable. Someone go bring the King his Lazy Susan!<br />
</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">15. The King is like everyone else unless he fed a diet of that is royal. Yes, says Tuna Mutt. Bring the King a Royal Peanut Butter Jelly.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;">16. A King is Named.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 20.0pt; line-height: 150%;"><span style="font-family: 'TimesNewRomanPSMT','serif'; color: #262626;"> </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
