<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: The Concept of the Person: A Brief Psychoanalytic Critique</title>
	<atom:link href="/metaphysicalvillain/the-concept-of-the-person-a-brief-psychoanalytic-critique/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-concept-of-the-person-a-brief-psychoanalytic-critique/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/the-concept-of-the-person-a-brief-psychoanalytic-critique/#comment-65</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 01:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=836#comment-65</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[metaphysicalvillain- re: &quot;I suspect many philosophical thinkers avoid the term “subject” because it has, since Descartes, accrued so much conceptual baggage that it seems no longer recoverable.&quot; Your further discussion of the psychoanalytic &quot;subject&quot; brings this statement into relief, as it was exactly Descartes&#039;s &quot;subject&quot;, his &quot;cogito&quot;, that later Lacan recuperated and restated, in a manner which is often defined as his definitive break from Heidegger&#039;s Dasein--another clear attempt to avoid an atavistic term for the human.   In Seminar XIV: The Logic of Phantasy he proposed that we think of the Cogito as &quot;the subject of the unconscious&quot;.  It is here that he plays with truly elliptical ideas such as &quot;I think where I am not&quot; and &quot;I am where I am not thinking&quot;.  Zizek discusses the difference between these juxtaposed statements in his essay &quot;Why Lacan is not a Heideggerian&quot;, where he also stresses that for Lacan the cogito as the &quot;subject of the unconscious&quot; is the gap between &quot;being and thinking&quot;. Lacan makes this very clear when he annotates the Cartesian equation as such &quot;Cogito : Sum&quot; and stresses how this colon marks the symbolic obfuscation that prevents any immediate extension to the predicate of existence.  This cogito or the psychoanalytic subject does not magnetize thought with being in the pure sense of attraction; rather, like a magnetic reaction, there is a remanence, that which falls out from the incongruity of placing one thing next to another (no matter how snug it might feel). In the most riddling of senses, it is this fall out or glow that the &quot;subject of the unconscious&quot; evinces.  Though these terms deviate from the ones you used above, I think that all attempts at conceiving a Rational person or believing we can &quot;fully incorporate&quot; anything (thought, action, moral code) into our &quot;will&quot; ignore as you point out the hard truth of the Freudian lesson--that we risk being at our most irrational when we are at our most rational, when we identify our reason with our own sense of &quot;personhood&quot;.  The psychoanalytic point is simply that we just can&#039;t do that, in spite of our best efforts.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>metaphysicalvillain- re: &#8220;I suspect many philosophical thinkers avoid the term “subject” because it has, since Descartes, accrued so much conceptual baggage that it seems no longer recoverable.&#8221; Your further discussion of the psychoanalytic &#8220;subject&#8221; brings this statement into relief, as it was exactly Descartes&#8217;s &#8220;subject&#8221;, his &#8220;cogito&#8221;, that later Lacan recuperated and restated, in a manner which is often defined as his definitive break from Heidegger&#8217;s Dasein&#8211;another clear attempt to avoid an atavistic term for the human.   In Seminar XIV: The Logic of Phantasy he proposed that we think of the Cogito as &#8220;the subject of the unconscious&#8221;.  It is here that he plays with truly elliptical ideas such as &#8220;I think where I am not&#8221; and &#8220;I am where I am not thinking&#8221;.  Zizek discusses the difference between these juxtaposed statements in his essay &#8220;Why Lacan is not a Heideggerian&#8221;, where he also stresses that for Lacan the cogito as the &#8220;subject of the unconscious&#8221; is the gap between &#8220;being and thinking&#8221;. Lacan makes this very clear when he annotates the Cartesian equation as such &#8220;Cogito : Sum&#8221; and stresses how this colon marks the symbolic obfuscation that prevents any immediate extension to the predicate of existence.  This cogito or the psychoanalytic subject does not magnetize thought with being in the pure sense of attraction; rather, like a magnetic reaction, there is a remanence, that which falls out from the incongruity of placing one thing next to another (no matter how snug it might feel). In the most riddling of senses, it is this fall out or glow that the &#8220;subject of the unconscious&#8221; evinces.  Though these terms deviate from the ones you used above, I think that all attempts at conceiving a Rational person or believing we can &#8220;fully incorporate&#8221; anything (thought, action, moral code) into our &#8220;will&#8221; ignore as you point out the hard truth of the Freudian lesson&#8211;that we risk being at our most irrational when we are at our most rational, when we identify our reason with our own sense of &#8220;personhood&#8221;.  The psychoanalytic point is simply that we just can&#8217;t do that, in spite of our best efforts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
