<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Guns also kill people</title>
	<atom:link href="/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-21</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 04:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-21</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Still trying to figure out how to post it in a comment. For now, I think the Guardian has the right kind of chart: 

http://www.guardian.co.uk/news/datablog/2012/jul/22/gun-homicides-ownership-world-list#data]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Still trying to figure out how to post it in a comment. For now, I think the Guardian has the right kind of chart: </p>
<p><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/news/datablog/2012/jul/22/gun-homicides-ownership-world-list#data" rel="nofollow">http://www.guardian.co.uk/news/datablog/2012/jul/22/gun-homicides-ownership-world-list#data</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: A.-O.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-20</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.-O.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 02:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-20</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To inquire into the &#039;foundations&#039; of gun violence is intelligent and necessary. Not to insist on the immediate implementation of gun control is idiotic and dangerous. I agree that the weight of the gesture is significant in itself. It is a matter of breaking a positive feedback cycle that is (i again agree) tied to the lure of total gratification perpetuated by technology and the culture industry--they are indissociable--in tandem. The question to ask is: what is a mother of two living in the lap of first world luxury doing with semiautomatic weapons in her house? In what culture is this normal? Answer: in the same culture in which torture is a part of mainstream discourse.. A mother who owns semiautomatic weapons has already validated their use. Also: I don&#039;t condone shooting anything, but there is a difference between a hunting rifle and a weapon whose design principle is the efficiency with which it terminates human lives. Somebody stick a good comparison of gun violence stats by nation up on this thing...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To inquire into the &#8216;foundations&#8217; of gun violence is intelligent and necessary. Not to insist on the immediate implementation of gun control is idiotic and dangerous. I agree that the weight of the gesture is significant in itself. It is a matter of breaking a positive feedback cycle that is (i again agree) tied to the lure of total gratification perpetuated by technology and the culture industry&#8211;they are indissociable&#8211;in tandem. The question to ask is: what is a mother of two living in the lap of first world luxury doing with semiautomatic weapons in her house? In what culture is this normal? Answer: in the same culture in which torture is a part of mainstream discourse.. A mother who owns semiautomatic weapons has already validated their use. Also: I don&#8217;t condone shooting anything, but there is a difference between a hunting rifle and a weapon whose design principle is the efficiency with which it terminates human lives. Somebody stick a good comparison of gun violence stats by nation up on this thing&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-19</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 22:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-19</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@ Mouse. I wanted to add one note, which is that I do not blame the violence of media. If we could call that the content, then it is the form itself that I am more critical of. You can be lured into the desire for immediate gratification with ponies and talking clouds nowadays.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@ Mouse. I wanted to add one note, which is that I do not blame the violence of media. If we could call that the content, then it is the form itself that I am more critical of. You can be lured into the desire for immediate gratification with ponies and talking clouds nowadays.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-18</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 21:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-18</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@ Mouse. I see what you&#039;re driving at. It makes me think that somehow the right has more of a grasp on the problem...? They either blame culture or pure evil. I don&#039;t want to speak for the left, because there are obviously enough who don&#039;t speak about this. (Was Obama&#039;s recent &quot;there are too many of these tragedies occurring&quot; a reference to gun control?) For me, it seems like an important pragmatic step and it also, at the very least, constitutes a symbolic gesture of repair. I know that it would be 50 years before there would be any noticeable changes, but let us just say that Adam&#039;s mother hadn&#039;t owned guns, and to get a gun, this kid would have had to go down to some shady alley or something, might this not have prevented him from acting? I think on the slim chance that we could say yes, it is worth pursuing. I do think it is about temptation in relation to accessibility. I also think that a culture that is stricter with gun laws might reconfigure brains a bit, &#039;for the better&#039;. I guess these are my lefty dreams.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@ Mouse. I see what you&#8217;re driving at. It makes me think that somehow the right has more of a grasp on the problem&#8230;? They either blame culture or pure evil. I don&#8217;t want to speak for the left, because there are obviously enough who don&#8217;t speak about this. (Was Obama&#8217;s recent &#8220;there are too many of these tragedies occurring&#8221; a reference to gun control?) For me, it seems like an important pragmatic step and it also, at the very least, constitutes a symbolic gesture of repair. I know that it would be 50 years before there would be any noticeable changes, but let us just say that Adam&#8217;s mother hadn&#8217;t owned guns, and to get a gun, this kid would have had to go down to some shady alley or something, might this not have prevented him from acting? I think on the slim chance that we could say yes, it is worth pursuing. I do think it is about temptation in relation to accessibility. I also think that a culture that is stricter with gun laws might reconfigure brains a bit, &#8216;for the better&#8217;. I guess these are my lefty dreams.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: mouseonthemoon</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-17</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 21:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-17</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@J.R. I agree that you&#039;ve got to account for the influence of media in someway -- there is little doubt that these scenes are cinematic. Fiction opens up a space for fantasy and we wouldn&#039;t have it any other way. But criticizing violence in the media is also something  that the left is not very good at. For one, you risk being associated with the moral majority and two you risk seeming like a snob who can&#039;t appreciate the fun of a good action flick. 

It leaves us in a place where we have to criticize &quot;culture,&quot; which is something I find uncomfortable.  I would rather just leave culture alone. I&#039;d like to remain neutral on the question of, let&#039;s say, the value of aesthetic value for society. Yes, media are commodified today, but it&#039;s not easy to say how exactly commodification has affected media, and what would change if media suddenly became de-commodified. In a world without social contradiction, it matters little to me if people spend their time playing Call of Duty or studying renaissance sculpture and now I don&#039;t want to have to say, maybe all of this shit IS bad for people...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@J.R. I agree that you&#8217;ve got to account for the influence of media in someway &#8212; there is little doubt that these scenes are cinematic. Fiction opens up a space for fantasy and we wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way. But criticizing violence in the media is also something  that the left is not very good at. For one, you risk being associated with the moral majority and two you risk seeming like a snob who can&#8217;t appreciate the fun of a good action flick. </p>
<p>It leaves us in a place where we have to criticize &#8220;culture,&#8221; which is something I find uncomfortable.  I would rather just leave culture alone. I&#8217;d like to remain neutral on the question of, let&#8217;s say, the value of aesthetic value for society. Yes, media are commodified today, but it&#8217;s not easy to say how exactly commodification has affected media, and what would change if media suddenly became de-commodified. In a world without social contradiction, it matters little to me if people spend their time playing Call of Duty or studying renaissance sculpture and now I don&#8217;t want to have to say, maybe all of this shit IS bad for people&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: mouseonthemoon</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-16</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 21:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-16</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@ J.R. Gun control couldn&#039;t hurt, but I&#039;m wondering why appeals to gun control seem like a sort of forced reaction for the left for lack of anything else to say. It&#039;s partially because there is some truth to the fact that things like this might still happen with the same frequency even with tight gun control laws (though this is maybe a bad, ahistorical argument, since it&#039;s hard to imagine what America would be like without guns). Just yesterday a man in China slashed 20-some school children with a knife,  and any ban on guns that is politically conceivable would never ban guns entirely -- so there is already an implicit sense that gun control will not stop violence, only maybe mitigate it in some circumstances.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@ J.R. Gun control couldn&#8217;t hurt, but I&#8217;m wondering why appeals to gun control seem like a sort of forced reaction for the left for lack of anything else to say. It&#8217;s partially because there is some truth to the fact that things like this might still happen with the same frequency even with tight gun control laws (though this is maybe a bad, ahistorical argument, since it&#8217;s hard to imagine what America would be like without guns). Just yesterday a man in China slashed 20-some school children with a knife,  and any ban on guns that is politically conceivable would never ban guns entirely &#8212; so there is already an implicit sense that gun control will not stop violence, only maybe mitigate it in some circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-15</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 21:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-15</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@Mouse and Brady.  Referring back to Adorno, I think one narrative, one cause, which is also symptomatic of &#039;modernity&#039;, is the lust for immediate gratification. It seems that the desire to commit these acts is infused with  the fantasy of some absolute, cinematic gesture. In this sense, we could hypothesize that such desire spawns from the increasing &#039;precarity&#039; of the middle class. Though almost paradoxically, it is because these people, like the Batman killer, have access to immediate gratification that they seek it in a more definitive way.  In this sense, if there is something wanting in these kids&#039; hearts (do they have hearts?), it is  caused by the insufficiency of all the gifts of technology. Not that I blame video games or Hollywood, but it does seem that on a more abstract level, all the playing and watching certainly cultivates the possibility of these acts.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@Mouse and Brady.  Referring back to Adorno, I think one narrative, one cause, which is also symptomatic of &#8216;modernity&#8217;, is the lust for immediate gratification. It seems that the desire to commit these acts is infused with  the fantasy of some absolute, cinematic gesture. In this sense, we could hypothesize that such desire spawns from the increasing &#8216;precarity&#8217; of the middle class. Though almost paradoxically, it is because these people, like the Batman killer, have access to immediate gratification that they seek it in a more definitive way.  In this sense, if there is something wanting in these kids&#8217; hearts (do they have hearts?), it is  caused by the insufficiency of all the gifts of technology. Not that I blame video games or Hollywood, but it does seem that on a more abstract level, all the playing and watching certainly cultivates the possibility of these acts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: mouseonthemoon</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-14</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mouseonthemoon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 20:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-14</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[@Brady. You&#039;re right that we shouldn&#039;t discount class too easily. Part of the difficulty of understanding this phenomenon is that we can&#039;t really discount anything. It confronts us with the problem of using &quot;modernity&quot; as an explanation.  One aspect of modernity, in America at least, is a widespread access to powerful killing technology. There is also a growing economic precariousness for the middle class, which can cause all kinds of reactions, violent ones included. 

But my sense is that the left -- or maybe it&#039;s just me -- is a lot more comfortable explaining violence when it can directly link it to capital: to the systematic poverty of inner city minorities, or to someone who &quot;snaps&quot; and does some unexpectedly violent thing because he or she became vulnerable to the movement of capital. 

But cases like Sandy Hook resist these easy narratives.  Here we might be talking about all kinds of environmental factors that are quite possibly the result of modernity and capitalism but maybe also not. In any case the links between cause and symptom become less and less clear and you move into this sort of vague area known generally as &quot;culture&quot; : culture of violence, a culture of youth disaffection, and distraction, and I really have very little of substance to say about that.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>@Brady. You&#8217;re right that we shouldn&#8217;t discount class too easily. Part of the difficulty of understanding this phenomenon is that we can&#8217;t really discount anything. It confronts us with the problem of using &#8220;modernity&#8221; as an explanation.  One aspect of modernity, in America at least, is a widespread access to powerful killing technology. There is also a growing economic precariousness for the middle class, which can cause all kinds of reactions, violent ones included. </p>
<p>But my sense is that the left &#8212; or maybe it&#8217;s just me &#8212; is a lot more comfortable explaining violence when it can directly link it to capital: to the systematic poverty of inner city minorities, or to someone who &#8220;snaps&#8221; and does some unexpectedly violent thing because he or she became vulnerable to the movement of capital. </p>
<p>But cases like Sandy Hook resist these easy narratives.  Here we might be talking about all kinds of environmental factors that are quite possibly the result of modernity and capitalism but maybe also not. In any case the links between cause and symptom become less and less clear and you move into this sort of vague area known generally as &#8220;culture&#8221; : culture of violence, a culture of youth disaffection, and distraction, and I really have very little of substance to say about that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Brady</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-13</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brady]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 19:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-13</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Also, I wouldn&#039;t give up the class question so easily. A lot of these shooters might be middle class, but that doesn&#039;t mean what it used to mean, if it used to mean anything. It&#039;s probably too vague to say that these shootings have something to do with the &quot;demoralizing effects of modernity.&quot; But it&#039;s probably not going too far to say that the increasingly dire straits in which a lot of ostensibly middle class people live has something to do with creating the situations in which these people snap. Everyone is part of the precariat, though not everyone knows it yet--the contradictions inherent in such a situation are probably more explosive than simply knowing that your life probably isn&#039;t going to be what you thought it was. It&#039;s not hard to imagine why some people lose it.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Also, I wouldn&#8217;t give up the class question so easily. A lot of these shooters might be middle class, but that doesn&#8217;t mean what it used to mean, if it used to mean anything. It&#8217;s probably too vague to say that these shootings have something to do with the &#8220;demoralizing effects of modernity.&#8221; But it&#8217;s probably not going too far to say that the increasingly dire straits in which a lot of ostensibly middle class people live has something to do with creating the situations in which these people snap. Everyone is part of the precariat, though not everyone knows it yet&#8211;the contradictions inherent in such a situation are probably more explosive than simply knowing that your life probably isn&#8217;t going to be what you thought it was. It&#8217;s not hard to imagine why some people lose it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Brady</title>
		<link>/metaphysicalvillain/guns-also-kill-people/#comment-12</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brady]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 19:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=600#comment-12</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There may be no easy left response to the phenomenon of mass killings, but the much more mundane--and ultimately bloodier--violence that happens in a lot of American cities every day would certainly be helped by ending the drug war and not treating the prison system like a warehouse for people deemed undesirable.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There may be no easy left response to the phenomenon of mass killings, but the much more mundane&#8211;and ultimately bloodier&#8211;violence that happens in a lot of American cities every day would certainly be helped by ending the drug war and not treating the prison system like a warehouse for people deemed undesirable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
