<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Concepts &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/concepts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Black Magician (a stupid aside)</title>
		<link>/h-b/the-black-magician-a-stupid-aside/</link>
		<comments>/h-b/the-black-magician-a-stupid-aside/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 18:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[H.B.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hegel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dialectic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaphysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ontology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phenomenology of Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simone Weil]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=703</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My Hegel Problem: Here’s the thing with Hegel&#8217;s Phenomenology of Spirit: the dialectic works in both ways, al(l)ways; it always-already covers all the &#8220;angles&#8221;. In a way, I would risk saying it is an operation of reflection directed against the operation of writing, or of the philosopher against the writer. Whatever it is you lay [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>My Hegel Problem</strong>:</p>
<p>Here’s the thing with Hegel&#8217;s <em>Phenomenology of Spirit</em>: the dialectic works in both ways, al(l)ways; it always-already covers all the &#8220;angles&#8221;. In a way, I would risk saying it is an operation of reflection directed against the operation of writing, or of the philosopher against the writer. Whatever it is you lay claim to, or write, Hegel will look at what’s behind it and say that it was a direct result of the latter. A <em>direct</em> result.  <span id="more-703"></span> For him, the différance must be reducible to an (ultimately <em>metaphysically-closable</em> &#8211; the dangling carrot that is the Notion) system of inter-differentiated identities (that in turn are the products <em>and</em> the materials – again the double movement – of that very system). Hegel will seize you on every <em>example</em>; on every claim. His <em>faith</em>, the force of his dialectic (with that he is a true genius), is that creation is impossible; but we’re not talking about an ontological impossibility: this one is a <em>metaphysical impossibility</em>. It is an impossibility in that which I have no access to except as being its confused symptom. That, I believe, is the metaphysical principle at work in the dialectic: it is a direct attack on the metaphysical concept of creation (which will, I think, by necessity resonate into all conceptions of time that Hegel might have – hence perhaps his tendency to read History the way he does). Hegel’s attacks are such that they cannot be defended against, because they attack precisely that which works in silence, in secret; that which cannot, by definition, defend itself. “Either everything is on the table, or you have not thought through what you are saying,” is what he decisively tells you at every reflective turn-of-thought. But once it’s on the table, Hegel always knew it would be there in advance; not in content necessarily, but in form. <em>What</em>-ever you say can and will be held against you; but the saying will always and forever be left as remainder, as refuse(d), as something the writer/thinker should be ashamed of (and shut up/out). This perhaps is why the <em>Phenomenology</em> hurts me, almost a palpable, physical pain: if I want to say “the Other puts the I into question,” Hegel would immediately ask who/what is this &#8216;Other&#8217;, in what does this Other consist? “Give me an <em>example</em>!” He will then invariably direct the attention to the ‘I’ – to the most concrete part of the statement – and then work everything around it and toward it, using the gravity of the &#8216;I&#8217;s ontology to suck out the grace of an Other&#8217;s metaphysics &#8211; to use Simone Weil&#8217;s terms. He will always insist that the whole equals the sum of its parts, always; more radical even than Aristotle, since Aristotle at least assumed the diremption of the immovable mover (and has been rightly critiqued  as having that undermine his entire system). Hegel, <em>systematically</em>, rids himself of any-<em>thing</em> that might go against his system, against ‘system.’ His genius lies in a constitutive inability to refute him, as if it was this very inability that writes itself (as many already noticed; most notably Werner Hamacher, who, I think, shared my physical pain – but this is only a hunch). Any refutation would have to enter into his dialectical game, which always ambushes <em>the outcome</em> and claiming itself as already having waited there from the start. In theological terms, <em>this</em> is a radical atheism, a radical Protestant move: that which is said being used, structurally, to void the saying. That is also why my own initial approach to Hegel – “read Hegel so as not to become Hegel” – was so painfully mistaken, or self-defeating: anyone, who takes any position towards Hegel, is always already Hegel when they read him. A true black magician. That’s why Adorno will always fail any “negative” dialectic because the dialectic literally eats &#8220;negative&#8221; for breakfast. Perhaps one plausible way is to skip the diabolical devices of the <em>Phenomenology</em> and focus on his <em>Logic</em>, <em>Encyclopedia</em>, or <em>Philosophy of Right</em>, as many have done as well. Personally (afflicted as I am with the need to read this torture-device), I still see no way out of this conundrum; my only intuition, as stupid as it may sound, is not to read myself against Hegel, nor Hegel against Hegel, nor anyone else against Hegel (Jay Bernstein, for example, does a great job at demonstrating/performing how any such attempt can finally be sucked back into Hegel despite itself – he can show you Hegel in everyone: Derrida, Nancy, Levinas…). My only idea so far is to read through it, with Hegel, and follow all the moves with a firmly erected middle-finger throughout your journey. Not “negative dialectic”, not even “otherwise than dialectic,” but a “fuck dialectic.” I propose this as a theoretical approach – as self-contradictory and irresponsibly stupid as it sounds. It is perhaps only stupidity that can break the grip of this specific Anaconda.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/h-b/the-black-magician-a-stupid-aside/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Notion</title>
		<link>/j-r/the-notion/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 15:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Notion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aufhebung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Begriff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hegel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hegel's Notion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phenomenology of Spirit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hegel’s (re)formulation of the German word Begriff in Phenomenology of Spirit is so distinct that it inspired A.V. Miller to translate it into English as Notion instead of as the expected, traditional, translation Concept. Perhaps it is the singular function of this term, the Notion, or perhaps it is the way it never seems to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hegel’s (re)formulation of the German word <em>Begriff</em> in <em>Phenomenology of Spirit</em> is so distinct that it inspired A.V. Miller to translate it into English as Notion instead of as the expected, traditional, translation Concept. Perhaps it is the singular function of this term, the Notion, or perhaps it is the way it never seems to fall into consciousness that encouraged this decision. As Martin Heidegger tells us <span id="more-166"></span>  in <em>The Fundamental Concepts of Metaphysics</em>, the word <em>Begriff</em> (he is not explicitly referring to Hegel) etymologically possesses the root of the German verb g<em>reifen</em>, to hold. He leads with this fact in order to describe the difficulty of holding onto a concept, and the way in which consciousness of a concept also implies that the concept holds on to you. Hegel’s <em>Begriff</em>, I believe, incorporates this strange interplay of holding, though by declaring the primacy of this one Notion, we do not solely confront the difficulty of holding onto one item of thought; rather, we confront the very difficulty of &#8216;holding on&#8217; itself.</p>
<p>In the <em>Phenomenology</em> Hegel describes how the Spirit (<em>Geist</em>), mind, self-consciousness, enters particular stages (self-conceptions) which each reveal variable orientations around the theme subject and object. For example, in the section entitled “Freedom of Consciousness ”  directly after the well-trodden Master/Slave dialectic, Hegel describes a movement of Spirit from Stoicism, to Skepticism, to the Unhappy Consciousness. Hegel utilizes the Notion here to critique and also move through each of these stages, always illustrating that an imbalance exists in the value attributed to the subject and object of each stage. The Notion, which is what &#8216;can be&#8217; transparently reasoned at the ultimate stage Absolute Knowledge, is present before this final stage as the measure of error in each prior stage. It is also present as that which seeks its own resolution. Since the Notion is the perfect balance of subject and object, each stage errors on the side of too much of one or the other.  In Stoicism, for example, Hegel places the error on the side of objectivity: the stoic treats self-consciousness as a “pure abstraction of the I”  (Hegel, p. 119), in doing so the stoic ignores the “<em>intrinsic</em>”  (Hegel, p. 120) or subjective element of Spirit.  The Notion rescues us from this static conception, thereby transferring us into a new form of self-consciousness, Skepticism, where Spirit declares: “the Notion is for me straightaway <em>my</em> notion&#8221;  (Hegel, p. 120). Skepticism is thus directly opposed to Stoicism, for where the stoic objectifies self-consciousness the skeptic registers it as a sign of freedom, as a sign that “I am not in an <em>other</em>”  (Hegel, p.120). Well, this reconfiguration of Spirit, in the end, acts as a type of overcompensation, carrying the skeptic too far into the error of subjectivity, thereby requiring another movement, so to bring the Notion closer to itself.</p>
<p>Hegel&#8217;s famous term <em>Aufhebung</em> defines this capacity to shift from object to subject and then back again (subject to object); it is the &#8216;sublative&#8217; act that reconfigures the balance sheet so to say. One crucial element of <em>Aufhebung</em> which spurs on the teleology of the Spirit (wherein Spirit is self-conscious of the Notion itself) is its capacity to record this action into the history of the Spirit. When the skeptic sublates the objectivity of the stoic into subjectivity, <em>Aufhebung</em> inscribes this action in such a way so as to bring Spirit closer to the Notion. Thus, though the skeptic seems at first to have swung far too close to solipsism, the stoical concept of an external mind remains to ensure that the skeptic, now moving towards another sublation, “truly experiences itself as internally contradictory” (Hegel, p. 126). The skeptic is thus capable of simultaneously recognizing the objectivity of the stoic and his or her original subjective freedom. Yet, at the moment the Spirit grasps, seizes, this contradiction it has enacted a second <em>Aufhebung</em>, and acceded to a new stage, in this case, “The Unhappy Consciousness”. Why unhappy? Because it is conscious of itself as a definitively “contradictory being”  (Hegel, p. 126), with no hope to merge subject and object. As Hegel says about the Unhappy Consciousness, “The duplication of self-consciousness within itself, which is essential in the Notion of Spirit, is thus here before us, but not yet in its unity”  (Hegel, p. 126).</p>
<p>This unity is the Notion as Notion, a self-consciousness that registers nothing but the Notion itself, a conception of subject and object that no longer treats them as contradictions, that treats them as constitutive of each other, decisively &#8220;extimate&#8221; if you will. To reach this ultimate stage, once we have arrived at the stage of “Unhappy Consciousness”, we need to travel through, with nothing in our sack but <em>Aufhebung</em>, all religious, philosophical and artistic ventures of the mind.  Yet, even on the penultimate page, we still find the Notion struggling to present itself. At this point, Hegel’s language nears an ecstatic incomprehensibility: “The self-knowing Spirit knows not only itself but also the negative of itself, or its limit: to know one’s limit is to know how to sacrifice oneself. This sacrifice is the externalization in which Spirit displaces the process of its becoming Spirit in the form of free contingent happening, intuiting its pure Self as Time outside of it, and equally its Being as Space. This last becoming of Spirit, Nature, is its living immediate Becoming; Nature, the externalized Spirit, is in its existence nothing but this eternal externalization of its continuing existence and the movement which reinstates the Subject”  (Hegel, p. 492). Though we might read this as the final stage of the Notion, Hegel is not finished yet, describing how the knowledge the Spirit attains here is a “withdrawal into itself in which it abandons its outer existence and gives its existential shape over to recollection. Thus absorbed in itself, it is sunk in the night of its self-consciousness”  (Hegel, p. 492).  A few hundred words from “infinitude” and we are once again shrouded in “the night where all cows are black.”</p>
<p>And then Hegel exerts the <em>Aufhebung</em> one last time, and would have us believe, or would have himself believe, that this final <em>Aufhebung</em> has achieved the Spirit’s transparent conception of itself as subject and object, as <em>Notion</em> qua <em>Notion</em>, recording all the previous <em>Aufhebung’s</em> of each stage in such a way as to expose itself in its naked light.</p>
<p>In recent years, many attempts have been made to extract Hegel’s Notion from its teleological consummation at the end of the <em>Phenomenology</em>. In Jean-Luc Nancy’s text “<em>L’inquiétude du négatif</em> (The Restlessness of the Negative)”,   Nancy  argues that the Notion negates every conception of self, and in this sense, the Notion is the source of <em>Aufhebung</em>, that which tears a hole in our <em>imago</em> or self-identification. By lopping off the final stage, Nancy simultaneously reconfigures the manner in which Spirit records the history of the <em>Aufhebung</em>. Without teleology, the history of Spirit no longer progresses towards the Notion; instead, the memory or trace of <em>Aufhebung</em> emphasizes that Spirit can never behold the Notion directly. Nancy does not aspire towards a self-conscious registration of the Notion, for such a conception would still possess the potential of negation present in each previous stage of the Spirit, immediately revealing its own error. Without this final stage, the Notion becomes a method of critique; it sublates the dogmatism and ego of each particular construct self-consciousness enters. This type of thinking, I believe, brings Hegel’s <em>Begriff</em> very close to Freud’s <em>Treib</em>. It flows underneath each object of desire, which manifests for Freud in fantasy and for Hegel in the imbalance of subject and object. The Notion divides us, like drive, into our identity, while the trace of this division remains so to inadequate our self-consciousness. The strength then of Hegel’s Notion resides in its aggressive redundancy, its constant undercutting force.</p>
<p>In the final section on Absolute Knowledge, where Hegel attempts to bring the Notion into self-consciousness by way of speculative Reason, Hegel seems to have forgotten the very nature of his Notion. He enters a sort of dogmatic trance where he has at last grasped the Notion in true form. It is like watching a man debride himself and then call the inside of his skin his god.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-255" title="debride" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/debride2.jpeg" alt="" width="260" height="188" /></p>
<p>G.W.F. Hegel, <em>Phenomenology of Spirit</em>, trans. A.V. Miller (New York: Oxford University Press, 1977).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>objet a</title>
		<link>/j-r/objet-a/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 23:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[objet a]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lacan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Objet petit a]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Objet petit a is never what you say it is. Objet petit a is that feeling you get when after hearing something that nags at you for the rest of the day, you soon suspect that that statement nagging at you is just the star dust of the dead one shooting through you. Objet petit [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Objet petit a is never what you say it is.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is that feeling you get when after hearing something that nags at you for the rest of the day, you soon suspect that that statement nagging at you is just the star dust of the dead one shooting through you. <span id="more-51"></span></p>
<p>Objet petit a is what would make you think you have fallen victim to the sisters of destiny, when in fact it is the very chance you are given to play another hand.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what turned Beatrice into a shiny glistening angel and led the pilgrim through the banalities of hell.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what you miss when you make a proclamation.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what the doctor can only find within himself when he pulls the plug.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is not your jizm. It is what gives you the right not to obey.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is why one year from now the girl who prayed so devoutly on her knees at Church will be performing fellatio with virtuosic precision on a boy with herpes simplex B.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is crushed when it is given form. And if you don’t let yourself go with it, it stands outside of you, and laughs at what you understand.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what inspires the curvature of your body when you plead with god.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what I sought and what infected me when I called her 30 times that night and then ran across Brooklyn and knocked on her door.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the 5 years you waited to prove to him you were right.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the anxiety that there is no apical destination for the heternomy of your soul’s next possible address.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is not the cause of anastomosis or flocculation or genetic transcription, it is, however, what causes you to search for a cause and to swear under oath that you have found it.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what you dream about as you arch your back and orgasm.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is why I sometimes cannot fight my misogyny and why I hoped that by taking it up the ass I would release myself from my desire.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the only thing you should concern yourself with. And if you happen to avoid concerning yourself with it, rest assured that it is the only thing which concerns you.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the cutest face in the whole wide world: Medusa’s.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is that which you feel you are missing when depression sets in; in other words, depression is when you are certain that objet petit a has abandoned you, and this feeling is drawn from that which you fear is missing, objet petit a. Therefore it would seem conclusive, since the depressed are those who have no hope for the day ahead, that the objet petit a is what you reach out towards when you fall asleep and wake up, that which is beneath the desire to lay down and rise up.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is not what makes you cough nor snore nor bleed; it is that intermittent seizure of thought: “Am I not the same, when will I become the same again.”</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the iridescence you see in her smile, perhaps you see it behind the pupils, perhaps in the dimple above her upper lip, or in the strain raising your cheeks that has spread from the strain raising hers, and objet petit a is what she feels when she smiles, when she sees you smiling back.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the desire to swallow.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the desire to ingest, swell, squeeze, push, and empty—then hold.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what you think will happen to you when you turn on the Television.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the genus under which the species Fetish Object has been revealed. Marx neglected though to see that the objet petit a was there when he diagnosed all surplus value as capitalistic, as if the objet petit a is not the source of economy itself.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what turns you against someone, so much so that you fantasize their death by your own hands.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what distracts you so you leave a word missing or a note off at the end of a melody.</p>
<p>Objet petit a can trick you into thinking you are in control of yourself and focused.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is how friends can forgive each other without the burden of guilt.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the struggle to remain certain that your cruelty was guided by the hands of justice.</p>
<p>Objet petit a obscures the truth of those who believe that experience is divine, it also obscures the truth of those who think they are what they are. Incidentally, it is also the source of God and the Ego.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is the thought so many leave behind.</p>
<p>Objet petit a disappears into every object, and it is also why it disappears into every object, for objet petit a persists by way of its own disappearance.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what pushes you on to the next word and the next sentence, it is not what sews the meaning together, but that rush you get, maybe it is quite small, that rush of joy, when for a moment you understand.</p>
<p>Objet petit a is what Lacan accredits Freud with presenting to the first psychoanalytic patient Anna O.—his genius as Lacan sees it was his durability, his refusal to ever interpret his patient’s desire as himself—he always watched it trail in and out of him.</p>
<p>Objet petit a gave the lie to our diamond rings, and then it continued to shine, until it dulled our jewelry and our kisses and our ecstasy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
