<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Museums as the Cathedrals or Mausoleums of Post-Modernity?</title>
	<atom:link href="/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 18:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: J.R.</title>
		<link>/peaty/museums-as-the-cathedrals-or-mausoleums-post-modernity/#comment-55</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 17:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=800#comment-55</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Peaty, I noticed that your division between the Church and the Modern Museum parallels, and not incidentally, the division I spoke about in my essay /j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/&lt;/a&gt;, that between a religious and secular ritualism or ideology. I did briefly mention Deleuze&#039;s theory of the baroque church as a &#039;field&#039; that pulls the visitor (viewer) into a 2nd plane, a transcendent one, which I think is what you emphasize with your question about the &quot;ivory tower&quot; and &quot;aesthetic transcendence&quot;.  It is interesting though, since I transitioned in my essay from the church to cleavage, to remain glued to the standpoint of architecture as it continues to offer a sacred experience in its modern (postmodern? -- I know one babyvitruvius who says architecture can never become postmodern) form. Though of course I think you were being quite nice, or nicer than I would be about these places. And you weren&#039;t even being that nice ;)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peaty, I noticed that your division between the Church and the Modern Museum parallels, and not incidentally, the division I spoke about in my essay <a href="/j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/" rel="nofollow">/j-r/on-the-use-and-abuse-of-cleavage/</a>, that between a religious and secular ritualism or ideology. I did briefly mention Deleuze&#8217;s theory of the baroque church as a &#8216;field&#8217; that pulls the visitor (viewer) into a 2nd plane, a transcendent one, which I think is what you emphasize with your question about the &#8220;ivory tower&#8221; and &#8220;aesthetic transcendence&#8221;.  It is interesting though, since I transitioned in my essay from the church to cleavage, to remain glued to the standpoint of architecture as it continues to offer a sacred experience in its modern (postmodern? &#8212; I know one babyvitruvius who says architecture can never become postmodern) form. Though of course I think you were being quite nice, or nicer than I would be about these places. And you weren&#8217;t even being that nice 😉</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
