<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Riddles &#8211; Plain Honey</title>
	<atom:link href="/combs/riddles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mosquito</title>
		<link>/j-r/mosquito/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 16:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A mosquito landed on the 2nd Regiment of the Royal Guard in battle with the Legion Nostradominitus, a vigilante group sworn to protect the virginity of Satan. It began to find parts of skin that were exposed to the shredded spectrum of daylight in the growing dim of agony. It found many spots to snack. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mosquito landed on the 2<sup>nd</sup> Regiment of the Royal Guard in battle with the Legion Nostradominitus, a vigilante group sworn to protect the virginity of Satan. It began to find parts of skin that were exposed to the shredded spectrum of daylight in the growing dim of agony. It found many spots to snack. Timmy, a red-haired chap from Devon was bit; and then Steven from Liverpool, on his calloused thumb. The Nostradominiti charged forth, encouraged by the sapping of blood from their enemy. <span id="more-1438"></span></p>
<p>A flare was sent off and landed in the pitch dark night.</p>
<p>Fair Mosquito was drunk on blood, and his friends left him for the trees.</p>
<p>A few bodies wriggled, but no noise.</p>
<p>On April 5<sup>th</sup> the headlines declared, “Far be it for me!” And the streets ran red with celebration underneath a grey cloud.</p>
<p>“Bzzz….”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bored</title>
		<link>/j-r/bored/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 23:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[People always try to fall asleep when a story starts, and I am not any different. I don’t think details such as “the middle of the week” and “the middle of the day” repudiate my being so much like everyone else—I was simply not ready from the moment I digested breakfast to do anything other [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People always try to fall asleep when a story starts, and I am not any different. I don’t think details such as “the middle of the week” and “the middle of the day” repudiate my being so much like everyone else—I was simply not ready from the moment I digested breakfast to do anything other than lay down and try to dissolve myself between the sheets, the mattress, and a few images I’d’ve sold off in a few mid-grade novels if just to get them “away from here”. I say story and what I mean is time, or whatever bakes us together into specific <span id="more-1278"></span>directional coordination; you think I’m joking, but what else would a dissolute consciousness be as it extends into the sheet than the opposite of a ‘stack’, where one by one by one instead of leaving I, you, we grow up to be something.</p>
<p>I must say I had the perfect opportunity to do all this nothing I wanted to do. I had a new plant aside my window, and it was freshly potted and really reaching each of its pinnate stems into all the sunshine, which, diffused throughout my bedroom, stretched the plant in so many directions that it almost resembled a sphere. Moreover, I was invested in this curry leaf plant because I had nearly suffocated it to death earlier that week when I turned the air conditioner on high, so that now I made sure to place it outside each morning. Since it was brittle and the wind on the sixth floor could be rather blustery, I would lay in bed and watch over it and sometimes move it back inside which required I lift it gingerly back over the cable wire that ran a diagonal at the base of my window down through the center of my fire escape. What really lulled me in was the blue sky, the bricks across the street, the one cloud that brought all the wind and that if I just stayed in bed I could cloak myself in all this, and especially this plant, whose growth also meant I could season my eggs rather esoterically for the next girl I brought home.</p>
<p>So, I am in bed, I slept all night and I am in bed at noon. My shades are not drawn. My bed is not too crumby or cummy, and I am trying to go right back to being away. And the only thing that could stop me, the ‘bad conscience’ that grows like bacteria in a bowl of rotten meat around unproductive behavior was utterly missing in that here and now where they all fucking tell us to find and fasten to short shadows.  I digress only to emphasize the heroism of my laziness, that it took a heroic nonchalance to be so inert and useless. But I didn’t see it like that. I had to make up a less abstract lie: I am caring for my plant. The less I existed, the fuller would stretch my plant’s withered leaves.</p>
<p>When the first jarring clank came through the wall followed by the next one, I immediately knew it would not stop because some squirrely long-haired Dominicans were renovating the apartment next door. Still, that it would not stop did not stop me from imagining I could still stop everything by dissolving. I was angry and had no reason to be. It’s just that the banging was basically coming from inside my apartment. It was such an intimate series of bangs, and even when it seemed the Dominicans were being gentle, just hammering a nail into damp wood, it was far too loud to not be irritating. And it kept coming toward me until its proximity started to make me feel like it was rattling deep inside my organs; no “I was not making the sound myself” though its repeated permanence combined with my refusal to move certainly made me complicit.</p>
<p>I don’t know how to explain what door of reality opened up and ushered in all that transpired; stupidly, though this was the third day in a row, and though I had left my apartment each of those days at this time, I refused to move, and I blame the plant, whose full leaves did not hear one of those bangs, still enjoying the gentle breeze and its riven grip on the fresh soil. Really though the plant was not unique, I could have found any reason to sit around wishing to sleep. Could’ve watched a Television show.</p>
<p>I am not sure when the power saw turned on, though it did not prevent someone else from continuing to hammer. For one moment, I only heard the power saw, and its variegated consistent texture without any sudden pops or shrill pitches made me thankful for a second that this uninvited orchestra had come to me now, and I was optimistic that I could turn it all in my favor.  But there can never be too many nails in a board, and the saw was probably just multiplying the prospective targets. And I started to dislike both sounds as soon as it was clear they were <em>ensemble</em>. I had a window and a plant and a bed and all I could think about was the hellish noise, and it was made worse by the fact that I couldn’t even concentrate on it entirely, so much so that I continually imagined, between the gap of each blow, that time had extended beyond the few second interval it took for another hammering and that  the construction crew had already departed. I imagined this every couple seconds.</p>
<p>They never departed. The last thing I remember before they took my ears and severed all my bones was that awful silence when their tools finally broke all the way through the beams and plaster into the space of my room. What made it worse was that I had wanted this. I had thought: “If I can’t reach nothingness peacefully, well let all the clatter break down my walls and devour me, whichever way I get there, I don’t care.” I said it filled with the sass of an old gay dialectician. But in your dreams your dreams come true. And I refused to account for the noise.</p>
<p>The buzz chain saw hammer null that came over me then with its constituent blood and bone dust did not worry my plant, deaf and sun-soaked where I belong.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lacking Pynchon&#8217;s Rainbow</title>
		<link>/j-r/lacking-pynchons-rainbow/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 03:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=831</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 19th, 2004: I thought you had the greenest eyes and your skin battened so vibrantly all around them. On July 3rd, 2006: You had slimmed and that was miraculous and I wanted you more. I remembered all the fat you used to show, how your shirts used to slide up around your jeans—“So [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On April 19<sup>th</sup>, 2004: I thought you had the greenest eyes and your skin battened so vibrantly all around them.</p>
<p>On July 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2006: You had slimmed and that was miraculous and I wanted you more. <span id="more-831"></span> I remembered all the fat you used to show, how your shirts used to slide up around your jeans—“So now you want me to pull it all off?” That’s what I heard you saying to me, and it worked.</p>
<p>On March 10<sup>th</sup>, 2009: I just could not be sure anymore, were you still there? How do I erase you—I never had a big stomach and it should have been the size of Pynchon’s rainbow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turn your Light on with a Gun!</title>
		<link>/j-r/turn-your-light-on-with-a-gun/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 01:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=630</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Why does this exist? Really haunting: I saw some kids playing with this today, showing off for their parents. Read all about it!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-631" title="Bang-2" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Bang-2-500x336.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="336" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Bang-2-500x336.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Bang-2.jpg 554w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Why does this exist? Really haunting: I saw some kids playing with this today, showing off for their parents.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.design42day.com/media-partnerships/listing/bang-what-if-your-lamp-remote-control-was-a-handgun%E2%80%A6" target="_blank">Read all about it!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Etch-A-Sketch Faces</title>
		<link>/j-r/etch-a-sketch-faces-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 22:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=546</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A couple minutes after I closed my eyes last night, hours before I fell asleep, I was given the chance to find, among a crowd of people, the “woman of my dreams” (as long as we agree this is only a phrase of speech). This parenthetical is necessary because the whole riddle of this daydream [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-560" title="jakey-etch-a-sketch-riddle-2012-1024px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/jakey-etch-a-sketch-riddle-2012-1024px-500x500.jpg" alt="" width="270" height="270" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/jakey-etch-a-sketch-riddle-2012-1024px-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/12/jakey-etch-a-sketch-riddle-2012-1024px-500x500.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/12/jakey-etch-a-sketch-riddle-2012-1024px.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 270px) 100vw, 270px" /></p>
<p>A couple minutes after I closed my eyes last night, hours before I fell asleep, I was given the chance to find, among a crowd of people, the “woman of my dreams” (as long as we agree this is only a phrase of speech). This parenthetical is necessary because the whole riddle of this daydream centered around the inability to manifest desire in form.</p>
<p><span id="more-546"></span>I may have been at the mercy of other forces, specifically the influence of an online journal called Plain Honey wherein a Peaty updates a blog called Etch-A-Sketch with, how do I say this, “weird images” digitally rendered into a digital image of this famous device.</p>
<p>For a moment, in the room, there was all this vibrancy and I thought I was about to stumble upon ‘her’, but then everyone I faced had an Etch-A-Sketch face—I mean literally their faces were square and had knobs. And it was such a sudden shift, one where this seemingly great opportunity became the judgment: you will never be able to animate the face you want. So that everyone in the room remained blurry, incoherent, and though the vibrancy and color and music remained, there was nobody there I wanted to talk to. And I didn’t even try to fuss with any knobs—I somehow knew the proposition would end in all these squiggly lines.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potato Head</title>
		<link>/j-r/potato-head/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 15:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=236</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gone. Revoked. Forced to begin again. How the summers washed over the felt of his digit. A bit of loose change fell on the ground before his feet. Why, screaming from above, oh why, did it transform? “A neuron like a die spilling with ant seeds go on up the granite!” “You’ll take two of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gone. Revoked. Forced to begin again. How the summers washed over the felt of his digit. A bit of loose change fell on the ground before his feet. Why, screaming from above, oh why, did it transform?</p>
<p>“A neuron like a die spilling with ant seeds go on up the granite!” <span id="more-236"></span></p>
<p>“You’ll take two of them?”</p>
<p>“I will have to if anything is to get done around here.”</p>
<p>The grain and the mountain. The wooden tracks he skipped over onto.</p>
<p>“Look!” A lady curled herself in jest across the tracks with whatever parts of her you wanted to see revealed. The man considered his digit again. The feel of her mouth, and then the feel of her thigh, and the sensation of an imminence with a pussy.</p>
<p>“How do I classify this?”</p>
<p>“Oh dear.”</p>
<p>“I think a train is coming to run us over.”</p>
<p>This is how it ended. First, it seemed clear that the woman would disappear. At that point, the protagonist was able to find clarity on the horizon. A sentence or two described with a graceful lushness the seaside out beyond the hill, and for the first time, and also the end time, the man’s eyes glistened. However, this is not necessarily what is possible. Imagining his digits disappearing (gone in the Myrmidon sunshine), she gets up clothed and we develop sympathy for what had seemed a Potato-head object employed by Waste Control. Third, here we are, alone, sternly grasping for purpose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>RNC</title>
		<link>/j-r/rnc-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.R.]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Riddles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=56</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The preacher told them all these things: “You should not outlast your own image, for in it you are bound to the fumes of disinterment. You should not forget to bless your comfort, for it places you among the sheaves of hundreds upon thousands of your closest friends. You should wait there, right where you [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The preacher told them all these things: “You should not outlast your own image, for in it you are bound to the fumes of disinterment. You should not forget to bless your comfort, for it places you among the sheaves of hundreds upon thousands of your closest friends. You should wait there, right where you are, alongside me, until together we can hold hands without the sweat of cowardice <span id="more-56"></span> shielding our union. You will become the fleece and the ghost, and the triniculum will serve you the plates of ambrosia. You will wash me and I will wash you. You will devour lust, you must never reflect upon this hatred of yours—feed it embers, pyres, forests, kindle the world, and watch as the fire fills the cosmos. Humble yourself before my coiled staff and suck on it until it is as rigid as your heart before the word of the Lord. Make peace with time, enjoy children, be like the flower. And from the…”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the crosswalk between Guernsey and Mount St. Helen, a wicked little man punctured the tank and the gasoline poured down the street, past the church, until it reached the highway which led straight to her door.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
